[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[AUDIENCE EXCLAIMING]
[观众惊呼]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
SPOT: Hello, world.
斑点：你好，世界。
This is CS50, Harvard University's introduction
这是 CS50，哈佛大学的介绍
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
到计算机科学的智力事业
and the art of programming.
以及编程的艺术。
Woof, woof.
汪汪。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
I'm sorry, Dave.
对不起，戴夫。
[PINK, "WHAT ABOUT US"] What about us?
[粉红， “我们呢？”] 我们呢？
What about us?
我们呢？
La-da-da-da-da-da-da.
啦哒哒哒哒哒哒哒。
We are searchlights.
我们是探照灯。
We can see in the dark.
我们可以在黑暗中看到。
We are rockets pointed up at the stars.
我们是朝向星辰发射的火箭。
We are billions of beautiful hearts.
我们有数十亿颗美丽的心脏。
And you sold us down the river too far.
你把我们卖得太远了。
What about us?
我们呢？
What about all the times you said you had the answers?
你说你拥有答案的时候呢？
What about us?
我们呢？
What about all the broken happy ever-afters?
那些破灭的幸福结局呢？
What about us?
我们呢？
What about all the plans that ended in disaster?
那些以灾难告终的计划呢？
What about love?
爱情呢？
What about trust?
信任呢？
What about us?
我们呢？
La-da-da-da-da-da-da.
啦哒哒哒哒哒哒哒。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
戴维·马兰：好的。
So--
所以--
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[掌声，欢呼声]
This is CS50, Harvard University's introduction
这是 CS50，哈佛大学的介绍
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
到计算机科学的智力事业
and the art of programming.
以及编程的艺术。
And this is Spot.
这是斑点。
And our thanks to our friends at 3D Cowboys
感谢我们 3D 牛仔的朋友们
for bringing him by class today.
今天带他来上课。
Perhaps a round of applause for our special Professor [INAUDIBLE]..
也许我们可以为我们的特殊教授[听不清]鼓掌..
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
My name is David Malan.
我的名字是戴维·马兰。
And I actually took this class, CS50, myself, some years ago.
我实际上几年前自己修过这门课，CS50。
But I almost didn't.
但我差点没修。
And I didn't because when I got to campus, as a first-year,
我没修是因为当我作为大一新生来到校园时，
I really gravitated toward things already familiar, things
我真的倾向于那些我熟悉的东西，那些
with which I was already comfortable, specifically, government.
我感到舒适的东西，特别是政府。
And I came in here thinking I was going to major or concentrate in government.
我来到这里，以为自己要主修或专注于政府。
And it was only once I got to sophomore year, fall semester,
直到我升入大二，秋季学期，
that some friends of mine were coming to this class called
我才发现一些朋友要来上这门课，叫
CS50 that was very much to beware at the time, in that it
CS50，那门课当时真的很让人望而生畏，因为它
was an unfamiliar field to so many of us, myself included.
对我们很多人来说都是一个陌生的领域，包括我自己。
But I got up the nerve to go over the threshold, sit in on the first class,
但我鼓起勇气跨过了门槛，参加了第一堂课，
just shop it, so to speak.
可以这么说，我只是试听一下。
And I was hooked.
然后我上瘾了。
I found that homework was, for the first time, fun.
我发现作业第一次变得有趣了。
And this was after having enrolled only because the professor let
而我之所以注册，只是因为教授允许
me enroll pass/fail or [INAUDIBLE] because I didn't really
我以 P/F 方式注册，或者[听不清]，因为我真的
think I could even cut it.
不认为自己能应付得了。
But fast forward to five Mondays later in the semester,
但快进到学期中之后的五个星期一，
I actually switched to a letter grade, deciding,
我实际上改成了字母成绩，决定，
wow, this is actually something for me.
哇，这对我来说真的很不错。
And I say this because computer science, what
我说这些是因为计算机科学，我当时没有意识到的是，它真的
I didn't realize about it at the time, really
是一种非常通用的思考方式和解决问题的方式。
is this very general purpose way of thinking and way of solving problems.
即使这是你唯一修过的 CS 课程，
And even if this is the only CS class you ever take,
即使这是你唯一的编程正规培训，
even if this is the only formal training you have in programming
作为一项实用技能，它真的太适用
as a practical skill, it's just so darn applicable
于许多其他领域了——艺术、人文、社会科学、
to so many other fields-- the arts, humanities, social sciences,
自然科学等等，当然也包括 STEM 领域，
natural sciences, and beyond, and certainly within the STEM fields,
本身。
themselves.
也就是说，它经常会让人感觉有点像这样。
That said, it's going to often feel a little something like this.
这是我们麻省理工学院的朋友们的作品，就在附近，是他们的一次黑客活动
This is from our friends at MIT, down the road, which is one of their hacks
他们将一个消防栓连接到一个饮水喷泉上，
whereby they connected a fire hydrant to a drinking fountain,
上面还贴了一个小牌子，上面写着，“从麻省理工学院接受教育就像
with a little sign up there that says, "GETTING AN EDUCATION FROM MIT IS LIKE
喝消防水龙头的水，”也就是说，在很多时候，在这门课中，
DRINKING FROM A FIRE HOSE," which is to say that it's
你会经常觉得，
going to feel, quite often, in this class,
有很多信息。
too, that there's just a lot of information.
你不可能全部吸收，但要意识到
And you can't possibly absorb it all, but realize
这是意料之中的，尤其是在入门课上。
that's to be expected, especially in an introductory class.
重点是让很多东西感觉很新，但随着练习，随着时间的推移，
The whole point is for so much of it to feel new, but with practice, with time,
甚至几年后，回过头来看，你就会对这些材料越来越得心应手。
with years, even, looking back, will you get all the more
但你并不应该在学习过程中感到舒适。
comfortable with the material.
所以我鼓励你，邀请你，期望
But you're not meant to feel comfortable along the way.
你在学习过程中能适应这种不适，
And so let me encourage you, invite you, expect
无论你是否拥有计算机科学或编程方面的经验。
you to get comfortable feeling uncomfortable along the way,
现在，在我那个年代，课程大纲略有不同。
whether you have or have not prior computer science or programming
而且，实际上，当我和我的所有同学完成这门课后，
experience.
我们会告诉朋友，我们学会了用 C 语言编程，这门语言我们自己也会学习。
Now, back in my day, the class' syllabus was a little bit different.
但那是唯一一门语言。
And, really, when I and all of my classmates exited the class,
但现在，你会看到，我们不仅会学习这门叫做 C 的旧语言，还会学习一门叫做 Python 的更现代的语言，
we would say to friends that we learned how
这门语言在数据科学、Web 应用等领域非常流行，
to program in C, which is a language that we, ourselves, will still
以及更多领域。
learn in this class.
。
But that was it for languages.
But nowadays, as you'll see, we'll explore not just
。
this older language called C, but a more modern language
called Python that's very much in vogue for data science, and web applications,
。
and much more.
But we'll also introduce you, along the way,
但我们也会在学习过程中，
to another language called S-Q-L or SQL, which is specifically for databases.
介绍另一种称为 S-Q-L 或 SQL 的语言，专门用于数据库。
And SQL is a different type of programming language
而 SQL 是一种不同类型的编程语言
that's just going to give you different ways of solving problems,
它只是提供了解决问题的不同方法，
different building blocks with which to express problems you want to solve.
不同的构建模块，用于表达你想要解决的问题。
We'll introduce you, toward the end of the semester,
在学期末，我们会向你介绍
yet another language, JavaScript, often used
另一种语言，JavaScript，通常与
with markup languages called HTML and CSS, with which maybe you
标记语言 HTML 和 CSS 配合使用，也许你
have some experience if you've made websites.
如果做过网站，你可能会有一些经验。
But we'll do this because so many of today's actual real-world software
但我们会这样做，因为当今实际的现实世界软件
is web-based.
都是基于网络的。
Or it's phone-based, mobile-based, but even then,
或者它基于手机、基于移动设备，但即使那样，
it's using these same languages, like JavaScript.
它也使用这些相同的语言，比如 JavaScript。
And so by the end of CS50, in particular,
所以到 CS50 结束时，尤其是
you won't know how to program in X, or Y, or Z, per se.
你不会知道如何用 X、Y 或 Z 编程，严格来说。
But, period, you'll learn how to program.
但是，总之，你会学会编程。
And, indeed, among the goals of this class
实际上，这门课的目标之一
is to equip you with enough of a set of concepts, enough practical skills
是让你掌握足够的概念，足够的实用技能
and experience that after CS50, again, if you never take another CS class,
和经验，以便在 CS50 之后，再次强调，如果你不再学习任何其他 CS 课程，
you can teach yourself new languages.
你可以自学新的语言。
And you won't feel--
你不会感到——
you won't have been reliant on a class to, indeed,
你不会依赖于某个课程来，实际上，
introduce you to each and one of those ideas.
向你介绍每一个这些想法。
And what are we going to do, then, in this class?
那么，在这门课中，我们要做什么呢？
And, really, what are we going to start doing today?
实际上，我们今天要开始做什么呢？
Well, we're going to learn how to solve problems.
好吧，我们将学习如何解决问题。
And that's really what computer science is all about.
而这正是计算机科学的精髓所在。
We'll, very specifically, today, knock off a few to-dos.
我们今天会非常具体地完成一些待办事项。
We'll learn how to represent simple things, like numbers.
我们将学习如何表示简单的事物，比如数字。
We'll learn how to represent letters of an alphabet, like English.
我们将学习如何表示字母表中的字母，比如英语。
We'll learn how to represent colors-- red, green, blue,
我们将学习如何表示颜色——红色、绿色、蓝色，
and everything in between.
以及介于两者之间的所有颜色。
We'll learn how to represent, more interestingly,
我们将学习如何表示，更有趣的是，
full-fledged images that you might see on the web or your phone.
你可能在网页或手机上看到的完整图像。
We'll talk about representing videos and even audio files.
我们将讨论如何表示视频甚至音频文件。
So, by the end of today, alone, you will exit here
所以，仅仅到今天结束时，你就会离开这里
with a newfound mental model for how you can
带着一个新发现的心理模型，了解你可以如何
represent all of today's media and multimedia that we take for granted
表示我们习以为常的所有当今媒体和多媒体
and use most every day.
并且每天都在使用。
But we'll also focus today, ultimately, on how
但我们今天也会最终关注如何
to write algorithms, like step-by-step instructions for solving
编写算法，就像解决某个问题的逐步指令，
some problem, specifically, implementing algorithms with code.
具体来说，就是用代码实现算法。
And that's what we'll find.
这就是我们将会发现的。
An algorithm is just something you can express
算法只是你可以用
in English or any human language, but code is a translation of that
英语或任何人类语言表达的东西，但代码是它的翻译
to, presumably, the 0's and 1's that you've probably heard
成，可以推测，可能是你可能听说过的 0 和 1
is all that computers ultimately speak.
是计算机最终使用的语言。
And if you're feeling like that's a lot for today,
如果你觉得今天的内容很多，
if you're feeling like that's a lot for the whole semester,
如果你觉得整个学期内容很多，
realize and take comfort in knowing that -thirds of you
意识到并感到欣慰的是，你们中三分之二的人
have never taken a CS course before.
以前从未学习过 CS 课程。
So even if you think, like I did all those years ago,
所以即使你认为，就像我多年前那样，
that, surely, my friends, the kids I didn't even in the class,
一定，我的朋友们，那些甚至不在课堂上的孩子们，
must know more than I, have been programming
肯定比我知道得多，他们从小就开始编程
since they were six years old.
从六岁开始。
That's just not the case.
事实并非如此。
You're in very much good company.
你们都是很好的同伴。
And within the class will you find different tracks,
在课程中，你会发现不同的学习路径，
by way of the homework assignments, called "problem sets,"
通过作业，称为“问题集”，
by way of the sections or recitations.
通过课程小节或复习。
There will be different tracks for those of you
对于你们中
less comfortable, more comfortable, somewhere in between.
不太适应、更适应或介于两者之间的人，会有不同的学习路径。
And if you really don't know why you are here today,
如果你真的不知道今天为什么要来这里，
we'll even have sections for those least comfortable, where you just
我们甚至会为那些最不适应的人设立专门的小节，在那里你只需要
don't necessarily feel ready to dive into CS or maybe STEM, more generally.
不一定觉得自己准备好深入学习 CS 或更广泛的 STEM 领域。
But we'll get you there by way of the course's support structure.
但我们会通过课程的支持体系帮助你达到目标。
And it's very much grounded in this mindset.
它很大程度上基于这种思维方式。
What ultimately matters in this class is not so much
在这门课中，最终重要的是
where you end up relative to your classmates,
你最终与你的同学相比处于什么位置，
but where you end up relative to yourself, when you began.
而是你与最初的自己相比，最终达到了什么水平。
So whether you have or have not prior programming or CSS experience,
所以无论你是否拥有之前的编程或 CSS 经验，
it's not going to matter when it comes to evaluation, when
在评估时，这并不重要，当
it comes to the output, be it a grade, or a satisfactory mark, or the like.
在评估结果时，无论它是一个分数、一个及格的标志，还是类似的东西。
It's going to depend on, really, where you are today,
它将取决于，实际上，你今天处于什么位置，
in this, what we call week zero, versus the very end of the semester, when
在这个我们称为第零周的学习阶段，与学期结束时相比，当
you will have built something grand, of your very own, in software.
你将会用软件构建出你自己伟大的作品。
But CS50 is also characterized, fairly uniquely,
但 CS50 也具有相当独特的特点，
by its community, its culture.
它的社区，它的文化。
And along the way, you'll see that your experience
在学习过程中，你会发现你的学习经历
is punctuated by a lot of social and academic events alike.
充斥着各种社会和学术活动。
CS50 lunches, most every Friday, we'll gather at a nearby restaurant
CS50 午餐，几乎每个星期五，我们都会在附近的一家餐厅
called Changsho where we'll have Chinese lunch together.
名为 Changsho 的餐厅一起吃中餐。
And as many of you as might want to attend
只要你们中想参加的人
that week will be able to join us, sit down, and chat casually with me,
都可以加入我们，坐下来，与我随意聊天，
the course's teaching staff, friends of ours, alumni from industry, as well.
与课程的教学人员、我们的朋友、行业校友一起聊天。
CS50 Puzzle Day, coming up this weekend, will be an opportunity,
CS50 谜题日，这个周末即将到来，将是一个机会，
even if you have no prior CS experience, just to solve problems,
即使你没有之前的 CS 经验，也可以尝试解决问题，
not jigsaw puzzles, but puzzles in the logical sense.
不是拼图，而是逻辑上的谜题。
We'll hand you a packet of puzzles--
我们会给你一包谜题——
logic problems, or riddles, or the like--
逻辑问题、谜语或类似的东西——
that you, as teams, can solve together.
你们可以组成团队一起解决。
And at the very end, we'll walk you through.
最后，我们会带你一步步完成。
And along the way, there'll be not only these puzzles, but pizza, and prizes,
在这个过程中，不仅有这些谜题，还有披萨和奖品，
and so much more, as well.
还有更多其他东西。
Towards the end of the semester, we'll have a CS50 Hackathon whereby
在学期结束的时候，我们会举办一个 CS50 黑客马拉松，
we'll get together around 7:00 PM, at the start of reading period,
我们会在大约晚上 7 点，阅读周开始的时候聚在一起，
and we'll finish up around 7:00 AM the next morning.
并在第二天早上 7 点左右结束。
And it will be this opportunity to really bond
这将是一个真正增进感情的机会
with your classmates, your project partners, if you work in a team,
与你的同学，你的项目伙伴，如果你在一个团队工作，
on your very own final project, which is meant
在你自己的最终项目上，它的目的是
to be a capstone of the course, something you build, yourselves,
成为课程的顶峰，一些你亲自构建的东西，
that we don't hand you a specification for.
而不是我们给你一个规格。
But it's your final offboarding, so that when you exit CS50,
但这是你最终的离职，这样当你离开 CS50 时，
you don't need CS50 anymore.
你就不再需要 CS50 了。
You don't need me.
你不需要我。
You don't need your TF.
你也不需要你的助教。
You can actually write code and solve problems on your own.
你实际上可以自己编写代码并解决问题。
So this picture here is one of our past photos from earlier in the evening.
所以这张照片是我们之前晚上拍的照片之一。
Things get a little quieter as we then, around 5:00 AM,
然后，大约凌晨 5 点，事情变得安静一些，
drive anyone who's still awake and energetic to a nearby IHOP
我们会把那些仍然清醒并且精力充沛的人开车送到附近的一家 IHOP 餐厅
for pancakes, around then.
去吃煎饼，大约那个时候。
But here is how most of the evenings tend to end for at least some
但这是大多数晚上对于至少一些
of your classmates prior.
你的同学来说的结束方式。
But at the very end of the class is the so-called CS50 Fair,
但在课程结束的时候会有一个所谓的 CS50 展览会，
an exhibition of all of your final projects for friends, faculty,
展示你们的所有最终项目，面向朋友，教职工，
students, and staff across campus, whereby
学生以及全校的教职工，在那里
you'll be invited to a space like this.
你将会被邀请到这样一个地方。
Bring your laptop.
带上你的笔记本电脑。
Bring your phone, whatever it is you have built and created.
带上你的手机，无论你构建和创造了什么。
And we'll just show it off for a bit of the afternoon,
我们只是在下午展示一下，
complete with music, and friends from industry,
配上音乐，以及来自工业界的伙伴，
and candy, and all what makes gathering together at term's end fond.
还有糖果，以及所有让学期结束时的聚会令人难忘的东西。
And you'll wear, ultimately, very proudly,
最后，你会非常自豪地穿上，
we hope, your very own "I took CS50," stating, very matter of factly,
我们希望，你自己的“我修过 CS50”的 T 恤，非常实事求是地表明，
what I did some years ago; that, indeed, this was a course I, myself, took.
就像几年前我做的那样；确实，这是一门我自己修过的课程。
So, today, let's focus, then, on computer science, like what is it.
所以，今天，让我们集中精力，然后，谈谈计算机科学，它是什么。
Well, it's really the study of information.
嗯，它实际上是对信息的学习。
But, really, it's, more specifically, about solving problems,
但实际上，更具体地说，它是关于解决问题的，
using certain ideas and techniques, all of which you'll exit the course with.
使用某些想法和技巧，当你离开这门课的时候，你都会掌握。
So, as such, problem solving is a goal that we'll
所以，这样一来，解决问题是我们会
approach by way of something called "computational thinking."
通过一种叫做“计算思维”的方式来解决。
So computational thinking, you can oversimplistically think about it
所以计算思维，你可以过于简单地把它想成
as thinking like a computer.
像计算机一样思考。
But it's really the application of ideas that we'll dive into today
但它实际上是我们今天要深入研究的想法的应用，
and we'll finish some weeks from now, that you
并且我们将在几周后完成，这样你
can apply to problems from this field or most any other, but in a computational,
可以应用到这个领域或几乎所有其他领域的问题，但以一种计算的方式，
that is, a very methodical, very careful way.
也就是说，一种非常有条理，非常谨慎的方式。
And that's what CS really did for me and does for a lot of people.
这就是 CS 真的为我做到的，也为很多人做到的。
It helps clean up your thought processes.
它有助于理清你的思维过程。
Even if you go off into the real world and do nothing in tech,
即使你进入现实世界，在科技领域不做任何事情，
you have an ability, after classes like this,
你有一种能力，在学习了这样的课程之后，
to express yourself a little more correctly, more
更准确地表达自己，更
precisely and, generally, having better command
精确地，一般来说，对自己的想法和语言有更好的掌握。
of your own ideas and your language.
你自己的想法和你的语言。
So what's problem solving?
那么什么是解决问题呢？
Let me propose that this is it.
让我提议这就是它。
This is as simple as we can make today's goals and the semester's goals.
这是我们今天目标和本学期目标所能达到的最简单的方式。
Problems to be solved look like this.
要解决的问题看起来像这样。
You've got some input, the problem to be solved.
你有一些输入，要解决的问题。
You've got a goal being the output, like the solution there, too.
你有一个目标是输出，就像那里的解决方案一样。
And then somewhere in the middle is the secret sauce,
然后在中间的某个地方是秘诀，
where we'll spend the next several weeks figuring out how
我们将花接下来的几周时间弄清楚如何
we can convert these inputs to outputs.
将这些输入转换为输出。
But before we can do that, we all just have
但在我们能做到这一点之前，我们都必须
to agree on how to represent these inputs and outputs,
就如何表示这些输入和输出达成一致，
whether it's with English or, really, any type of language.
无论是用英语还是任何类型的语言。
But, as I spoiled earlier, you probably came in here already
但是，正如我之前剧透的那样，你可能已经来这里了
with a general sense that, yeah, computers somehow
对计算机有一种普遍的感觉，是的，计算机以某种方式
only speak or know 0's and 1's, the so-called binary system.
只说或知道 0 和 1，即所谓的二进制系统。
But that's just one way of representing information.
但这只是表示信息的一种方式。
Even simpler than binary is unary.
比二进制更简单的则是 unary。
So if you've ever, at this age or any prior age, counted on your fingers,
所以，如果你曾经，在这个年龄或任何之前年龄，用手指计数，
this is unary notation, whereby each of your digits, your fingers
这就是 unary 计数法，其中你的每个数字，你的手指
literally represent some piece of information;
字面意思上代表一些信息；
taking attendance, like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
点名，就像 1、2、3、4、5。
But on your one human hand, how high can you count in this unary notation?
但是，你的一只手，在 unary 计数法中能数到多高呢？
AUDIENCE: Five.
观众：五。
DAVID J. MALAN: Five, I'm hearing five.
大卫·马兰：五，我听到五了。
Six, I heard one six.
六，我听到一个六。
But I'm going to go further and say the answer, if you're clever about it,
但我还要更进一步，说答案是，如果你很聪明，
is actually--
实际上是——
AUDIENCE: 40?
观众：40？
DAVID J. MALAN: Not quite 40.
大卫·马兰：不是 40。
You overbid, but--
你出价过高，但是——
AUDIENCE: 31.
观众：31。
DAVID J. MALAN: 31 is as high as I can actually count.
大卫·马兰：31 是我能数到的最高数字。
And that's because if I actually-- and if you're thinking
这是因为，如果我实际上—— 如果你正在思考
this is weirdly painful now, it will be, but this
现在这有点奇怪地令人痛苦，它确实如此，但这
is my hand representing the number 0.
是我的手代表的数字 0。
Normally, in unary, this is 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, of course, obviously.
通常，在 unary 计数法中，这是 1、2、3、4、5，当然，很明显。
But what if I take into account the order in which I'm
但是，如果我考虑我
putting my fingers up and down?
上下伸手指的顺序呢？
So maybe this is still 0.
所以，也许这仍然是 0。
Maybe this is still 1.
也许这仍然是 1。
But maybe this is now 2, where it's just the single second finger up,
但也许现在这是 2，那里只有第二根手指伸起来，
not two of them, total.
总共不是两个。
Maybe this is now 3.
也许现在是3。
Maybe this is now-- often offensive, with just the middle finger up.
也许现在是——通常是冒犯的，只有中指竖起来。
This is now [LAUGHS] 5.
现在是[笑声] 5。
This is now 6.
现在是 6。
This is now 7.
现在是 7。
And my hand just hurts too much if I try to count higher than seven.
如果我尝试数到超过七，我的手就太痛了。
But, theoretically, because each of my fingers can be down or up
但从理论上讲，因为我的每根手指都可以是向下或向上
and I've got five of them, that's actually 32 possible permutations,
而我有五根手指，实际上有 32 种可能的排列组合，
up and down.
向上和向下。
But wait a minute.
等等。
We said, 31, but if you start at 0.
我们说是 31，但如果从 0 开始。
You have to subtract 1 from the biggest possible value.
您需要从最大的可能值中减去 1。
So this is to say you and I have been using unary because it's just simple,
所以也就是说，你和我都一直在使用一元制，因为它很简单，
and it gets the job done.
而且它能完成工作。
But if we just think about representation a little more cleverly,
但如果我们更巧妙地思考一下表示方式，
we can do exactly what computers do, using not what mathematicians call
我们可以做到与计算机完全相同的事情，而不是使用数学家所说的
"base-1," where the finger is either there or it's not, but base-2.
“1 进制”，手指要么存在要么不存在，而是 2 进制。
And in base-2, we just need two digits at our disposal.
在 2 进制中，我们只需要两个数字。
And we could call these digits 1 and 2, A and B, black or white.
我们可以称这些数字为 1 和 2，A 和 B，黑色或白色。
We just need two words to describe two pieces of information.
我们只需要两个词来描述两条信息。
Computers keep it simple.
计算机保持简单。
And just like we humans start counting 0, 1, 2, 3 on up,
就像我们人类开始从 0、1、2、3 开始计数一样，
computers use 0 and 1, and that's it.
计算机使用 0 和 1，仅此而已。
But that's by convention.
但这只是一个约定。
But why do they do that?
但为什么他们这样做？
Well, it turns out, when you use base-2, otherwise known as binary, well,
事实证明，当你使用 2 进制（也称为二进制）时，
it just maps really readily to the real world.
它很容易映射到现实世界。
Because, at the end of the day, what do we all
因为，归根结底，我们所有人
do, if you've got a laptop, or a phone, or any device?
在你有笔记本电脑、手机或任何设备的情况下，会做什么？
You plug it into the wall because it needs electricity at some point.
你需要将它插到墙上，因为它在某个时刻需要电力。
And what if you have electricity or not?
如果你是有电力还是没有电力？
Well, there's your two possible values.
那么，这就是你两种可能的取值。
Either it's there, or it's not.
要么是存在，要么是不存在。
And because computers are electrical devices,
由于计算机是电子设备，
this is why binary is just useful.
这就是二进制如此有用的原因。
It's nice and simple.
它简单而实用。
Either electricity is there, or it's not.
要么有电力，要么没有。
So when you plug this device in and you've
所以，当你将这个设备插入并拥有
got all these electrons or whatever flowing, maybe
所有的这些电子或其他东西流动，也许
if we just hang on to some of that electricity,
如果我们保留一些电力，
we can represent what we'll call a 1.
我们可以用 1 来表示。
And maybe if we let it dissipate or go away, that's a 0.
如果让它消散或消失，那就表示 0。
So on and off maps very readily to this idea of just 0's and 1's.
因此，开和关很容易映射到 0 和 1 的概念。
And if you've ever thought of this, now, as binary digits--
如果你曾经将此视为二进制数字——
"bi" implying 2, 0 and 1-- well, if you've ever heard this term now,
“bi” 表示 2，0 和 1 —— 如果你曾经听说过这个词，
"bit," it just means binary digit.
“比特”，它只表示二进制数字。
A single bit is just a 0 or 1.
一个比特只是一个 0 或 1。
But we could have called these things anything we want.
但我们可以随意称呼这些东西。
Now how does this map to be clear to the real world?
现在，这如何映射到现实世界中？
Well, we can't see the tiny little switches inside of our Macs,
嗯，我们无法看到 Mac 内部、
PCs, and our phones that are actually turning the electricity on
PC 和手机内部那些实际控制电力的开关，
or off, storing electricity or not.
打开或关闭，存储或不存储电力。
But they're called transistors.
但它们被称为晶体管。
They've got millions of them in today's hardware.
现代硬件中拥有数百万个晶体管。
And they're just on or off, like a switch or a light bulb.
它们只是开或关，就像开关或灯泡。
So, for instance, if there's no electricity,
例如，如果没有电力，
the switch is off, we would call this, by convention, a 0.
开关处于关闭状态，根据约定，我们将其称为 0。
If, though, you throw the switch and it actually turns on, we would call this--
但是，如果你按下开关，它实际上打开了，我们会将其称为——
AUDIENCE: On.
观众：开。
DAVID J. MALAN: --an "on," exactly, a 1.
戴维·J·马兰：——“开”，没错，1。
We could have reversed it.
我们也可以反过来。
But this is just the way the world decided to standardize.
但这只是世界决定标准化的方式。
And that's it.
就是这样。
So you've either got something on or off, a 1 or a 0.
所以，你只能是开或关，1 或 0。
And this, then, is this thing we know now as a binary digit or a bit.
因此，这就是我们现在所知的二进制数字或比特。
So once we've got these values, what about how--
那么，一旦我们有了这些值，如何——
how can we go about, perhaps, representing things?
如何才能表示事物呢？
Well, you know what?
你知道吗？
It turns out we've got a lot of light bulbs right here.
事实证明，我们这里有很多灯泡。
Let me grab-- thanks.
让我拿一下——谢谢。
Excuse me, spot.
打扰一下，地方。
Let me grab the little music stand here.
让我拿一下这里的小乐谱架。
Let me borrow a couple of these bulbs and see
让我借几个灯泡看看
if we can't make clearer than my hand, alone, what's going on here.
是否可以比我的手更清晰地说明这里发生了什么。
So I'm going to go ahead and grab two of these.
所以我要去拿两个。
And I'll just put them here.
我就把它们放在这里。
And I can turn these things on or off now.
现在我可以打开或关闭这些东西了。
So if I've got two bits, two switches, two transistors, if you will, well,
所以，如果我有两个比特，两个开关，两个晶体管，如果你愿意的话，
if I go ahead and turn on this one, I'm representing what number in binary,
如果我打开这个，我在二进制中表示哪个数字，
perhaps?
也许？
AUDIENCE: 1.
观众：1。
DAVID J. MALAN: So just 1.
戴维·J·马兰：所以只是 1。
Now, if I'm using unary, I would turn this one on and be done with it.
现在，如果我使用一元制，我会打开这个，然后就完成了。
And that's 2, but not in binary.
那是 2，但不是在二进制中。
Binary, it's the permutations, which ones are on and off, that matters.
在二进制中，重要的是排列组合，哪些是开哪些是关。
So what, now, am I representing here, perhaps?
那么，我现在正在这里表示什么？
AUDIENCE: 2.
观众：2。
DAVID J. MALAN: 2.
戴维·J·马兰：2。
So this is when I put my single pointer finger up.
所以，当我抬起我的食指时，
But then when I did this, in my human hand,
但当我用我的手这样做时，
this was like representing the number 3.
这就像表示数字 3。
How do I represent the number 4.
我该如何表示数字 4。
Yeah, I need another light bulb, so I need more hardware, so to speak.
是的，我需要另一个灯泡，所以说，我需要更多硬件。
So if I turn--
所以，如果我打开——
if I leave this one-- if I turn this one on, this one off, this one off,
如果我保留这个——如果我打开这个，关闭这个，关闭这个，
now I have the number 4.
现在我有了数字 4。
And someone tell me, saying the words "on"
有人告诉我，说“开”
and "on" and "on," or "on," or "off," or "on,"
和“开”和“开”，或者“开”，或者“关”，或者“开”，
using combinations of "on," "off" and-- "on"
使用“开”，“关”和——“开”的组合
and "off," how do I represent 5, from your left to your right?
还有“关”，怎么用从左到右的方式来表示 5？
How about over here?
这边呢？
AUDIENCE: On, off, on.
观众：开，关，开。
DAVID J. MALAN: "On, off, on," I heard.
大卫·马兰：我听到的是“开，关，开”。
And that's exactly right.
完全正确。
And how do I represent, maybe, 6?
那 6 怎么表示呢？
Over here?
这边？
AUDIENCE: Off, on, on.
观众：关，开，开。
DAVID J. MALAN: Off, on, on, not quite.
大卫·马兰：关，开，开，不太对。
From left to right?
从左到右？
AUDIENCE: Off-- the other way.
观众：关，另外一边。
DAVID J. MALAN: The--
大卫·马兰：那…
[LAUGHS] OK, so from right to left.
[笑] 好，从右到左。
So I think we leave this one on.
所以我觉得这个应该开着。
This one, I'm going to claim, represents, now, 6 and 7.
我声称，这个现在代表的是 6 和 7。
AUDIENCE: On, off.
观众：开，关。
DAVID J. MALAN: I'm just going to-- it's actually going to be "on, on, on."
大卫·马兰：我打算…实际上应该是“开，开，开”。
Now, if you're wondering, where are these people coming up
如果你想知道，这些人是怎么想出这些组合的，这里面其实是有规律的。
with these combinations, there's actually a system here.
It's actually hard for me to do it backwards.
我反着做实际上很难。
But it turns out there's actually a system that's not all that unfamiliar.
但事实证明，这套系统其实并不陌生。
In fact, let me propose this.
实际上，我想提议…
Let me propose that we consider what you and I all
我想提议我们考虑一下，你和我都…
learned in grade school, which was something like the base-10 system, 10
在小学学到的，比如十进制系统，就是用十个数字，而不是两个，而是十个。
meaning that you use 10 different digits, not two, 10.
就是用十个数字，而不是两个，而是十个。
So 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, that's the base-10 system, otherwise known
所以 0，1，2，3，4，5，6，7，8，9，这就是十进制系统，也叫…
as decimal, "dec" implying 10.
十进制，"dec" 表示十。
So that's what you and I use every day.
所以这就是我们每天使用的。
Well, let's think about how we represent numbers in decimal,
那么，我们想想如何在十进制中表示数字，
in the normal human way.
以正常的人类方式。
Well, here is a number.
这是一个数字。
It's what number, of course?
当然，是什么数字呢？
AUDIENCE: 123.
观众：123。
DAVID J. MALAN: 123.
大卫·马兰：123。
So we all just have an intuition for that, obviously.
所以我们对这个数字都有直觉，很明显。
But it's not necessarily 123.
但这并不一定是 123。
You're just assigning meaning to the positions of these digits.
你只是给这些数字的位置赋予了意义。
This is really the pattern 1-2-3.
实际上是 1-2-3 这个模式。
But you immediately jump, mathematically, to 123, but why?
但你立刻就从数学上跳到了 123，为什么呢？
Well, odds are, in grade school, you learned that the rightmost digit is
嗯，很有可能，你在小学学过，最右边的数字是…
the ones place or the ones column.
个位数或个位数列。
This is the tens place or the tens column.
这是十位数或十位数列。
This is the hundreds place.
这是百位数。
And so why is this relevant?
那么，这有什么意义呢？
Well, this is like doing 100 times 1 plus 10 times
嗯，这就像 100 乘以 1 加 10 乘以…
2 plus 1 times 3 or, if we multiply that out, 100 plus 20 plus 3,
2 加 1 乘以 3，或者，如果我们把它乘出来，就是 100 加 20 加 3，
ergo, the number, now, that we just take for granted is 123.
因此，这个数字，现在我们理所当然地认为是 123。
But that's in base-10, the so-called decimal system,
但那是十进制，也就是我们所说的十进制系统，
whereby each of these digits is in a different column.
每个数字都在不同的列里。
And those columns are, again, ones place, tens, hundreds.
这些列，还是个位数、十位数、百位数。
If we keep going, thousand, ten thousand, and so forth.
如果我们继续下去，千位数，万位数，等等。
But where did these come from?
但是这些是怎么来的呢？
Well, here's the base.
嗯，这就是底数。
If you remember exponents and all of that,
如果你还记得指数和所有这些，
this is just 10 to the 0, 10 to the 1, 10 to the 2, ad infinitum.
这仅仅是 10 的 0 次方，10 的 1 次方，10 的 2 次方，无限循环下去。
And so, now, what if we just changed the base from 10, 0 through 9,
所以，现在，如果我们把底数从 10，也就是 0 到 9，
to just two digits, 0 and 1?
改为只有两个数字，0 和 1 呢？
Well, now the math is fundamentally the same.
嗯，现在数学原理是相同的。
But it's 2 to the 0, 2 to the 1, 2 to the 2,
但它是 2 的 0 次方，2 的 1 次方，2 的 2 次方，
which gives us the ones place, twos place, and fours place.
这就得到了个位数、两位数和四位数。
Now, why is this relevant?
现在，这有什么意义呢？
If you've got three light bulbs or three bits that are off, off, off,
如果你有三个灯泡或三个位，它们都是关着，关着，关着，
what have I done?
我做了什么？
4 times 0 plus 2 times 0 plus 1 times 0 is, obviously, the number
4 乘以 0 加 2 乘以 0 加 1 乘以 0，很明显，这个数字是…
you and I know, in decimal, as 0.
我们都知道，在十进制中是 0。
This, though, represents the number you and I know as--
但是，这代表的是我们所知的…
AUDIENCE: 1
观众：1
DAVID J. MALAN: This represents--
大卫·马兰：这个代表的是…
AUDIENCE: 2.
观众：2。
DAVID J. MALAN: --3, 4.
大卫·马兰：…3，4。
And just to be clear, this is why, when I grabbed the additional light bulb,
为了说清楚，这就是为什么，当我拿了额外的灯泡时，
we claimed that this now was 4.
我们说这个现在是 4 了。
Because we had "on, off, off," "on, off, off."
因为我们有“开，关，关”，“开，关，关”。
This now is 5.
这个现在是 5。
This now is 6.
这个现在是 6。
This now is 7.
这个现在是 7。
And if I wanted to count higher, what would the pattern of 0's and 1's be
如果我想数更大的数字，0 和 1 的模式是什么呢？
for the number 8?
对于数字 8？
AUDIENCE: 1, 0--
观众：1，0…
DAVID J. MALAN: 1, 0, 0, 0.
大卫·马兰：1，0，0，0。
So we just need more hardware, more bits.
所以我们只需要更多的硬件，更多的位。
So it wasn't arbitrary, even if it was non-obvious,
所以它并不是随意的，即使它并不明显，
what I was actually doing with turning these light bulbs on and off.
我实际上用这些灯泡的开和关在做什么。
Now, it turns out here we are talking about how to represent information,
现在，我们谈论的是如何表示信息，
like numbers, but we could also use bits, 0's and 1's, light bulbs
比如数字，但我们也可以用位，0 和 1，灯泡，
to represent instructions, as well.
来表示指令。
Because, at the end of the day, that's all computers do.
因为，归根结底，这就是电脑做的所有事情。
They process data, information of some sort, whether it's files,
它们处理数据，某种形式的信息，无论是文件，
or numbers, or images, or videos, or the like.
还是数字、图片、视频或类似的东西。
And you do things with those files.
你用这些文件做事情。
You open them.
你打开它们。
You print them.
你打印它们。
You edit them and the like.
你编辑它们等等。
So there's this notion of instructions, what the computer can actually do.
所以，就有指令的概念，电脑实际上能做什么。
And I bet we could come up with some pattern of 0's and 1's
我敢打赌，我们可以想出一些 0 和 1 的模式，
or, equivalently, light bulbs that tell even Spot what to do.
或者，等价地，告诉 Spot 该做什么的灯泡。
Maybe, go up, or down, or left, or right.
也许，向上、向下、向左或向右。
And it could certainly do this autonomously by using various sensors.
它可以通过使用各种传感器自主地完成这些操作。
We need to keep things safe today.
我们今天需要确保安全。
We're using Wi-Fi in sending Spot these very instructions.
我们正在使用 Wi-Fi 向 Spot 发送这些指令。
But what's happening, wirelessly, with our friend Andrew, here, is,
但无线情况下，发生在我们朋友安德鲁身上的是
essentially, he's sending Spot instructions just encoded, wirelessly,
本质上，他只是将编码指令无线发送给Spot，
somehow, as patterns of 0's and 1's.
以某种方式，将其编码为 0 和 1 的模式。
And the folks at Boston Dynamics, who built this robot, programmed
而波士顿动力公司的人员，他们制造了这款机器人，他们对
Spot to recognize certain patterns as meaning "up,"
Spot进行了编程，使其能够识别某些模式，将其理解为“向上”，
a certain pattern as meaning "down," "left," "right,"
某些模式则代表“向下”、“向左”、“向右”，
and any number of other things.
以及其他许多事情。
So, in fact, Spot, come on over here, if you could.
所以实际上，Spot，如果你可以的话，过来这里。
Come on, Spot.
来吧，Spot。
[FOOTSTEPS]
[脚步声]
OK.
好的。
So Spot, for instance, may very well have a pattern
所以Spot，例如，可能会有一个 0 和 1 的模式
of 0's and 1's that represents shake.
代表摇晃。
Shake, Spot.
摇晃，Spot。
So he could do that and any number of other movements, as well.
所以它可以做到这一点，以及其他许多动作。
And maybe, especially with sensors here and also a little human help over here,
也许，尤其是这里有传感器，还有这边有一点人类的帮助，
for today, what if we went ahead and did something-- maybe
今天，我们如果做点什么——也许
ask Spot some questions?
问Spot一些问题？
So let's go ahead, and we'll start simple.
所以，让我们继续，从简单的问题开始。
Spot, here we have some bits, "off, off, on."
Spot，这里我们有一些位，"关，关，开"。
Spot, what [LAUGHS]-- OK.
Spot，这是什么 [笑]——好的。
Spot, what is this representing, "off, off, on"?
Spot，这是什么意思，"关，关，开"？
[SPOT TAPS STAGE]
[Spot 轻敲舞台]
Correct?
正确吗？
I think so.
我认为是。
Very horse-like, OK.
非常像马，好的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right, so a round of applause for Spot here.
好的，所以让我们为Spot鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
So, Spot, what if we [LAUGHS] turn--
所以，Spot，如果我们 [笑] 把——
OK.
好的。
We'll turn that one off here.
我们将把这个关掉。
How about if we turn this one on?
如果我们把这个打开怎么样？
So it's "off, on, off."
所以是 "关，开，关"。
Spot, what's this number?
Spot，这是几？
[SPOT TAPPING STAGE]
[Spot 轻敲舞台]
Is that correct?
正确吗？
Nice.
不错。
OK.
好的。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
[LAUGHS] How about one final flourish?
[笑] 最后再做点花样怎么样？
How about, Spot, instead of "off, on, off,"
Spot，怎么样，不弄 "关，开，关"，
let's go ahead and do "off, on, on"?
我们来做 "关，开，开"？
So think, in your mind's eye, what the answer should be.
所以在脑海中想想答案应该是什么。
All right, Spot, "off, on, on."
好的，Spot，"关，开，开"。
[SPOT LANDING ON THE STAGE]
[Spot 着陆在舞台上]
OK.
好的。
And a round of applause for, Spot, as well.
让我们也为Spot鼓掌。
[LAUGHS]
[笑声]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So this is to say, no matter how--
所以我想说，无论多么——
thank you, Spot.
谢谢，Spot。
No matter how fancy today's hardware or software is,
无论今天的硬件或软件多么花哨，
it really just boils down to representing
它最终还是要归结为表示
information and instructions.
信息和指令。
And computers, and phones, and the like really are just
而计算机、手机之类的东西实际上就是
operating on those same pieces of information,
处理这些相同的信息，
whether implemented in 0's and 1's or with, really, anything else.
无论是以 0 和 1 的形式实现，还是用其他任何东西。
All right.
好的。
So, where can we take this, once we have this agreed-upon system
那么，有了这个约定俗成的系统，我们能把它带到哪里去
for representing [LAUGHS] information?
来表示 [笑] 信息呢？
Well, it turns out that using three bits, three 0's and 1's, at a time,
事实证明，一次使用三位，三个 0 和 1，
isn't actually all that useful.
实际上并不是那么有用。
And you and I, even in conversation, don't often say the word "bit."
而你和我，即使在交谈中，也不常说 "位" 这个词。
We say the word "byte."
我们说 "字节" 这个词。
And what is a byte, if familiar?
如果熟悉的话，什么是字节？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: It's eight bits.
观众：它是八位。
DAVID J. MALAN: So it's just eight bits.
大卫·J·马兰：所以它就是八位。
It's just a more useful unit of measure.
它只是一个更实用的度量单位。
And it happens to be a power of 2, 2 to the third,
它恰好是 2 的幂，2 的三次方，
which just makes math work out cleanly.
这使得数学运算很干净利落。
But it's just a convention, to have more interesting units of measure
但这只是一个约定，为了拥有比单个位更有趣的度量单位
than individual bits.
而不是单个位。
So a byte is eight bits.
所以一个字节是八位。
So, for instance, this represents, using eight bits, eight light bulbs,
例如，这个用八位，八个灯泡，
the number you and I know is 0.
表示你我所知的数字 0。
And this byte of all 1 bits--
而这个全是 1 位的字节——
now you've got to do some quick math-- represents what number, instead?
现在你要做一些快速的数学运算——它代表什么数字？
So it's all 1's; eight of them, total.
所以全是 1，一共八个。
How about over here, on the end?
这边呢？
AUDIENCE: 255.
观众：255。
DAVID J. MALAN: So it's, indeed, 255.
大卫·J·马兰：所以确实，是 255。
Now, that's not the kind of math that you
现在，这不是你在
need to do in your head for a class like this, but you could.
这种课程中需要在脑子里进行的数学运算，但你可以这样做。
This is the ones place, twos, fours, eight, 16, 32, 64, 128.
这是个位、两位、四位、八位、十六位、三十二位、六十四位、一百二十八位。
And because they're all 1, you just have to add up all of those columns' values.
因为它们都是 1，你只需要将所有这些列的值加起来。
And you get 255.
然后你得到 255。
But a little mental trick, too, is that, if you've got eight bits
但还有一个心理技巧，就是如果你有八位
and each of them can be two possible values, 0 or 1,
而且每个位都有两种可能的值，0 或 1，
that's like 2 possibilities here times 2 times 2 times 2 times 2, eight times.
那就相当于 2 种可能乘以 2 乘以 2 乘以 2 乘以 2，一共八次。
So that's 2 to the eighth, so that is maybe a little easier to do.
所以那是 2 的 8 次方，可能更容易计算。
That's 256.
那就是 256。
Or easier, in the sense that you get used to seeing these numbers in CS.
或者说更容易，因为你在 CS 中经常看到这些数字。
That's 256.
那就是 256。
But wait a minute.
等等。
How do I reconcile this with your 255?
我该如何将它与你的 255 联系起来？
Because you start at 0.
因为你从 0 开始。
So you lose one on the high end because we started counting and representing
所以你在高位损失了一个，因为我们从计数和表示开始
the number, like 0.
数字，例如0。
All right.
好的。
Questions on how we've represented just numbers or, for instance,
关于我们如何表示数字，或者例如，
instructions to Spot, thus far?
到目前为止，对 Spot 的指令？
Any questions on binary, unary, or the like?
关于二进制、一元或类似的东西，还有其他问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right, so seeing none, let's let things escalate a bit.
好的，既然没有人提问，我们来升级一下难度。
So how do you represent letters because, obviously, this
那么，你如何表示字母，因为很明显，这个
makes our devices more useful, whether it's
使我们的设备更有用，无论是
in English or any other human language.
英语还是其他任何人类语言。
How could we go about representing the letter A, for instance?
例如，我们如何表示字母 A 呢？
If, at the end of the day, all our computers,
如果说到底，我们所有的电脑，
all our phones have access to is electricity; or, equivalently,
我们所有的手机所能接触到的只有电；或者等效地，
switches; or, metaphorically, tiny little light bulbs
开关；或者比喻地说，就是里面可以开或关的小灯泡
inside of them that can be on and off-- that's it.
——就是这些。
There's no more building blocks to give you.
没有更多的构建块给你了。
How could we represent something like the letter A?
我们如何表示像字母 A 这样的东西？
Yeah, how about here?
是啊，这里怎么样？
Yeah?
是吧？
AUDIENCE: You could assign a number.
观众：你可以分配一个数字。
DAVID J. MALAN: Perfect.
大卫·J·马兰：完美。
So we could just assign every letter a number.
所以我们可以简单地给每个字母分配一个数字。
And we could do this super simply.
我们可以非常简单地做到这一点。
Maybe 0 is A, and 1 is B. Or maybe 1 is A,
也许 0 是 A，1 是 B。或者也许 1 是 A，
and 2 is B. It doesn't really matter, so long as we all agree and we all
2 是 B。这并不重要，只要我们都同意，我们都
use the same types of computers, in some sense, ultimately.
使用相同类型的计算机，在某种意义上，最终来说。
Well, for various reasons, the humans that designed this system,
好吧，由于各种原因，设计这个系统的人类，
they went with the number 65.
他们选择了数字 65。
So, nowadays, anytime your computer is showing you the capital letter
因此，现在，每当你的电脑在屏幕上显示大写字母
A on the screen, underneath the hood, so to speak,
A 时，在幕后，可以说，
it's actually storing a pattern of 0's and 1's that represents the number 65.
它实际上存储着一串 0 和 1 的模式，代表着数字 65。
And it tends to use seven bits or, typically, eight bits, total,
它通常使用七位，或者通常是八位，总共，
even if it doesn't need all of those bits in total.
即使它并不需要所有这些位。
So how do we get there?
那么我们如何做到这一点呢？
Well, here, for instance, is that same pattern.
好吧，这里，例如，就是同一个模式。
Here is that pattern of bits that represents 65.
这里就是代表数字 65 的比特模式。
And why?
为什么？
Well, quick check here.
好吧，快速检查一下。
This is the ones place, twos, fours, eights, 16, 32, 64's place.
这是个位、两位、四位、八位、十六位、三十二位、六十四位。
OK, so 64 plus 1 gives me 65.
好的，所以 64 加 1 等于 65。
So that is to say here's how a computer, using some light switches, so to speak,
也就是说，这就是计算机用一些开关，比喻地说，
would represent the number 65.
来表示数字 65 的方式。
And our Macs, our PCs, our phones just all know this.
我们的 Mac、PC 和手机都知道这一点。
So whenever they see that in their memory, so to speak,
所以，每当它们在内存中看到它时，比喻地说，
they show a capital letter A on the screen.
它们就会在屏幕上显示一个大写字母 A。
So that's it.
就是这样。
That's the system known as ASCII, the American Standard
这就是被称为 ASCII 的系统，美国标准
Code for Information Interchange.
信息交换代码。
And the A is actually operative there because we're only talking, thus far,
而且 A 实际上在那里起作用，因为到目前为止，我们只讨论
about English letters in our alphabet.
英语字母表中的字母。
And, in fact, I claimed, a moment ago, that we only use
而且，事实上，我之前说过，我们只使用
seven, maybe eight bits to represent letters of an alphabet.
七位，也许是八位来表示字母表中的字母。
So, just to come back to you, if I may, how many
所以，如果可以，回到你那里，我们可以用八位表示多少个
possible letters of the alphabet could-- how
字母表中的字母？
many possible letters of any alphabet could we represent with eight bits?
我们可以用八位表示多少个字母表中的字母？
AUDIENCE: 256.
观众：256。
DAVID J. MALAN: 256, the numbers 0 through 255.
大卫·J·马兰：256，从 0 到 255 的数字。
Now, that's more than enough for English because we've
现在，这已经足够表示英语了，因为我们有
got A through Z, uppercase, lowercase, a bunch of numbers,
从 A 到 Z，大写、小写，一堆数字，
a bunch of punctuation symbols.
一堆标点符号。
But in a lot of languages, with accented characters, a lot of Asian characters,
但是对于很多语言来说，有重音符号，很多亚洲字符，
this is not nearly enough memory or bits with which
这些内存或位根本不够
to represent all of those possible values.
来表示所有这些可能的值。
So we need to do a little better than ASCII,
所以我们需要比 ASCII 更好一点，
but we can build on top of what they did years ago.
但我们可以建立在他们多年前所做之上的。
So here is a chart of ASCII codes.
这里是一个 ASCII 码表。
It's just a bunch of columns showing us the mapping between letters
它只是一堆列，向我们展示了字母之间的映射关系
and numbers.
和数字。
So, for instance, up here is the capital letter A, 65; capital B, 66;
例如，这里是大写字母 A，65；大写字母 B，66；
capital C, 67; dot, dot, dot.
大写字母 C，67；等等。
72 is H. 73 is I and so forth.
72 是 H。73 是 I，等等。
There's some weird things over here, like special symbols,
这里有一些奇怪的东西，比如特殊符号，
that we'll learn about over time.
我们会随着时间的推移了解这些。
But there's a mapping between every English letter
但是，每个英语字母
of the alphabet and some number, just as you'd propose,
与某个数字之间都有映射，就像你提出的那样，
both for uppercase and lowercase.
对于大写和小写都是如此。
So, for instance, if we highlight just a few of these for now
例如，如果我们现在只突出显示其中几个
and I say that I've just received a text message or an email that,
我收到一条短信或一封电子邮件，在幕后，
underneath the hood, so to speak, if I have the ability
说，如果我有能力
to look at what switches are on and off, I received this message here.
查看哪些开关是开着的，哪些是关着的，我收到了这里的信息。
Well, first-- and this is not what CS is about, but just fun fact.
好吧，首先——这并不是 CS 的重点，只是一个有趣的事实。
Does anyone know what number this would represent in decimal,
有人知道这个二进制模式在十进制中表示什么数字吗，
if this is the binary pattern, like ones place, twos place?
就像个位、两位一样？
AUDIENCE: 72?
观众：72？
DAVID J. MALAN: 72 is correct.
大卫·J·马兰：72 是正确的。
And again, not, intellectually, all that interesting
再说一次，从智力上来说，这并不是那么有趣
and this is not the kind of math that we spend all day as CS--
这并不是我们作为计算机科学家整天做的那种数学——
a computer scientist doing.
一名计算机科学家所做的事情。
But it's just following the same darn pattern, which
但是它只是遵循着相同的模式，
is to say it might look cryptic, but, conceptually,
也就是说，它可能看起来很神秘，但从概念上来说，
intellectually, it ultimately is exactly as we did before.
从智力上来说，它最终和我们之前做的一模一样。
So, yes, I'll spoil the rest of the math.
所以，是的，我会把剩下的数学问题都告诉你。
It's 72, 73, 33.
是 72、73、33。
Now, anyone remember, in your mind's eye, what message we just spelled?
现在，有人记得我们刚才拼写的字母吗？
AUDIENCE: Hi.
观众：嗨。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so it is, in fact, "Hi!"
大卫·J·马兰：是的，实际上是“嗨！”
Though, no one really said that excitedly.
不过，没有人真正兴奋地说。
What's the 33, if you noticed?
如果你注意到了，33 是什么？
AUDIENCE: Exclamation point.
观众：感叹号。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so a lot of people noticed.
大卫·J·马兰：好的，所以很多人注意到了。
Yes, it's an exclamation point.
是的，这是一个感叹号。
And that's, indeed, noticeable right here.
而且，确实，这里很明显。
33 is the exclamation point.
33 是感叹号。
And that's just something, eventually, that might sink in.
而这只是，最终，可能让你恍然大悟的事情。
But, for the most part, if you remember capital A is 65,
但，大部分情况下，如果你记得大写字母 A 是 65，
you can figure out at least 25 other answers to these kinds of questions
你可以找出至少 25 个其他类似问题的答案
because they're all contiguous like that.
因为它们都是这样连续的。
So there's the exclamation point.
所以，这就是感叹号。
But at the end of the day, we might just have this mapping known as ASCII.
但最终，我们可能只会拥有这个被称为 ASCII 的映射。
And it's how our phones, and computers, and devices, more
而这就是我们的手机、电脑和设备，更多
generally, actually store information.
一般来说，存储信息的实际方式。
So we thought we'd make--
所以我们想做--
maybe take a little pressure off of me here.
也许可以减轻一下我的压力。
And could we maybe flip things around?
我们可以换个方式吗？
How about we try applying this newfound knowledge--
我们可以尝试应用这种新知识吗--
if it's, indeed, new to you-- with seven volunteers, seven bits, if we could?
如果你真的是第一次接触，我们可以用七位志愿者，七位，好吗？
OK.
好的。
I saw your hand first.
我看到你的手了。
Come on down.
快过来。
Maybe your hand, there.
也许是你的手。
OK, three, come on down over here.
好的，三位，快过来这边。
How about four and five?
四号和五号呢？
Yep, come on down.
好的，快过来。
Yep, in the black shirt, yep.
是的，穿黑色衬衫的，是的。
How about let me go farther back?
再往后退一点？
How about in the green, over there?
穿着绿色衣服的那位，过来？
And how about you, seven, over here?
你呢，七号，过来这边？
All right.
好的。
Come on down.
快过来。
[CHATTER]
[交谈声]
Come on down.
快过来。
So a round of applause for our brave volunteers.
让我们为我们勇敢的志愿者鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
So if you'd like to stand, roughly, side by side, here in the middle
所以，如果你愿意，站在一起，大概像这样，在舞台中央
of the stage.
舞台中央。
First of all, thank you.
首先，谢谢。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, perfect.
1、2、3、4、5、6、7，完美。
OK.
好的。
And let's go all the way over to this place, here.
然后我们走到这边来。
If you would like to introduce yourself to the class.
如果你愿意的话，向同学们介绍一下自己。
RACHEL RICHEY: I'm Rachel Richey.
瑞秋·里奇：我是瑞秋·里奇。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
And what year?
你是什么年级？
Anything about you?
还有其他关于你的吗？
RACHEL RICHEY: Oh, first year, concentrating in CS.
瑞秋·里奇：哦，大一，主修计算机科学。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
Welcome to the stage.
欢迎来到舞台。
Next.
下一个。
SPEAKER: Hi.
演讲者：你好。
I'm [? Kang. ?] Also a first-year concentrating in CS.
我叫[？康？]，也是大一，主修计算机科学。
SPEAKER: Hello.
演讲者：你好。
My name is [? Lam. ?] I'm a [INAUDIBLE] student from education department.
我叫[？林？]，我是教育系的[听不清]学生。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
大卫·J·马兰：很好。
OK.
好的。
Next.
下一个。
JORDAN MITTLER: Hi.
乔丹·米特勒：你好。
I'm Jordan Mittler, concentrating in economics and maybe some CS.
我是乔丹·米特勒，主修经济学，也许还会学点计算机科学。
SPEAKER: So, hi.
演讲者：所以，你好。
I'm [? Natalia. ?] First year, and I want to do CS.
我叫[？娜塔莉亚？]，大一，我想学计算机科学。
SPEAKER: Hi.
演讲者：你好。
I'm [? Khadija. ?] I'm a first-year, and I want to do CS.
我叫[？哈迪加？]，大一，我想学计算机科学。
DAVID J. MALAN: [LAUGHS].
大卫·J·马兰：[笑]。
SPEAKER: Hello.
演讲者：你好。
I'm [? Caleb. ?] And, once again, first year, concentrating in CS.
我叫[？凯莱布？]，再次强调，大一，主修计算机科学。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
Wonderful.
太棒了。
A pattern, yes.
有一种模式，是的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So, if you haven't guessed already, each of these volunteers
所以，如果你还没有猜到，这些志愿者
is going to represent a bit, from left to right, or right to left,
将代表一位，从左到右，或者从右到左，
in this case.
在这种情况下。
So let's see.
让我们看看。
If you want to represent-- how about the twos place?
如果你想代表-- 那两位数呢？
How about the fours place, the eighths place, 16ths place, 32's, 64, and 128?
四位数呢，八位数呢，十六位数呢，32 位数呢，64 位数呢，还有 128 位数呢？
Although, wait a-- I think I screwed up.
不过，等等-- 我好像搞错了。
We needed one-- eighth volunteer.
我们需要一位-- 第八位志愿者。
I think you know-- well, I think--
我想你应该知道-- 好吧，我想--
[CLEARS THROAT] Spot?
[清喉咙] Spot？
OK.
好的。
Come on over.
快过来。
If you guys could step forward a little bit, and then scooch this way,
如果你们能稍微向前走一点，然后往这边挪一挪，
just to give Spot some room.
给 Spot 留点地方。
[FOOTSTEPS]
[脚步声]
So Spot will represent the ones place.
所以 Spot 将代表个位。
Now, what our volunteers have on the back of their sheets of paper
现在，我们的志愿者在他们纸的背面
are little instructions.
有一些小说明。
We're going to spell out a three-letter word in English by using three bytes,
我们将使用三个字节，用英语拼出一个三个字母的单词，
from left to right, because now we have eight volunteers.
从左到右，因为我们现在有八位志愿者了。
I'm going to propose that you raise your hand, if you're
我建议如果你
supposed to represent a 1.
应该代表 1 的话，就举手。
Or you just stand there, without raising your hand,
或者你什么也不做，只是站在那里，不要举手，
if you're meant to represent a 0.
如果你应该代表 0。
And what we'll have the audience do is do the quick math
而我们让观众做的，就是快速计算
to figure out-- one, two, three-- each letter, what number is it.
去弄清楚-- 一、二、三-- 每个字母，它是什么数字。
What letter is it?
它是什么字母？
And we'll see what word that we have finally spelled.
然后我们来看看我们最终拼出的单词是什么。
All right.
好的。
So, in round one--
所以，在第一轮中——
you have instructions on your back of your sheet that will tell you to--
你的纸张背面有说明，会告诉你——
what your number is.
你的号码是多少。
If you're 0, stand there.
如果你的是0，就站在那里。
If you're a 1, raise your hand.
如果你的是1，就举起你的手。
[PAPER RUSTLING]
[纸张沙沙声]
What number do these guys seem to be representing?
这些家伙似乎代表什么数字？
AUDIENCE: 68.
观众：68。
DAVID J. MALAN: 66, I think.
戴维·J·马兰：我认为是66。
64 plus 2, so 66, which is the letter--
64 加 2，所以是 66，也就是字母——
AUDIENCE: B.
观众：B。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so, B. OK, so, B. All right.
戴维·J·马兰：好的，所以是B。好的，所以是B。好的。
Hands down.
放下手。
Second letter is going to be spelled how?
第二个字母将如何拼写？
[SPOT LANDS ON THE STAGE]
[点落在舞台上]
AUDIENCE: Whoa.
观众：哇。
DAVID J. MALAN: [LAUGHS] All right.
戴维·J·马兰：[笑] 好的。
What are we spelling now?
我们现在拼什么？
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[模糊的交谈声]
I think-- psst, yep, OK.
我认为——嘘，是的，好的。
Yeah, I think you're one.
是的，我认为你是1。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK.
好的。
Now what number are we spelling?
现在我们拼什么数字？
AUDIENCE: 79
观众：79
DAVID J. MALAN: 79, I heard, which is the letter?
戴维·J·马兰：我听到是79，那是哪个字母？
AUDIENCE: O.
观众：O。
DAVID J. MALAN: O. OK.
戴维·J·马兰：O。好的。
So hands down.
所以放下手。
Thank you, Spot.
谢谢，斑点。
One final flourish.
最后一次华丽的收尾。
So we've spelled B-O--
所以我们已经拼出了B-O——
third letter, go ahead.
第三个字母，继续。
[SPOT LANDS ON THE STAGE]
[斑点落在舞台上]
What number, now, is this?
现在，这个是什么数字？
AUDIENCE: 87.
观众：87。
DAVID J. MALAN: I heard it here, 80--
戴维·J·马兰：我在这里听到是80——
AUDIENCE: Seven.
观众：七。
DAVID J. MALAN: --seven, which is?
戴维·J·马兰：——七，也就是？
AUDIENCE: W.
观众：W。
DAVID J. MALAN: W, which, of course, spells "bow."
戴维·J·马兰：W，当然，拼写成“bow”。
So if our volunteers could take a bow, Spot included.
所以，如果我们的志愿者可以鞠躬，包括斑点。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So this will make more sense in week one,
所以这将在第一周更有意义，
when we have an assignment involving a certain someone from the Nintendo
当我们有一个作业涉及到任天堂世界中的某个人时
World.
世界。
But we have a lovely parting gift for each of you.
但我们为你们每一个人准备了一份可爱的告别礼物。
SPEAKER: Thank you.
演讲者：谢谢。
[LAUGHS]
[笑声]
DAVID J. MALAN: Thank you for volunteering.
戴维·J·马兰：感谢你的志愿服务。
SPEAKER: Thanks.
演讲者：谢谢。
DAVID J. MALAN: You might need to share it with the folks next to you.
戴维·J·马兰：你可能需要与你旁边的人分享。
[CHATTER]
[聊天声]
Oop, here we go.
哦，开始了。
There we go.
开始了。
Thank you--
谢谢——
SPEAKER: Thank you.
演讲者：谢谢。
RACHEL RICHEY: Thank you.
瑞秋·里奇：谢谢。
DAVID J. MALAN: --so much.
戴维·J·马兰：——非常感谢。
One more round of applause, if we could, for our volunteers.
再为我们的志愿者鼓掌一次，如果可以的话。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Did you lose something?
你丢了什么东西吗？
OK.
好的。
All right.
So, [LAUGHS] Spot's had it.
所以，[笑声] 斑点已经够了。
So let's see, then, if we've solved, now,
所以让我们看看，然后，如果我们已经解决了，现在，
the problem of representing English letters of the alphabet,
用英语字母表来代表字母的问题，
being able to spell out words like "bow," B-O-W. What if we actually do
能够拼出像“bow”这样的词，B-O-W。如果我们实际上有
have accented characters?
有重音字符？
What if we do have other glyphs that we want to represent?
如果我们确实有我们想要表示的其他字形呢？
Well, here, of course, is a standard US English keyboard, which a lot of you
当然，这里有一个标准的美国英语键盘，你们很多人都
might have.
可能拥有。
But there's also characters that you can type much more
但也有你可以输入得更方便的字符
easily if you have a foreign keyboard, relative to the US,
如果你有一个外国键盘，与美国相比，更容易输入，
or with certain keystrokes on your own Mac, PC, and phone.
或者在你的Mac、PC和手机上使用特定的按键。
But, nowadays, too, there's this menu that, probably, you've
但是，现在，还有这个菜单，可能你已经
used in the past hour or two to actually send some emoji.
在一两小时前使用过，来实际发送一些表情符号。
An emoji, even though they look like pictures
表情符号，即使它们看起来像图片
and they actually are pictures on the screen,
而且它们实际上就是屏幕上的图片，
they're, technically, just characters, characters of an emoji alphabet
从技术上讲，它们只是字符，表情符号字母表的字符
that happened to use a certain pattern of 0's and 1's to represent
恰好使用了0和1的特定模式来表示
each of these faces, each of these people, and places, and things.
所有这些面孔，所有这些人，所有这些地方，所有这些东西。
And it turns out that one of the reasons that we have just
事实证明，我们现在有如此多[笑声]字符的原因之一是，我们现在
so many [LAUGHS] such characters nowadays is because we now
使用Unicode而不是ASCII。
use Unicode instead of ASCII.
So Unicode is a superset, so to speak, of ASCII,
所以Unicode可以被认为是ASCII的超集，
which is to say that we, humans, realized, some time ago, that just
也就是说，我们人类在很久以前就意识到了，仅仅
using eight bits to represent letters of the alphabet
使用八位来表示字母表中的字母
certainly isn't very good when we want to represent
当我们想表示其他非英语语言时，肯定不太好。
other, non-English languages.
其他非英语语言。
So Unicode doesn't just use eight bits.
所以Unicode不仅仅使用八位。
It sometimes uses 16 bits per character, sometimes 24 bits per character,
它有时使用每个字符16位，有时使用每个字符24位，
and sometimes even 32 bits per character.
有时甚至使用每个字符32位。
Now, why those numbers?
现在，为什么是这些数字呢？
That's just one byte, two bytes, three bytes, or four bytes.
这只是 1 个字节、2 个字节、3 个字节或 4 个字节。
And that gives us--
这给了我们——
does anyone know?
有人知道吗？
That gives us the ability to represent as many as 4
这让我们能够表示多达 4
billion possible characters.
0 亿种可能的字符。
Because if the longest one is 32 bits, that's 2 to the 32,
因为如果最长的一个是 32 位，那就是 2 的 32 次方，
which, if you do out the math, trust me, is roughly 4 billion.
相信我，如果你算一下，大约是 40 亿。
So that's a lot of characters.
所以有很多字符。
And we've got a lot of room, then, for these emoji.
那么，我们就有很多空间来存放这些表情符号。
But it's not just about having fun, pictorially, on the screen.
但这不仅仅是为了在屏幕上以图片形式玩得开心。
Unicode's mission really is to represent and to preserve all human languages
Unicode 的使命实际上是代表和保留所有人类语言，
digitally, both past, present, and future.
以数字形式，无论过去、现在还是将来。
So it is really about capturing the entirety of human knowledge,
所以它实际上是关于捕捉人类知识的全部，
as we've expressed it in language, but also
正如我们用语言表达的那样，但也是
giving this newfound ability that's been used centuries ago, too-- in writings,
赋予这种新发现的能力，这种能力几个世纪前就已被使用——在文字中，
on walls, and the like-- pictograms via which
在墙壁上等等——象形文字，通过它
we can still communicate, even independently
我们仍然可以交流，即使是独立
of our own human language.
于我们自己的语言。
So we'll reduce it, today, to just patterns of 0's and 1's, but
所以我们今天把它简化为 0 和 1 的模式，但
the problem being solved is much greater and well-beyond CS, itself, there.
正在解决的问题要大得多，远远超出了 CS 本身。
So here is a pattern of 0's and 1's using
所以这里有一个使用 0 和 1 的模式，
Unicode, so more than eight bits, that represents a very popular emoji, which
Unicode，超过 8 位，它代表着一个非常受欢迎的表情符号，它
might be a bit of a hint.
可能有点提示。
This is the most popular emoji, as of last year, at least,
至少到去年为止，这是最受欢迎的表情符号，
statistically, internationally.
从统计上来说，在国际上。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插话声音]
DAVID J. MALAN: Does this help?
大卫·J·马兰：这有帮助吗？
It's, roughly, this number here.
它大约是这里这个数字。
No?
没有？
It's this one here.
是这里这个。
So this is the most popular emoji, by most measures, as of last year.
所以，根据大多数标准，这是去年最受欢迎的表情符号。
But it doesn't always look like this.
但它并不总是这个样子。
Those of you who have a Mac or an iPhone recognize this symbol, perhaps,
你们中那些拥有 Mac 或 iPhone 的人可能认识这个符号，
immediately.
马上就认出来了。
Those of you with Android devices or other platforms
你们中那些使用 Android 设备或其他平台的人
might notice that it's the same idea, but it's a little bit different.
可能会注意到它表达的是同一个意思，但略有不同。
And this is because, too, emojis, at the end of the day,
而这也是因为，归根结底，表情符号
just represent character, but those characters can be drawn,
只代表字符，但这些字符可以被绘制，
can be painted in different ways.
可以用不同的方式来描绘。
And reasonable people will interpret differently
而且合理的人会对这个表情符号有不同的解释，它官方的名字是“流着泪的笑脸”。
this emoji, whose official name is "face with tears of joy."
而且，的确，谷歌对它的解释与苹果、微软、Meta 以及其他公司都略有不同。
And, indeed, Google interprets it a little differently
你可以把这些不同的公司想象成拥有不同的表情符号字体。
from Apple, versus Microsoft, versus Meta, versus other companies, as well.
这确实开始把它们与文本和字符的世界联系起来。
So you can almost think of those different companies
所以，你只是为了让你见过它。
as having different fonts for emoji.
下次再说这个吧。
And that really starts to connect things to the world of text and characters.
事实证明，表情符号，以及更普遍的字符，
So, just so you've seen it.
我们不使用二进制 0 和 1 来表示它们，
More on this, another time.
因为包括我在内，没有人会认出哪个是哪个。
It turns out that emoji and, really, characters, in general,
数学太复杂了。
we don't use binary 0's and 1's to represent them
它毫无趣味。
because no one, myself included, is going to recognize what's what.
即使是十进制数字——是 40 亿还是其他的——
It's just too much math.
我记不住哪个数字是哪个。
It's not interesting.
所以我们用更紧凑的方式来表示事物。
And even decimal numbers-- that was 4 billion or some--
诚然，这看起来仍然很神秘，
I don't remember which number is which.
但这是使用另一种数学系统，
So we represent things a little more compactly.
称为 16 进制或十六进制的 Unicode 代码点。
And this, too, admittedly, still looks cryptic,
下次再说这个吧。
but this is a Unicode code point that uses another system, mathematically,
但这仅仅是一种以更简洁的方式表示数字的方法，
called base-16 or hexadecimal.
在屏幕上写得更少，因为你不仅使用 0
More on that, another time.
到 9，就像十进制一样。
But it's just a way of representing numbers even more succinctly,
但你也在使用 A 到 F，所以英语字母表中的一些字母也参与进来。
writing less on the screen, because you're using not just 0
但现在，对于那些关心的人来说，这更容易记忆，
through 9, as in decimal.
因为，那个数字代表着“流着泪的笑脸”。
But you're using A through F, as well, so a few letters
但如果我们想要一个自定义的表情符号呢？
of the English alphabet come into play.
这种情况越来越多。
But, for now, that's just a little easier
例如，这里有 5 种肤色，
to remember, too, for people who care, that that is the number that
如今，手机、笔记本电脑和台式电脑都支持这些肤色。
represents "face with tears of joy."
它基于一种叫做“菲茨帕特里克量表”的东西，
But what if we want a customized emoji?
它本质上将人类肤色分为 6 类，或者在本例中，
And this, increasingly, is the case.
分为 5 类，从浅到深。
Here, for instance, are the five skin tones
但这表明，哇，如果我们想用这 5 种不同的肤色来表示人，
that phones, and laptops, and desktops, nowadays, support.
这可能会大大增加我们需要的每种可能面孔的 0 和 1 的唯一模式的数量。
It's based on something called the "Fitzpatrick scale," which essentially
但如果我们从工程的角度来看，
categorizes human skin tone into six or, in this case, five
我们实际上可以把肤色看作是对某个默认颜色的修改，
different categories, from lighter to darker.
无论好坏。
But this suggests that, wow, if we want to represent people
而黄色是事实上的默认颜色，辛普森风格。
with five different skin tones, like this, that could significantly
但为了把它修改得看起来更像人类，从浅到深，
increase how many unique patterns of 0's and 1's we
也许我们只使用相同的位模式，
need for every possible face.
来表示一个人的拇指，例如，竖起拇指或竖起大拇指。
But if we think about it from an engineering perspective,
然后我们只需修改那个字符，使其以不同的肤色显示出来。
we can actually just think of skin tone as modifying some default
例如，这里就是你在不同平台上可能使用的“竖起大拇指”。
color, for better or for worse.
让我声明一下，这是一个 Unicode 代码点。
And yellow is the de facto default, Simpson style.
它是 Mac、PC 和手机在后台用来表示默认黄色“竖起大拇指”的数字。
But to modify it to look more genuinely human-like, from lighter to darker,
但如果你想给它一个中等肤色，
well, maybe we just use the same pattern of bits
你仍然使用相同的数字，相同的 0 和 1 的模式，
to represent a human thumb, for instance, thumbs up or thumbs down.
来表示“竖起大拇指”。
And we just, then, modify that character to be displayed with a different skin
所以，下次再说吧。
tone.
我们会在下节课中讨论这些话题。
So, for instance, here, then, is the "thumbs up"
所以，下次再说吧。
that you might use on various platforms.
我们会在下节课中讨论这些话题。
And let me just stipulate that this is the Unicode code point.
所以，下次再说吧。
That is the number that Macs, PCs, and phones
我们会在下节课中讨论这些话题。
use underneath the hood to represent the default yellow "thumbs up."
But if you want to give it a medium skin tone,
我们会在下节课中讨论这些话题。
you still use that same number, that same pattern of 0's and 1's,
or switches, underneath the hood.
或者开关，在引擎盖下面。
But you use a few more switches that the computer or phone
但是你用更多开关，让电脑或手机
will interpret as, "Oh, you don't want to see the default in yellow
会解释为，“哦，你不想要看到默认的黄色
because of this second number that's in the computer's memory somewhere.
因为这个第二个数字存在于电脑的内存中的某个地方。”
You want me to adjust it to be the medium skin tone or any
你想让我调整它，让它变成中等肤色，或任何
of the other values, instead."
其他值，而不是。”
So that's the engineering solution to this problem
所以这就是这个问题的工程解决方案
of just trying to represent different ranges of emoji here.
只是试图在这里表示不同的表情符号范围。
Well, what about something like this?
好吧，像这样的东西呢？
There's a lot more combinatorics, nowadays,
现在，你的键盘上有很多组合，
on your keyboard for relationships, for instance.
比如，用于表示关系。
So here is a "couple with heart" here.
所以这里有一个“带心心的情侣”。
So the couple, here, of course, is represented with, apparently,
所以这对情侣，当然，用这个数字表示，显然，
this number here.
是这个数字。
But that's it.
但就是这样。
But if you want to be more specific-- like man and woman,
但是如果你想更具体一点 - 比如男人和女人，
or man-man, woman-woman-- it's the same idea,
或者男人男人，女人女人 - 都是一样的想法，
but we just need to express ourselves a little-- with a little
我们只需要稍微表达一下自己 - 用一点点
more information.
更多信息。
So, for instance, the way the Unicode folks came up with,
例如，Unicode 的人几年前想出来的表示方法是，
years ago, to represent, for instance, a woman with a heart and a man,
比如一个女人带心心和一个男人，
from left to right, would be using these values.
从左到右，会用这些值。
So things just escalated quickly, but only
所以事情迅速升级，但只是
in the sense that we're using more bits, more 0's and 1's, to represent,
从某种意义上说，我们正在使用更多的比特，更多的 0 和 1 来表示，
more expressively, this particular combination.
更具表现力地表达这个特定的组合。
So this happens to be the number in Unicode
所以这个数字恰好是 Unicode 中
that represents the woman at left.
表示左边女人的那个数字。
This is the number that represents the man at right.
这是表示右边男人的数字。
And this is the pair of numbers that represents
而这两个数字代表
the heart in the middle, sometimes red, sometimes pink, displayed here as pink.
中间的心，有时是红色，有时是粉色，这里显示为粉色。
But if we want to change the combination, for instance, to be,
但是如果我们想改变这个组合，例如，变成
say, woman--
比如，女人 -
if we want to change the combination to be woman-woman,
如果我们想把这个组合改成女人女人，
notice that, now, the left and the rightmost numbers match.
注意，现在，最左边和最右边的数字匹配了。
Or if we flip it back to man-man, it's just using different numbers
或者如果我们把它翻转回男人男人，它只是用不同的数字
on the tail end again.
在结尾处再次。
And meanwhile, if I rewind, there's these two identical values here.
同时，如果我倒带，这里有两个相同的数值。
These are called zero-width joiners or ZWNJ characters.
这些叫做零宽度连接符或 ZWNJ 字符。
It just is a special number that humans reserve to say,
它只是一个特殊的数字，人类保留下来说，
glue the emoji at the left to the emoji on the right and so forth.
把左边的表情符号粘到右边的表情符号上，依此类推。
So it connects ideas in this way.
所以它以这种方式连接想法。
So there's actually a lot of emojis, nowadays,
所以现在有很多表情符号，
that are a combination of different things.
它们是不同事物的组合。
"Heart on fire" is one that's, technically,
“燃烧的心”就是一个，从技术上来说，
the combination of a heart emoji, the fire emoji,
是心形表情符号和火焰表情符号的组合，
joined together, numerically, in this way.
以这种方式在数字上连接在一起。
So computer scientists who come up with these things
所以那些想出这些东西的计算机科学家
are just reducing things to representations.
只是将事物简化为表示。
All we have at our disposal are 0's and 1's.
我们所能利用的只有 0 和 1。
So we all just need to agree, ultimately--
所以我们都需要达成一致，最终 -
whether we're Google, Microsoft, or the like-- how we're going to standardize
无论是谷歌，微软，还是其他类似公司 - 我们将如何标准化
these kinds of things as information.
这些信息。
Questions, then, on how characters are represented in a computer,
那么，关于字符如何在电脑中表示，
be it English or any other language?
无论是英语还是任何其他语言？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: How is the plus a number?
观众：加号怎么是一个数字呢？
DAVID J. MALAN: How is the what?
大卫·J·马兰：什么怎么是数字？
AUDIENCE: The plus, the U+.
观众：加号，U+。
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, the U+ is just a convention, really.
大卫·J·马兰：哦，U+ 只是一个约定，真的。
So U+ represents a special Unicode character,
所以 U+ 代表一个特殊的 Unicode 字符，
which is a U with a plus in the middle.
它是一个中间有加号的 U。
And this is just the convention for saying,
而这只是一个约定，用于表示，
hey, everyone, here comes a number that represents a Unicode code point.
嘿，大家好，这里有一个数字，它代表一个 Unicode 码点。
The U and the 1 have no-- sorry.
U 和 1 没有 - 对不起。
The U and the plus have no mathematical significance.
U 和加号没有数学意义。
It's just a visual clue to folks.
它只是一个视觉提示。
Other questions on representing text in this way?
关于以这种方式表示文本的其他问题？
All right.
好的。
So what about colors?
那么颜色呢？
We've already started looking at pictures.
我们已经开始看图片了。
Well, how are those pictures, be it emojis or anything else, represented?
那么，那些图片，无论是表情符号还是其他任何东西，是如何表示的呢？
One of the most common ways is just with RGB--
最常见的方法之一就是用 RGB -
red, green, and blue.
红，绿，蓝。
It turns out that if we just keep track of how much red should
事实证明，如果我们只记录屏幕上应该有多少红色，
be on the screen, and how much green, and how much blue, combined together,
有多少绿色，有多少蓝色，组合在一起，
that gives us every color of the rainbow,
就能得到彩虹中的所有颜色，
from white to black and everything in between.
从白色到黑色，以及介于两者之间的所有颜色。
So how do we represent an amount of red, and green, and blue?
那么我们如何表示红色、绿色和蓝色的数量呢？
Well, frankly, just with three different numbers.
坦白地说，就用三个不同的数字。
And this is how computers typically represent colors.
这就是电脑通常表示颜色的方式。
Every one of the dots on your computer screen or your phone screen
电脑屏幕或手机屏幕上的每一个点
is called a pixel.
被称为像素。
And every single dot underneath the hood has three numbers associated with it,
而每个点在引擎盖下面都有三个数字与之关联，
so three numbers, three numbers, three numbers for every little dot.
所以每个小点都有三个数字，三个数字，三个数字。
And those three numbers, together, say how much red, green, and blue
而这三个数字加在一起，表示在那个位置应该显示多少红色、绿色和蓝色。
should the device display at that location.
设备应该显示在那个位置。
So, for instance, if you had a dot on your screen
例如，如果你的屏幕上有一个点
that said, "use this much red, this much green this much blue," because each
说：“用这么多红色，这么多绿色，这么多蓝色，”因为每个
of these numbers, I'll tell you, are one byte or eight bits,
这些数字，我会告诉你，都是一个字节或八个比特，
which means the total possible values is 0 to 255--
这意味着可能的总值为 0 到 255 -
let me just ballpark that the 72, it feels like a medium amount of red
让我随便说一下，72 感觉像是中等量的红色
because it's in between 0 and 255.
因为它介于 0 和 255 之间。
73 is a medium amount of green, and 33 of blue is just a little bit.
73 是中等量的绿色，而 33 的蓝色只是一点点。
So if you combine a medium amount of red, green, and a little bit of blue,
所以如果你把中等量的红色、绿色和一点点蓝色混合在一起，
anyone want to guess what color of the rainbow this is?
有人想猜猜彩虹中的这种颜色吗？
AUDIENCE: Brown.
观众：棕色。
DAVID J. MALAN: Sorry?
大卫·J·马兰：你说什么？
AUDIENCE: Brown.
观众：棕色。
DAVID J. MALAN: Brown?
大卫·J·马兰：棕色？
So, close.
所以，差不多。
It's a little more yellow than it is brown.
它比棕色更偏黄一点。
But if we combine them, it looks a little something like this.
但如果我们把它们结合起来，看起来会有点像这样。
This is just CS trivia, not something that even
这只是计算机科学的琐事，而不是我甚至
I would be able to eyeball, unless I came up with that particular example.
能够凭肉眼看出来的，除非我自己想出了那个特定的例子。
But wait a minute.
等等。
We've seen these numbers before.
我们以前见过这些数字。
72, 73, 33 represented what--
72、73、33 代表什么——
AUDIENCE: Hi!
观众：你好！
DAVID J. MALAN: --a few minutes ago?
大卫·J·马兰：——几分钟前？
So it meant "Hi!" but here I am, claiming, no, no, no, no,
所以它意味着“你好！”，但现在我说，不，不，不，不，
that means yellow.
那是黄色。
How do you reconcile this?
你怎么解释这个？
Well, at the end of the day, this is all we have,
好吧，归根结底，这就是我们拥有的全部，
0's and 1's, whether you think of them as numbers,
0 和 1，无论你把它们看作数字，
or letters, or even colors now.
还是字母，甚至现在的颜色。
But it depends on the context.
但这取决于上下文。
So if you've received a text message or an email,
所以，如果你收到了一条短信或一封电子邮件，
odds are the pattern of 0's and 1's that the computer
很可能计算机显示给你的 0 和 1 的模式将被解释为文本，因为那是
is showing you are going to be interpreted as text because that's
短信或电子邮件的全部意义所在。
the whole point of a text message or an email.
如果，不过，你打开了 MacOS、iOS、Windows 或者 Android 的
If, though, you opened up MacOS's or iOS's or Windows's or Android's
计算器应用程序，相同的 0 和 1 的模式可能会
calculator app, the same pattern of 0's and 1's might
被解释为数字，用于进行加法、减法或其他运算。
be interpreted as numbers for some addition, or subtraction, or whatever.
如果你在 Photoshop 中打开相同的 0 和 1 的模式，
If you open the same pattern of 0's and 1's in Photoshop,
比如在图形程序中，它们将在那个上下文中被解释为
like a graphics program, they're going to be interpreted, in that context,
颜色。
as colors.
所以上下文很重要。
So context matters.
而且，实际上，从下周开始，当你
And, indeed, as soon as next week, when you
开始使用名为 C 的语言编写代码时，
start writing code in that language called C,
你将有责任告诉计算机，将
the onus will be on you, the programmer, to tell the computer, interpret
以下位序列解释为数字、字母或其他东西。
the following sequence of bits as a number, or a letter, or something else.
你甚至不必担心 0 和 1 是什么，
And you won't have to even worry about what the 0's and 1's are,
但你需要给计算机一个提示，说明你正在表示什么类型的文件
but you need to give the computer a hint as to what type of file
或数据片段。
or piece of data you're representing.
所以，这就是位。
So that gives us bits.
而且你实际上可以在屏幕上看到这些点，这些像素。
And you can actually see these dots, these pixels on the screen.
让我放大，放大。
Let me zoom in, zoom in.
我们在这里看到了，只是这个表情符号，归根结底，
And here we have it, just with this emoji, which, at the end of the day,
是苹果公司的人在这种情况下的一个图画。
is a picture that someone at Apple, in this case, drew.
如果你真的放大，或者拿起你的手机或电视
And you can see-- if you really zoom in, or take your phone or TV
把它放在你脸前，你会看到所有这些点，
and really put it close to your face, you'll see all of these dots,
这取决于硬件。
depending on the hardware.
每个点，每个方块，都是
And each of these dots, these squares, is
存储 24 位或 3 个字节，24 位，24 位，24 位。
storing 24 bits or three bytes, 24 bits, 24 bits, 24 bits.
这就是为什么，点，点，点，如果你有
And that's whey, dot, dot, dot, if you've
比如一张照片，是 3 兆字节，也就是
got a photograph, for instance, that's three megabytes, which
300 万字节，那么很可能里面有 100 万像素，
is 3 million bytes, well, odds are there's 1 million pixels therein
因为你每个像素使用 3 个字节
because you're using three bytes per pixel
来表示每个颜色。
to represent each of those colors.
这有点过于简化了，但这
That's a bit of an oversimplification, but that's
就是为什么图像和照片现在越来越大。
why images and photos are getting bigger and bigger nowadays.
因为我们在文件中添加了更多的像素。
Because we're throwing even more pixels into the file.
音乐——
Music--
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
——你如何用数字的方式表示音乐，
--how could you represent music, digitally,
只用 0 和 1，或者说数字，来表示？
using just 0's and 1's, or numbers, really?
任何直觉，无论是音乐家还是非音乐家？
Any instinct, whether a musician or not?
是的。
Yeah.
观众：音符可以用数字来表示。
AUDIENCE: The notes could be represented by a number.
大卫·J·马兰：是的，所以我们可以用数字来表示音符。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so we can just represent notes by a number.
所以 A 是一个数字，B 也是。也许升调或降调是另一个数字。
So A is some number, and B. And maybe sharp or flat is some other number.
但音符可能不足以表达一些——
But note might not be quite enough for some--
是的？
yeah?
观众：[听不清]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
大卫·J·马兰：啊，好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Ah, OK.
所以一个音符——一个数字来表示音符本身，
So one note-- one number to represent the note, itself,
声音或音高；另一个数字来表示持续时间。
the sound or the pitch; one other number to represent the duration.
在钢琴的语境中，演奏者按下琴键的时间有多长？
In the context of piano, how long is the human holding the key down?
也许我可以再想一个，响度。
And maybe I can think of a third, the loudness.
演奏者弹奏那个音符的力度有多大？
How hard has the person played that note?
所以，至少用三个数字，你可以
So, minimally, with three numbers, you could
想象用这种方式来表示音乐。
imagine representing music, as well.
而且，实际上，当你在听声音时，计算机很可能就是这样做的。
And, indeed, that's very well might be what computers
视频呢？
are doing when you listen to sound.
你如何用数字来表示视频？
What about video?
是的？
How could you represent videos, as well?
观众：通过很多图像。
Yeah?
大卫·J·马兰：是的，很多图像。
AUDIENCE: Through many images.
所以，如果你曾经制作过电影或者看过一些小字说明，
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, many images.
每秒 30 帧，FPS，或每秒 29 帧
So if you've ever produced a film or looked at some of the fine print,
只是说明了屏幕上每秒播放多少张图片。
30 frames per second, FPS, or 29 frames per second
但实际上，这就是计算机上视频文件的所有内容，
is just how many pictures are flying across the screen.
很多图片以极快的速度在你我眼前移动，以至于我们的大脑
But that's really all a video file is on a computer,
把它解释为实际的运动。
lots of pictures moving so quickly in front of us that you and I, our brains,
实际上，从前，电影，
interpolate that as being actual motion.
就像那些给予运动错觉的图片，
And, in fact, from yesteryear, motion pictures,
即使屏幕上每秒只有 30 张左右的图片在移动。
it's like pictures that are giving the illusion of motion,
所以，现在我们有了一种方法来表示信息，无论是作为
even though there's only 30 or so of them flying across the screen.
输入还是输出，无论是数字、字母、图像，还是其他任何东西。
So we have a way, now, to represent information, both as
现在，让我们把注意力集中在那个黑盒子里，
input and output, whether it's numbers, letters, images, anything else.
可以说是，我们在那里有算法，一步一步的指令。
Let's now focus on what's inside of that black box,
so to speak, wherein we have algorithms, step-by-step instructions
可以这么说，我们有算法，一步一步的指令
for solving some problem.
用于解决一些问题。
Now, what do I mean by "algorithms" or "step-by-step instructions"?
现在，“算法”或“分步指令”是什么意思？
Well, maybe, if we were to turn this into code--
好吧，也许，如果我们要把它变成代码——
and that's how we'll connect the dots, ultimately, today.
这就是我们最终将要连接这些点的办法，今天。
Code is just the implementation, in computers, of algorithms.
代码只是在计算机中实现算法。
An algorithm can be something we do in the physical world.
算法可以是我们现实世界中所做的事情。
Code is how we implement that exact same idea, in the context of a computer,
代码是我们如何在计算机环境下实现相同的想法，
instead.
而不是。
And here, for instance, is a very common application inside of a computer,
举个例子，这里是在电脑中非常常见的应用，
for your context.
对于你的情况来说。
This is the iOS version of the icon.
这是 iOS 版本的图标。
And, typically, if you click on that icon,
而且，通常情况下，如果你点击那个图标，
you'll see something like all of your contacts here,
你将看到类似于你所有联系人的内容，
typically, alphabetical, by first name or last name.
通常情况下，按姓或名进行字母排序。
And your phone or your computer lets you often search for someone's name
你的手机或电脑经常让你可以搜索某人的姓名
at the very top.
在最上面。
And it will autocomplete, and it'll be pretty darn fast.
它会自动补全，而且速度会很快。
But it'll be pretty darn fast because the programmers who
但它会非常快，因为那些
implemented that application are looking for someone quickly for you.
实现该应用的程序员正在为你快速寻找某人。
Now, I can do this old school style, whereby we have one of these things
现在，我可以使用老式的做法，即使用其中一个东西
from yesteryear, an actual phone book.
来自过去年代的，一个真正的电话簿。
So, in a physical phone book like this, you might have 1,000 pages.
所以，在这样的一个实体电话簿中，你可能有 1000 页。
And on every page are a bunch of names and a bunch of numbers.
而且每一页都有很多姓名和电话号码。
And as I flip through this, I could look for someone specific.
当我翻阅它时，我可以寻找特定的人。
So suppose I want to call John Harvard, who's-- the first name, of course,
假设我想打电话给约翰·哈佛，他是——当然，他的名字是
starts with a J. Well, I could just turn, page by page,
以 J 开头的。好吧，我可以一页一页地翻，
looking for John Harvard.
寻找约翰·哈佛。
And if he's not there, I keep turning and turning.
如果他不在那里，我继续翻阅。
So this is an algorithm.
所以，这就是一个算法。
I'm stepping through the phone book, one page at a time.
我正在一页一页地翻阅电话簿。
Is it correct, this algorithm, assuming I'm looking down?
这个算法正确吗？假设我在往下看？
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
I mean, it's stupidly slow because why am
我的意思是，它太慢了，因为为什么我
I wasting my time with the A's, and the B's, and the so forth?
浪费时间去看 A、B 以及其他的字母？
I could probably take bigger bites out of it.
我可能可以更快地找到他。
But it is correct.
但它是正确的。
And that's going to be one of the goals of writing code, is to, of course,
而编写代码的目标之一就是，当然，
solve the problem you care about correctly.
正确地解决你关心的问题。
So correctness goes without saying, or else what's
所以，正确性是毋庸置疑的，否则写代码或解决问题——或者实现
the point of writing the code or solving-- or implementing
算法的意义何在？
the algorithm?
算法？
All right.
好的。
Well, let me at least speed things up.
好吧，至少让我加快速度。
So, instead of one page at a time, so, two, four, six, eight--
所以，不再是一页一页，而是两页、四页、六页、八页——
no, ignore that-- 10, 12, 14, 16, and so forth.
不，忽略那个——10 页、12 页、14 页、16 页，等等。
It's a little hard to do, physically, but it sounded faster.
从物理上来说，这有点难，但听起来更快。
It was twice as fast, theoretically, but is it correct?
理论上，它快了一倍，但它是正确的吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
观众：不。
DAVID J. MALAN: So, no.
大卫·J·马兰：所以，不。
Why?
为什么？
Yeah?
是吧？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, you might [INAUDIBLE].
观众：是的，你可能会 [听不清]。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, I might miss John Harvard because, just by accident,
大卫·J·马兰：是的，我可能会错过约翰·哈佛，因为，只是碰巧，
he might get sandwiched between two pages.
他可能夹在两页之间。
But do I have to throw the algorithm out altogether?
但是我是否必须完全放弃这个算法？
Probably not.
可能不会。
Once I reach the K section, which is past the J section,
一旦我到达 K 部分，它在 J 部分之后，
I could double back at least one page, at least, [PATS TELEPHONE BOOK]
我至少可以回退一页，至少，[拍电话簿]
and just make sure I didn't blow past him completely.
并确保我没有完全错过他。
So that is twice as fast, because I'm going two pages
所以它快了一倍，因为我一次翻两页
at a time, plus one extra step.
再加上一步。
So it's still an improvement.
所以它仍然是一个改进。
So the first algorithm, worst case, if it's
所以第一个算法，最糟糕的情况，如果它不是
not John, but someone whose name starts with Z,
约翰，而是某个名字以 Z 开头的人，
that might take me a full 1,000 steps.
这可能需要我 1000 步。
The second algorithm is just 500 steps because I'm
第二个算法只需要 500 步，因为我
going two pages at a time plus one, in case I have to double back,
一次翻两页，再加上一步，以防我不得不回退，
but that's in the worst case.
但这是最糟糕的情况。
But most of us in the-- in yesteryear, and what Apple, and Google, and others
但我们大多数人——在过去年代，以及苹果、谷歌和其他公司
are actually doing is, in software or here, physically,
实际上正在做的事情是，在软件中或是在这里，在现实中，
we're typically going, roughly, to the middle.
我们通常会直接翻到中间。
Especially if there's no cheat sheet on the side, like A through Z,
特别是如果没有像 A 到 Z 这样的索引，
I'm just going to go to, roughly, the middle.
我会直接翻到中间。
And, oh, here I am, not surprisingly, in the M section.
而且，哦，不出所料，我来到了 M 部分。
But what do I now know.
但我现在知道了什么。
If this is the M section, where is John Harvard?
如果这是 M 部分，那么约翰·哈佛在哪里？
So, clearly, to the left, alphabetically.
所以，很明显，在字母顺序上，他应该在左边。
And so here is where we can take a much bigger bite out of the problem.
所以，这里我们可以更快地解决问题。
We can really divide and conquer this problem
我们可以将问题分解，然后逐个解决
by tearing [TEARS BOOK] the problem in half, throwing half of it
通过撕开 [撕书] 问题的一半，扔掉一半
away, 500 pages away, leaving me with a smaller problem,
500 页，留下一个更小的问题，
half as big, that I can really just now repeat.
规模缩小了一半，我可以重复之前的步骤。
So I go, roughly, here, and now I'm in the E section.
所以，我粗略地翻到这里，现在我来到了 E 部分。
So I went a little too far back.
所以我退得太远了。
But what do I now know?
但我现在知道了什么？
If this is the E pages, where's John?
如果这是 E 部分，那么约翰在哪里？
AUDIENCE: To the right.
观众：在右边。
DAVID J. MALAN: So now he's to the right.
大卫·J·马兰：所以现在他在右边。
So I can-- again, hopefully, he's not on that page.
所以我——再次，希望他不在那页。
I can tear the problem in half again, throw that 250 pages away.
我再次将问题分成两半，扔掉 250 页。
And now I've gone from 1,000 to 500 to 250 pages.
现在我已经从 1000 页减少到了 500 页，再减少到了 250 页。
Now I'm moving because the first algorithm was one page at a time,
现在我正在移动，因为第一个算法是一页一页地翻，
second was two.
第二个是两页两页地翻。
This is hundreds of pages at a time.
现在是一次翻几百页。
And if I go, roughly, again, to the middle; roughly,
如果我再次粗略地翻到中间，粗略地
to the middle; roughly, to the middle, hopefully, I'll
翻到中间，粗略地翻到中间，希望我会
find John Harvard on one final page.
最终在某一页找到约翰·哈佛。
Can only do this once, but one final page.
只能做一次，但只剩最后一页了。
So that invites the question, I would think,
我想这会引出一个问题，
if the phone book does have 1,000 or so pages,
如果电话簿真的有1000页左右，
how many times can I divide the problem in half to get down to one last page?
我需要将问题分成几半才能得到最后一页？
So it's, roughly, 10.
所以大约是10次。
And the quick math is 1,000 goes to 500 to 250 to 125 to 67 something.
快速计算一下，1000变成500，变成250，变成125，变成67左右。
So we have to deal with rounding issues, eventually.
所以我们最终需要处理舍入问题。
But assuming we work out the math, it's, roughly, 10 page tears.
但假设我们算出来，大约是10页撕裂。
And that's crazy faster than 1,000 pages and still faster than 500 pages.
这比1000页快多了，也比500页快。
So it's fundamentally better.
所以它从根本上来说更好。
And, indeed, if I finally get to that final page, in the software world,
事实上，如果我最终得到了那最后一页，在软件世界中，
you'd see something like this, John Harvard and his number,
你会看到这样的东西，约翰·哈佛和他的号码，
which you're welcome to call or text.
你可以随意打电话或发短信。
But that's how we now have our answer, much like the single page there.
但这就是我们现在得到答案的方式，就像那只有一页一样。
But let's consider just how efficient that actually is.
但让我们考虑一下这到底有多高效。
So here's a very rough, broad-- with broad strokes, a chart.
所以这里有一个非常粗略的图表，用粗线条画。
So here's an xy plot.
所以这里是一个xy图。
So here, on the horizontal, is going to be the size of the problem.
所以这里，在横轴上，是问题的规模。
And, by that, I mean, how many pages are we trying to go through?
我的意思是，我们试图翻阅多少页？
This would be zero pages.
这里代表零页。
This would be a lot of pages.
这里代表很多页。
How much time does it take to solve the problem?
解决这个问题需要多长时间？
How long does it take to find John Harvard or anyone else?
找到约翰·哈佛或其他任何人需要多长时间？
This means no time.
这里代表不需要时间。
This means a lot of time.
这里代表需要很长时间。
So what's the relationship among these algorithms?
那么这些算法之间有什么关系呢？
Well, the first one is actually just a straight line.
第一个实际上就是一条直线。
If there's n pages in the phone book, well, I
如果电话簿中有n页，那么我
claim that it's a one-to-one relationship.
声称这是一个一对一的关系。
Because if Verizon or the phone company adds another page next year,
因为如果Verizon或电话公司明年增加了一页，
that just means I might have one more step next year,
那也只意味着我明年可能需要多走一步，
as well, to find John Harvard or anyone else.
才能找到约翰·哈佛或其他人。
But the second algorithm, it's also a straight line,
但第二个算法也是一条直线，
but it's lower, even though it might not look obvious.
但它更低，尽管看起来可能不太明显。
And what do I mean by that?
我这是什么意思？
Well, let me just draw some temporary lines.
好吧，让我画几条临时的线。
If this is how many pages are in the phone book-- dot,
如果电话簿有这么多页——点，
dot, dot-- notice that it takes this much time, on the red line,
点，点——注意，在红线上需要这么长时间，
to solve the problem.
才能解决这个问题。
But if I, instead, use the second algorithm,
但如果我使用第二个算法，
it takes me half as much time.
我只需要一半的时间。
So, even though they're both straight lines,
所以，虽然它们都是直线，
one is strictly lower than the other, which means it's faster.
但其中一个严格低于另一个，这意味着它更快。
It's better.
它更好。
But the third algorithm is a fundamentally different shape,
但第三个算法的形状从根本上来说不同，
and it looks a little something like this.
它看起来有点像这样。
And it looks like it's going to flatten, flatten, flatten out,
看起来它会变平，变平，一直变平，
but it never does.
但它永远不会。
It just rises ever so slowly.
它只是非常缓慢地上升。
And what this means is that if maybe Cambridge and Allston, here
这意味着，如果可能的话，剑桥和奥尔斯顿，这里
in Massachusetts, merge next year, so we go from 1,000 page phone book
在马萨诸塞州，明年合并，那么我们就从1000页的电话簿
to a 2,000 page phone book, that means, if we're here this year,
变成了2000页的电话簿，这意味着，如果我们今年在这里，
we're over here next year.
明年我们就在这里了。
It's not all that much higher.
它并没有高出太多。
But it would be much higher if we were using the first two algorithms.
但如果我们使用前两种算法，它会高很多。
Why?
为什么？
It'd be an extra 1,000 steps to find someone in that combined phone
这将需要多走1000步才能在合并的电话簿中找到某人
book or maybe another 500 steps.
或者可能需要多走500步。
But, to be clear, if we're using my third and final algorithm,
但明确地说，如果我们使用我的第三个也是最后一个算法，
how many more steps will it take me next year,
明年我需要多走几步，
when Cambridge and Allston merge into one 2,000-page phone book?
当剑桥和奥尔斯顿合并成一本2000页的电话簿时？
Just one more step, no big deal.
只有一步，没什么大不了的。
It's one more page tear.
就是撕一页。
And this is what we mean, ultimately, about not just writing
这就是我们最终想要表达的意思，不只是写
code or implementing algorithms that are correct, but, now,
代码或实现正确的算法，而是，现在，
that are well-designed or efficient, specifically.
设计良好或高效的算法，特别是。
And this is what makes someone a better programmer, perhaps,
这就是可能让某人成为比其他人更好的程序员的原因，
than someone else, or a better problem-solver than someone else,
比其他人更优秀，或成为比其他人更好的问题解决者，
is acquiring, over time, these skills.
是随着时间的推移，习得这些技能。
So that, sure, you could solve the problem quickly and dirtily,
因此，当然，你可以快速地、粗糙地解决问题，
so to speak, but if you're going to have a lot of data
可以这么说，但如果你要处理大量的数据，
eventually, be it in your phone book or maybe your Google website index,
最终，无论是在你的电话簿里还是你的谷歌网站索引中，
if you're searching the web, you're going
如果你正在搜索网络，你会
to want to try to think about how to design algorithms that look like this.
想要尝试思考如何设计这样的算法。
Mathematically, this is called a logarithm.
在数学上，这被称为对数。
And it's log base 2 because I'm halving, halving, halving, again and again.
这是以2为底的对数，因为我不断地将数据减半，减半，减半。
But, for now, just know that it's a fundamentally faster and different
但现在，你只需要知道，它从根本上来说更快，而且形状不同。
shape.
形状。
So, among our goals in CS50, ultimately, is not just
所以，在CS50中，我们的目标最终不仅仅是
to write and solve problems correctly, but, ultimately, ever more efficiently,
正确地编写和解决问题，而是最终要更有效率，
as well.
也是。
Any questions, then, on these ideas of efficiency and design?
那么，关于效率和设计，你们有什么问题吗？
Any questions here?
这里有人有疑问吗？
Yeah, in back?
后面那位同学？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
大卫·J·马兰：问得好。
Just to repeat it, can a graph like this capture the accuracy of the algorithm?
重复一遍，这样的图表可以反映出算法的准确性吗？
Short answer, no.
简短的回答，不行。
For instance, if I drew a straight line that
例如，如果我画一条直线，
is super low on this graph, which would imply that the algorithm takes
在这张图上非常低，这意味着算法需要
the same amount of time, no matter how many pages there are,
相同的时间，无论有多少页，
my algorithm might actually be to just pull a random page from the phone
我的算法可能是从电话簿中随机抽取一页，一步到位，然后说，就是这页。
book, one step, and say, here it is.
书，一步到位，然后说，就是这页。
But that's not necessarily going to be accurate,
但它不一定是准确的，
unless I get really, really lucky.
除非我非常非常幸运。
So the graph really only speaks to efficiency
所以这个图表实际上只说明了效率
and the design of the algorithm, not the correctness of it.
以及算法的设计，而不是它的正确性。
To analyze the correctness, you need to use another mechanism altogether,
要分析正确性，你需要使用完全不同的机制，
namely, logic.
即逻辑。
Other questions now, on efficiency, in this way?
现在，关于效率方面还有其他问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right.
好的。
So, with that in mind, let's begin to translate this to some actual code.
所以，考虑到这一点，让我们开始将它翻译成一些实际的代码。
And, in fact, before we look at, today, one actual programming language,
实际上，在我们今天查看一种实际的编程语言之前，
albeit a graphical one, let's consider something called pseudocode.
尽管它是一个图形化的语言，让我们考虑一下一种叫做伪代码的东西。
So pseudocode has no formal meaning.
所以伪代码没有正式的意义。
Generally, you write it in English or whatever your own human language is.
一般来说，你用英语或你自己的语言来写。
But you write your thoughts down tersely, succinct, but precisely.
但是你要简洁、扼要、准确地写下你的想法。
You try to really convey your thoughts, not with a wave of the hand,
你试图真正表达你的想法，而不是用挥手的方式，
metaphorically, but step by step, precisely.
比喻地，而是逐步地、准确地。
So what do I mean by this?
那么我这是什么意思呢？
Here might be some representative pseudocode
这里可能有一些代表性的伪代码
via which I describe that third and final algorithm in a way
通过它，我以一种方式描述了第三个也是最后一个算法
that I could hand it to you and you could do the same at home.
我可以把它交给你，你也可以在家里做同样的事情。
Or I could hand it to someone at Google, and they could implement it in Android.
或者我可以把它交给谷歌的人，他们可以在Android上实现它。
Or I could hand it to someone at Apple, and they could implement it in iOS.
或者我可以把它交给苹果的人，他们可以在iOS上实现它。
So, step one, I claimed, was "Pick up phone book."
所以，第一步，我声称是“拿起电话簿”。
Step two was "Open to the middle of the phone book."
第二步是“打开电话簿的中间”。
Step three, "Look at the page," as I did.
第三步，“看看页面”，就像我做的那样。
And now things get a little more interesting.
现在事情变得有点有趣了。
Step four, "If person is on page," I have to make a decision.
第四步，“如果这个人在这页上”，我必须做出决定。
Presumably, what should I do if John Harvard is on the page I'm looking at?
可以想见，如果我正在看的页面上有John Harvard，我该怎么办？
So stop and probably make the call, or email, or whatever the goal might be.
所以停下来，可能打电话，或者发邮件，或者任何目标。
And so I'm going to actually indent this, visually, by a few spaces,
所以我要实际地缩进这个，从视觉上来说，缩进几个空格，
just to make clear that you should only do line five if the answer to line four
只是为了明确，只有当第四行的答案是
is yes.
是“是”时，你才应该做第五行。
Otherwise, you don't bother.
否则，你就别费心了。
The next thing I'm going to do, line six, is consider another possibility.
接下来我要做的事情，第六行，是考虑另一种可能性。
"If the person I'm looking for is earlier
“如果我正在寻找的人更早
in the book," what do I want to do?
在书里，”我想做什么？
Well, I could write--
好吧，我可以写--
I could describe this in a bunch of ways.
我可以以多种方式描述它。
I'm going to do this tersely, as follows.
我将简明扼要地做，如下所示。
"Open to the middle of the left half of the book,
“打开书的左侧一半的中间，
so it's open to the middle of the left half of the book.
所以它打开了书的左侧一半的中间。
And then, what am I going to do?
然后，我要做什么？
Well, I've just divided the problem into something smaller.
好吧，我只是把问题分解成更小的部分。
But it's fundamentally the same problem.
但它本质上是同一个问题。
It's just a fewer number of pages.
只是页数更少。
So I'm just going to go back to line three and do it again
所以我只需要回到第三行，再做一次
because the problem is just getting smaller and smaller, presumably.
因为问题越来越小，可以想见。
Else, if the person I'm looking for is later in the book,
否则，如果我正在寻找的人在书的后面，
open to the middle of the right half of the book,
打开书的右侧一半的中间，
and, also, "Go back to line 3."
并且，“回到第三行”。
But there's a fourth possibility and its failure
但有一种第四种可能性，以及它的失败
to realize, sometimes, that there's other possible outcomes that
有时，意识到还有其他可能的结果
make computers crash, or spinning beach balls, or the like,
会让电脑崩溃，或者出现旋转的沙漏，或者类似的情况，
if a programmer doesn't anticipate some situation.
如果程序员没有预料到某些情况。
What's the fourth possible situation, when looking for John Harvard?
找John Harvard时，第四种可能的情况是什么？
AUDIENCE: If they're not in the book.
观众：如果他们不在书里。
DAVID J. MALAN: If they're not in the book, at all.
大卫·J·马兰：如果他们根本不在书里。
And, indeed, I might get to the very last page and John Harvard's not even
事实上，我可能会翻到最后一页，John Harvard甚至都不
on that one.
在那页上。
I'd better handle that and say, else, as a catchall, just quit altogether.
我最好处理一下，并且说，否则，作为兜底，干脆退出。
And, truly, often, in your Macs, PCs, phones,
而且，确实，通常，在你的Mac、PC、手机中，
when they freeze, or, again, spinning beach ball, or the like,
当它们冻结时，或者，再次出现旋转的沙漏，或者类似情况，
and just weird things happen, that's just
以及奇怪的事情发生，那只是
because some human made a dumb mistake.
因为有人犯了一个愚蠢的错误。
And they didn't realize that you could somehow get your phone or your laptop
他们没有意识到，你可能会以某种方式让你的手机或笔记本电脑
into a configuration that they didn't anticipate.
进入他们没有预料到的配置。
So we're going to try to handle that here.
所以我们要在这里尝试处理一下。
Now this is just one way of writing pseudocode.
现在这只是写伪代码的一种方式。
There's no one way to do this.
没有一种唯一的方法。
All of us in this room could come up with slightly different pseudocode.
我们房间里的每个人都可以想出稍微不同的伪代码。
But I think you'll find characteristic are certain building
但我认为你会发现，特征是一些特定的构建
blocks in all of our answers.
块，在我们的所有答案中。
Here, in yellow, are what, as of today, we're
这里，用黄色，是那些，从今天开始，我们将
going to start calling "functions," technically speaking.
开始称之为“函数”，从技术上来说。
These are like actions or verbs that literally, in this case, tell me
这些就像动作或动词，在这种情况中，它们实际上告诉我
what to do.
该做什么。
Next, we're going to have these things, conditionals,
接下来，我们将有这些东西，条件，
forks in the road, so to speak, that take me down this path or another,
道路的分岔路口，这么说吧，它们带我走这条路或另一条路，
metaphorically.
比喻地。
So I do this thing or something else.
所以我做这件事或者其他事情。
But how do I decide if I want to go this way, or this way,
但我如何决定我想走这条路，还是那条路，
or this way, or this way?
还是这条路，还是那条路？
I need to ask a question.
我需要问一个问题。
And in programming, we'll typically use what
在编程中，我们通常会使用
are called Boolean expressions, named after a mathematician, Boole.
叫做布尔表达式，以数学家布尔命名。
And a Boolean expression is essentially just a question
布尔表达式本质上只是一个问题
with a yes/no answer, a true or false answer, a 1 or 0 answer.
有一个是/否的答案，一个真或假的答案，一个1或0的答案。
It doesn't matter how you think about it, but it's got two possible answers.
无论你如何思考它，但它都有两种可能的答案。
And so you can think of these as being expressions with question marks,
所以你可以把这些想象成带有问号的表达式，
even though I didn't draw such.
尽管我没有画出来。
Person on page, person earlier in book, person later in book,
人在这页上，人更早地在书里，人更晚地在书里，
those are Boolean expressions.
这些都是布尔表达式。
And they tell me whether I should go down one fork in the road or another.
它们告诉我我应该走一条分岔路还是另一条。
And, lastly, there's this, "Go back to line 3," in two different places.
最后，这里还有“返回到第 3 行”这句话，出现在两个不同的位置。
That represents what we call a "loop," some kind of cycle that's
这代表我们所说的“循环”，某种反复执行的周期。
doing something again and again.
一遍又一遍地做着某件事。
Now these are just a few building blocks here--
现在，这里只是一些基本的构建块——
functions, conditionals, Boolean expressions, loops.
函数、条件语句、布尔表达式和循环。
But you'll find that they're characteristic of so
但你会发现，它们是如此之多的不同语言的特征，其中一种我们今天将要学习，另一种我们将在下周学习。
many different languages, one of which we'll look at today, another of which
许多不同的语言，其中一种我们今天将要学习，另一种我们将在下周学习。
we'll look at next week.
我们将在下周学习。
And those include, indeed, C, and Python, and other languages still.
它们包括 C、Python，以及其他一些语言。
And so this is why we focus on these basics
所以这就是为什么我们在这最初的几天里专注于这些基础知识
and fundamentals in these early days because we're
和基本原理，因为我们将会
going to see them again and again.
反复看到它们。
So even if you feel like that fire hose is hitting you sometime,
所以即使你感觉像水管喷射了你，
we'll give you, today, ultimately, more visuals
我们今天将最终为您提供更多视觉辅助
by which you can hang onto, so as to actually write code, ultimately,
以便您能抓住它们，最终实际编写代码，
in different languages and solve all sorts of problems.
用不同的语言解决各种各样的问题。
Now, we'd be remiss in not bringing up what's behind characters like Spot,
现在，如果我们不提及像 Spot 这样的角色背后的东西，我们会很疏忽，
and ChatGPT, and other software, artificial intelligence.
还有 ChatGPT 以及其他软件，人工智能。
And it turns out, to get to the point of AI,
事实证明，要达到人工智能的水平，
we're actually going to need more building blocks than just
我们实际上需要的不仅仅是函数、循环和条件语句。
functions, and loops, and conditionals.
函数、循环和条件语句。
It's not going to be quite that simple.
这不会那么简单。
But this has been a lot, so far.
但到目前为止，这已经很多了。
Let's go ahead, here, and take a five-minute break.
让我们在这里休息五分钟。
And when we resume, we'll take a look not only at AI,
当我们继续时，我们将不仅看一看人工智能，
but also a specific language called Scratch.
而且还将看一看一种名为 Scratch 的特定语言。
So no cake, just yet, but we'll come back in five.
所以还没有蛋糕，但我们将在五分钟后回来。
Before we dive back in, I just wanted to call out a special guest
在我们重新开始之前，我只想提一下一位特别的客人
that we have here today, beyond Spot, someone
除了 Spot 以外，今天来到这里的人，
who's come from even farther away.
他们来自更远的地方。
And, in fact, if any of you have taken CS50x, the OpenCourseWare version
事实上，如果你们中的任何人学习过 CS50x，也就是公开课版本
of the class, or dabbled in it over the past few years
的课程，或者在过去几年里尝试过它
in some of CS50's online social communities,
在 CS50 的一些在线社交社区中，
you might have had your questions answered
你可能得到了你的问题的解答
by a certain human from New Zealand.
来自新西兰的一位特定的人。
And she's come all this way, today, to spend this lecture with us.
而她今天千里迢迢来到这里，与我们共度这堂课。
This is CS50's own Brenda Anderson.
这位是 CS50 自己的布伦达·安德森。
If you might come up for acknowledgment from all of us here.
请你上来，接受我们所有人的致敬。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
It's not much, but just a little token of our thanks.
这不算什么，只是我们的一点感谢。
Brenda has helped, truly, thousands of students online
布伦达在过去几年里在线帮助了数千名学生。
for the past many years.
在过去几年里。
And, in fact, her own daughter has been the artist
事实上，她自己的女儿是艺术家
behind the duck that's about to loom large in CS50 this year and beyond.
创造了那只鸭子，它将在今年以及未来几年成为 CS50 的重要角色。
So, thank you to Brenda.
所以，感谢布伦达。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
So it's hard to escape a discussion of artificial intelligence, nowadays,
如今，我们很难回避人工智能的讨论，
but we thought we'd use this as an opportunity
但我们认为这是一个机会
to connect some of these dots.
将这些点联系起来。
Because, indeed, over the course of the semester,
因为，确实，在本学期的课程中，
we'll be-- not only be talking about artificial intelligence or AI,
我们将会—— 不仅讨论人工智能或 AI，
but really using it all the more constructively
而是更有效地利用它
to help you solve problems, help you get unblocked
帮助你解决问题，帮助你摆脱困境
when you hit a wall, cognitively or syntactically, when writing code.
当你遇到障碍，无论是认知上还是语法上，在编写代码时。
And, indeed, it's no accident that we have this duck here,
而且，确实，我们这里有这只鸭子并非偶然，
looming large, which is really the embodiment of the sort of AI
它占据了很大的空间，它实际上是你在今年的 CS50 中会体验到的那种人工智能的化身。
that you'll experience within CS50, itself, this year.
你在今年的 CS50 中会体验到的那种人工智能的化身。
So let's talk about the so-called chatbots that
所以，让我们来谈谈那些所谓的聊天机器人，
inspired some of those headlines with which we began
引发了一些我们开课时提到的那些标题，
class, that weren't quite on the nose.
那些标题并不完全准确。
So the class will still be taught by us humans,
所以这门课仍然由我们人类教授，
but helped by this CS50 duck, a chatbot of sorts.
但在某种程度上，会得到这只 CS50 鸭子的帮助，它是一种聊天机器人。
Now what do I mean by this?
现在，我的意思是？
Well, it turns out that, when it comes to implementing something
事实证明，当要实现一些东西
like an artificial intelligence, we don't quite
比如人工智能，我们还没有完全
have all of the building blocks yet, certainly after just today's week zero,
拥有所有的构建块，当然，仅仅经过了今天的零周，
to implement something like that.
去实现这样一些东西。
But I think we can skate in that direction, intellectually.
但我认为我们在智力上可以朝着那个方向滑行。
So, for instance, if we were to take a stab at implementing our own chatbot--
例如，如果我们要尝试实现我们自己的聊天机器人——
some interactive text-based program that talks to us,
一个与我们对话的交互式文本程序，
and answers questions, and the like-- we could
并回答问题，等等——我们可以
try borrowing some of today's ideas already, those functions, conditionals,
尝试借用一些今天已经存在的思想，那些函数、条件语句，
loops, and more.
循环等等。
And I could write something like this.
我可以写一些像这样的东西。
If I am writing code or pseudocode for a chatbot,
如果我正在为聊天机器人编写代码或伪代码，
I could program the chatbot to do something like this.
我可以将聊天机器人编程为执行类似的操作。
If the student says, hello, to the chatbot,
如果学生对聊天机器人说“你好”，
then the chatbot should say, hello, back.
那么聊天机器人应该说“你好”作为回应。
Else, if the student says, goodbye, well, the chatbot
否则，如果学生说“再见”，那么聊天机器人
should say, goodbye, back.
应该说“再见”作为回应。
Else, if the student asks how you are, the chat bot should say that it's well.
否则，如果学生问“你好吗”，聊天机器人应该说“我很好”。
But things get a little harder when you start
但当你开始
asking more interesting questions, like, else,
问一些更有意思的问题时，比如，否则，
if the student asks why 111 in binary is 7 in decimal.
如果学生问为什么二进制的 111 等于十进制的 7。
Now, you could imagine that we just have a conditional,
现在，你可以想象我们只有一个条件语句，
with this Boolean expression, that programs the chatbot to just give you
加上这个布尔表达式，将聊天机器人编程为直接给你
the answer and explain, in an English sentence, why that, in fact, is.
答案，并用一句英语解释为什么实际上是这样。
But what if you, the student, asks why 110 is 6 in decimal or why 010 is 2?
但如果你是学生，你问为什么 110 等于十进制的 6 或者为什么 010 等于 2 呢？
I mean, you can just imagine the explosion in the amount of code
我的意思是，你可以想象我们必须编写的代码量会爆炸，
that we would have to write to just anticipate every darn question that you
我们必须编写这些代码来预测你可能问的每一个问题，
might ask about today and every other class, not to mention all
你可能问的每一个关于今天和其他课的问题，更不用说所有
of the knowledge in the universe.
宇宙知识的海洋。
So, surely, there are other ways to implement algorithms
因此，肯定还有其他方法来实现算法
that allow something like a chatbot or AI,
从而允许类似聊天机器人或人工智能，
more generally, to be fed input, still, like all of the internet, all
更一般地说，可以持续输入信息，就像整个互联网一样，所有
of the worldwide web, all of the pages and textual content therein,
万维网，所有网页和其中的文本内容，
but to let it just figure out how to answer our questions based
但让它根据这些信息想办法回答我们的问题，
on those kinds of inputs, assuming the inputs, themselves, are accurate.
假设这些输入本身是准确的。
So "large language models" is a term you might
所以，你可能听说过“大型语言模型”，
have heard bandied about over the past several months, or LLMs.
或者叫做LLMs，在过去几个月里经常被提及。
And a large language model really is an implementation, in software,
大型语言模型实际上是软件中的一种实现，
of code that actually takes, as input, lots and lots of language--
代码实际接收大量语言作为输入——
like the text of lots and lots of web pages, dictionaries, encyclopedias,
例如，大量网页、字典、百科全书的文字，
Wikipedias, and the like--
维基百科等等。
and infers, from the patterns of English words or any human language,
并根据英语单词或任何人类语言的模式推断，
what a typical human might actually say when asked a question.
一个普通人被问到问题时可能会说什么。
And some of these questions are easy, right?
其中一些问题很简单，对吧？
Probably, on the internet, alone, not to mention everyday life, if someone
可能，仅仅是在互联网上，更不用说日常生活了，如果有人
extends their hand and says, "Hi.
伸出手说，“你好。
How are you," odds are, with 90% probability, you're going to say,
怎么样？”，你有 90% 的概率会说，
"Good.
“很好。
Thanks.
谢谢。
How are you?"
你呢？”
So I bet we could write software that just
所以我敢说我们可以编写软件，它只需
infers what it should say, probabilistically, statistically, based
根据这些模式推断出它应该说的话，以概率、统计的方式
on those kinds of patterns online.
在网上。
And that's, indeed, where the world is starting
这确实是世界正在走向的方向，
to go, when it comes to the most sophisticated
在最复杂的算法方面，
of algorithms, where you and I, the humans,
你我人类，
we don't try to anticipate every possible input.
不会试图预测所有可能的输入。
Rather, we give it a more general purpose
相反，我们给它一个更通用的目的
input, like all human knowledge, and ideally just let it figure things out.
输入，就像所有的人类知识一样，理想情况下，只是让它自己想办法解决。
Now, we're not quite there, yet.
现在，我们还没有完全达到那个阶段。
And odds are you've heard of hallucinations or just mistakes
你可能听说过这些大型语言模型产生的幻觉或者错误。
that these large language models make.
这些大型语言模型会犯的错误。
But their inputs are imperfect.
但它们的输入是不完美的。
And sometimes there's a bit of randomness sprinkled
有时会添加一些随机性，
in because you don't want the thing to always say the exact same thing.
因为你不希望它总是说同样的话。
Even you and I might say, "Eh, I'm not that great today" 10% of the time.
即使你我，也可能在 10% 的时间里说，“哎，我今天状态不太好”。
So you need to perturb the output in some way.
所以你需要以某种方式扰乱输出。
But within CS50 and within this world of large language models,
但在 CS50 和大型语言模型的世界里，
we do have these tools like ChatGPT, and Bing, chat, and others.
我们确实拥有 ChatGPT、Bing 聊天等工具。
And we'll stipulate that, for CS50's purposes,
并且，为了 CS50 的目的，
the direction we're going this year is that this
我们今年的方向是，
is what's in the syllabus, dot, dot, dot;
是课程大纲中规定的，点，点，点；
that it will not be allowed, it will be considered
不允许使用，会被认为是
not reasonable to use AI-based software, other than CS50's own.
不合理的行为，除了使用 CS50 自身开发的软件以外。
So the goal here is not to simply take away
所以，这里的目标不是简单地拿走
tools that are clearly inevitable, in my view, and clearly helpful
我认为，这些工具不可避免，而且很有帮助
and productivity savers.
并且可以提高效率。
But we'd like there to be some guardrails, intellectually, on just how
但是，我们希望在智力方面有一些限制，来规范这些聊天机器人到底有多
helpful these chatbots are.
有用。
Because as you've probably seen, if you ask it a question,
因为你可能已经看到，如果你问它一个问题，
these chatbots are already pretty good at not just helping
这些聊天机器人已经做得相当不错了，它们不仅仅是帮助
you finish your current thought, but it'll
你完成当前的想法，而且它还会
hand you your second and your third thought and do the assignment for you.
帮你完成第二个、第三个想法，并替你完成作业。
But I think, through prompting, so to speak,
但我认为，通过提示，可以说，
we'll be able to coax some of our own tools,
我们可以引导我们自己的工具，
being computer scientists, ourself, in a direction
作为计算机科学家，我们自己，朝着一个方向
that you actually find to be the right balance, akin to having
你会发现，那是正确的平衡，就像有一个
a good tutor by your side 24/7, who doesn't just hand you answers,
24/7 在你身边的好导师，他不会直接给你答案，
but, indeed, tries to lead you to the same.
而是试图引导你找到答案。
So you actually get something out of the experience,
所以你真的从这段经历中获得了东西，
and, ideally, three-plus months from now,
并且，理想情况下，三个多月后，
those training wheels can come off, too.
这些辅助轮也可以被移除。
And you're able to still stand on your own.
你能够独立站立。
So it will be reasonable to use CS50's own AI-based software which
所以，使用 CS50 自身开发的基于人工智能的软件是合理的，它
will actually take the form of a CS50 duck, which is actually available now--
实际上会以 CS50 小黄鸭的形式出现，现在就可以使用——
and we'll use it throughout the term-- at CS50.ai, a web-based application
我们将在整个学期使用它——在 CS50.ai，一个基于网络的应用程序
that's quite similar to ChatGPT, but that
非常类似于 ChatGPT，但是它
has the personality of a CS50 teaching fellow or TF, or teaching assistant,
具有 CS50 助教或 TF，或者教学助理的个性，
TA, that also happens to think of itself as a duck.
TA，它也恰好把自己当作一只小黄鸭。
And for reasons we'll get to in a couple of weeks time,
至于原因，我们将在几周后讲到，
but rubber ducks, in particular, are a thing in programming.
但橡胶鸭子，尤其是在编程领域，是不可或缺的一部分。
But more on that, before long, as you can even see from the one
不过，我们很快就会讲到，你甚至可以从我桌子上的那只
there on my desk.
看到。
With that said, too, well, I'm going to call out CS50's own Brenda
说到这里，我还要感谢 CS50 的 Brenda
Anderson, whose daughter, Sophie, kindly not only created
Anderson，她的女儿 Sophie 热心地不仅创造了
the first incarnation, digitally, of this duck, but also,
这只小黄鸭的第一个数字化版本，而且，
most recently, once it actually did more than quack a random number
最近，当它不仅仅是随机发出嘎嘎叫声，
of times in response to questions, has now
用来回答问题时，现在
been virtually brought to life, too.
也被赋予了虚拟生命。
So, all that and more, over the coming weeks, but you'll find, ultimately,
所以，所有这些以及更多内容，将在接下来的几周内呈现，但你最终会发现，
that the goal is to really bring to life the availability of an AI-based tutor
目标是真正实现一个基于人工智能的导师，
that you have access to, a friend in your--
你可以访问它，它是你身边的朋友——
next to you, that will help guide you through a lot of the course's
在你身边，它会帮助你完成这门课程的许多
challenges along the way.
挑战。
And we actually rolled it out this past summer,
实际上，我们在上个夏天就推出了它，
already, with some of your predecessors, through the Harvard Summer School.
已经，通过哈佛暑期课程，让一些你的前辈使用过它。
One student wrote, at summer's end, that this duck
一位学生在暑假结束时写道，这只小黄鸭
"felt like having a personal tutor--
“感觉就像拥有了一位私人导师——
I love how AI bots will answer questions without ego and without judgment
我喜欢 AI 机器人如何在没有自我和判断的情况下回答问题
generally entertaining even the stupidest of questions
通常情况下，即使是最愚蠢的问题也能让人觉得有趣
without treating them like they're stupid.
不会把他们当傻子对待。
It has, as one could expect, an inhuman level of patience."
正如人们所预期的那样，它拥有超乎常人的耐心。
So there's actually something really there because as many teachers
所以，这里真的有东西，因为像CS50中那么多的老师
as there are in CS50--
正如CS50中那样--
myself, the course's preceptors, teaching fellows, teaching assistants,
我自己，课程的助教、讲师、助教
and course assistants-- there's only so many of us.
和课程助理--我们人数有限。
And we're only awake so many hours of the day.
而且我们每天清醒的时间也很有限。
And I think you'll find, too, that we're on the cusp of something
我认为你也会发现，我们正处于一个新事物的边缘
pretty remarkable, in the coming years, where
在未来几年，这将变得非常了不起，在未来几年，在
it's going to get a lot more enabling, now, to learn material
学习材料将变得更加容易，现在，学习材料
not only within the confines of a class, but on your own, ultimately, as well.
不仅局限于课堂，最终也可以自己学习。
And as one other student put it, at summer's end, with respect to the duck,
正如另一位学生在暑假结束时所说，关于这只鸭子，
"Love love loved the duck.
“太喜欢这只鸭子了。
We're friends now."
我们现在是朋友了。”
So that, too, awaits.
所以，这也等待着你。
But, first, we're going to need to start with the basics.
但是，首先，我们需要从基础开始。
And we started today by talking about binary.
我们今天从谈论二进制开始。
And darn it, here it is again.
可恶，它又出现了。
So we can't actually get to the point of using, or solving, or implementing AI
因此，我们实际上还不能使用、解决或实现人工智能
until we understand this.
直到我们理解这一点。
And odds are most of you won't know, at a glance, what this piece of software
而且，大多数人可能不会一眼就认出这部分软件
does.
是做什么的。
But these are the 0's and 1's that represent, perhaps,
但这些 0 和 1 代表着，也许，
the first program that any programmer writes, which is now a clue to some
任何程序员编写的第一个程序，现在对一些
of you who have dabbled in code before.
之前接触过代码的人来说是个线索。
What does this pattern of 0's and 1's tell a typical computer to do?
这个 0 和 1 的模式告诉一台典型的计算机做什么？
Might someone guess?
有人能猜出来吗？
AUDIENCE: "Hello, world."
观众：“你好，世界。”
DAVID J. MALAN: It's going to have it say, "hello, world,"
戴维·马兰：它会说“你好，世界”，
which is one of the very first programmer-- programs
这是大多数程序员编写的第一个程序之一
that most any programmer writes.
任何程序员都会编写。
Should you be able to recognize these 0's and 1's?
你应该能识别这些 0 和 1 吗？
Do I recognize these 0's and 1's?
我认得这些 0 和 1 吗？
No, not at all.
不，一点也不。
I just happen to know that they are the same.
我只是碰巧知道它们是一样的。
And that was a leading question.
这是一个引导性问题。
But they are representing data and instructions, ultimately,
但它们最终代表着数据和指令，
data like H-E-L-L-O, comma, W-O-R-L-D and an instruction like,
数据如 H-E-L-L-O、逗号、W-O-R-L-D，以及一条指令，例如，
"Print that data to the screen."
“将该数据打印到屏幕上。”
As for what these patterns of 0's and 1's are,
至于这些 0 和 1 的模式是什么，
this is not something that a computer scientist or programmer worries about.
这不是计算机科学家或程序员需要担心的事情。
We just stipulate that, OK, someone, somewhere knows how to do this.
我们只是规定，好吧，有人，在某个地方知道怎么做。
And it's probably someone like Intel, who makes
而且，这可能是像英特尔这样的人，他们制造
the hardware inside of the computers.
电脑内部的硬件。
But you and I, starting now, already, in week zero,
但你和我在现在，已经，在第零周，
can start to view binary more abstractly.
可以开始更抽象地看待二进制。
We don't care about the 0's and 1's.
我们不在乎 0 和 1。
We only care that you can use 0's and 1's
我们只在乎你能用 0 和 1
to represent more useful quantities, like numbers,
来表示更有用的量，比如数字，
and letters, colors, and more.
还有字母、颜色等等。
So this, next week, is going to be the code we actually
所以，下周，这将是我们实际编写的代码
start writing at a keyboard.
在键盘上开始编写。
And this is that language called C. It's the same language I, myself, learned
这就是叫做 C 的语言。这与我本人多年前学习的语言相同，当时在学习 CS50 时，我们只学习了 C。
years ago, when taking CS50, when all we learned at the time was C.
多年前，当学习 CS50 时，当时我们只学习了 C。
But this, too, has some crypticness to it.
但这也有一些神秘之处。
And if you've never programmed before, you can probably wrap your mind around,
如果你以前从未编程过，你可能可以理解，
OK, I'm guessing the "printf" prints out the "hello, world."
好吧，我猜“printf”会打印出“你好，世界”。
But what's with the semicolon, the quotes, the backslash,
但分号、引号、反斜杠
and the curly braces, the #include, and all of this stupid syntax?
以及花括号、#include，还有所有这些愚蠢的语法？
A lot of this, in the beginning of any class, is really a distraction.
在任何课程的开始阶段，这些东西都是一个真正的干扰。
It is not intellectually interesting.
这在智力上并不有趣。
But it's the stupid kind of stuff that's going to trip you up quite often.
但这却是经常让你绊倒的愚蠢东西。
And so, today, what we'll do is focus not
所以，今天，我们将重点放在
on syntax, characters on the keyboard, but ideas
语法、键盘上的字符，而是思想
because what really matters in this program
因为在这个程序中真正重要的是
is that "printf" is a function here for our purposes.
“printf”在这里是一个函数，用于我们的目的。
And that function is to display information on the screen.
这个函数的作用是在屏幕上显示信息。
Everything else, as we'll soon see, has value
其他的，正如我们很快就会看到的，都有价值
and will be understood by you, before long, but for now, it's a distraction.
而且很快就会被你理解，但现在，这只是一个干扰。
Let's focus on those building blocks.
让我们专注于这些构建块。
When it comes time to write code, though, for the curious,
但是，当要编写代码时，对于好奇的人来说，
especially if you've programmed before, we'll
尤其是如果你以前编程过，我们将
use a very popular free and open-source tool
使用一个非常流行的免费开源工具
called Visual Studio Code, or VS Code.
叫做 Visual Studio Code，或 VS Code。
We'll use a cloud-based version of it that we pre-install everything
我们将使用它基于云的版本，我们预先安装了所有东西
you need in the cloud for you so you don't
你在云端需要的东西，这样你就不必
have to deal with headaches like getting your Mac or PC to work.
处理诸如让你的 Mac 或 PC 工作起来这样的头痛问题。
You'll use instead this URL, cs50.dev, but more
你将使用这个 URL，cs50.dev，但更多
on that in next week, week one.
关于下周，第一周的内容。
For now, we'll use another cloud-based editor called Scratch.
现在，我们将使用另一个叫做 Scratch 的基于云的编辑器。
And odds are some number of you use this probably
而且，你们中有些人可能用过这个
as early as like middle school or the like.
最早是在中学或者类似的阶段。
And that was fine to create your own animations, games,
而且这很适合创建你自己的动画、游戏、
interactive art, or the like.
交互式艺术，或者类似的东西。
But we'll use it today for just a bit.
但我们今天只会用它一小会儿。
And we'll use it in the course's first homework,
我们将在本课程的第一个作业中使用它，
AKA problem set 0, to explore now some of these same ideas.
也就是问题集 0，现在探索一些相同的概念。
And among the goals today for the remainder of today
而今天余下时间的目标之一
is not to focus so much on Scratch and the particulars
并不是太关注 Scratch 和细节
because this is not a language that you're
因为这不是你会经常使用的语言，而是为了
going to use often but to give you very visual representations of ideas
给你非常直观的概念表现形式。
so that when things do escalate next week to C, to the more cryptic,
这样，当事情在下周升级到C，也就是更隐秘的时候，
it's the same ideas just typed out instead of dragged and dropped.
使用的还是相同的思路，只是用打字代替了拖放。
So by that, I mean this.
我的意思是这个。
I'm going to go ahead and share in just a moment the user interface of Scratch.
我将在片刻后分享Scratch的用户界面。
But what's nice about Scratch is that this
但是Scratch的好处在于，这个
is how we're going to implement that same program today.
就是我们今天将要实现相同程序的方式。
These are two blocks or puzzle pieces on the screen,
屏幕上这两个是块或拼图碎片，
and they've been interconnected to tell the computer to say "hello, world"
它们相互连接，告诉计算机说“你好，世界”。
on the screen.
在屏幕上。
The user interface that we're about to use
我们即将使用的用户界面
will look generally something like this.
大体上会像这样。
It's a web-based editor that you can also
它是一个基于网页的编辑器，你也可以
download it locally to use offline.
将其下载到本地以离线使用。
And you'll see that at the left here are a whole bunch of puzzle pieces
你会看到左边这里有一堆拼图碎片
or blocks.
或块。
They're categorized by color, and the blue ones
它们按颜色分类，蓝色的一般
tend to relate to motion, for instance.
与运动有关，比如。
The purple ones represent looks.
紫色的一般代表外观。
The pink one represents sounds.
粉红色的一般代表声音。
The yellow one represents events.
黄色的一般代表事件。
More on that soon.
稍后会详细介绍。
The orange ones represent control, and then
橙色的一般代表控制，然后
there's operators, variables, my blocks, and even some extensions
还有运算符、变量、我的块，甚至一些扩展
we can install as well.
也可以安装。
So it just categorizes things visually and colorfully so that you
所以它只是以视觉和多彩的方式对事物进行分类，以便你
can find what you're looking for.
可以找到你想要的东西。
But we're going to use these puzzle pieces to drag and drop them
但我们将使用这些拼图碎片并将它们拖放到
onto this area here.
这个区域。
And we're going to connect them when we want them to do something.
当我们想让它们做某事时，我们将把它们连接起来。
What can they do?
它们能做什么呢？
Well, by default, Scratch comes with this cat here, otherwise known
默认情况下，Scratch 这里有一个猫，也被称为
as a sprite, which is a character in a game or in a graphics context.
精灵，它是游戏中或图形环境中的一个角色。
And this cat lives in this two-dimensional world in which
这只猫生活在这个二维世界中，
the cat can go up, down, left, right.
猫可以上下左右移动。
And you can actually change the cat's costume
你实际上可以改变猫的服装
to be a dog, a bird, or anything else.
成为狗、鸟或任何其他东西。
It really is more of an idea than it is a specific animal in this case.
实际上，它更像是一种概念，而不是具体动物。
But the world that Scratch lives in looks a little something like this.
但 Scratch 所处的世界看起来有点像这样。
It's like a Cartesian plane with x-coordinates and y-coordinates.
它就像一个笛卡尔坐标系，具有 x 坐标和 y 坐标。
And the numbers don't so much matter fundamentally,
从根本上说，数字并不那么重要，
except that when you want the cat or any character to go up,
除非你想让猫或任何角色向上移动，
down, left, or right by some amount, it's
向下、向左或向右移动一定距离，
useful to know, for instance, that 0, 0 is the middle, 0 comma 0 for x comma y.
知道这一点很有用，例如，0, 0 是中间，0 逗号 0 代表 x 逗号 y。
All the way up is a y value of 180.
最上面是 y 值为 180。
All the way down is -180.
最下面是 -180。
All the way to the left is -240.
最左边是 -240。
All the way to the right is 240.
最右边是 240。
And generally, you're not going to have to worry about numbers.
通常，你不用担心数字。
You're going to use these relatively-- go right, go left, go up, or down.
你会相对地使用这些——向右、向左、向上或向下。
But that's just the world that Scratch itself lives in here.
但这只是 Scratch 本身所处的世界。
So let's go about using Scratch here.
所以让我们开始使用 Scratch。
I'm going to change over to my cloud-based editor
我将切换到我的云端编辑器
here, where I've gone to scratch.mit.edu.
这里，我已经访问了 scratch.mit.edu。
And I've clicked Create in order to create a project.
我点击了“创建”来创建一个项目。
And that gives me this blank canvas here.
这给了我这个空白画布。
And I'm going to do these somewhat quickly because I kind of know
我将快速完成这些步骤，因为我多少知道
what I'm looking for.
我要找什么。
But part of the process with problem set zero is going to be clicking,
但问题集 0 的一部分将是点击，
and dragging, and sort of scrolling around
拖动，以及四处滚动
to see what building blocks exist.
看看有哪些构建块。
But I know under Events there's this puzzle piece here
但我清楚在事件下有这个拼图碎片
when green flag clicked.
当绿色旗帜被点击时。
Why is that germane?
为什么这很重要？
Well, if I zoom out, and go back to Scratch's world at the right here,
如果我放大，并回到右侧的 Scratch 世界，
notice that above Scratch's world there's
注意在 Scratch 世界的上面有一个
a green flag, which is going to mean go, and a red stop sign, which,
绿色旗帜，表示开始，红色停止标志，当然，表示停止。
of course, is going to mean stop.
当然，表示停止。
So if I drag this puzzle piece anywhere into the middle,
所以，如果我把这个拼图碎片拖到中间的任何地方，
it's just going to plop where I put it.
它就会落在我的放置位置。
But what that means semantically is when someone clicks that green flag,
但从语义上来说，这意味着当有人点击绿色旗帜时，
I want Scratch the cat to do this other thing.
我希望 Scratch 猫做另一件事。
Well, what do I want it to do?
嗯，我想要它做什么呢？
Well, let me go under Looks.
让我看看外观。
And looks here in purple have some puzzle pieces like this.
外观里有一些像这样的紫色拼图碎片。
Well, I can say hello for some number of seconds,
我可以说几秒钟的“你好”，
or I can just go ahead and say hello.
或者直接说“你好”。
So let's do that.
那就这样吧。
I'm going to drag this say block.
我要拖动这个“说”块。
And notice that as soon as I get close enough,
注意，当我靠近它时，
it's going to magnetically want to connect.
它就会像磁铁一样想要连接。
So I can let go, and they snap together automatically
所以我可以松开手，它们会自动连接在一起
because they're the right shape.
因为它们的形状是匹配的。
I don't have to say hello, exclamation point.
我不必说“你好”，感叹号。
I can change it to the more canonical, hello comma world.
我可以把它改成更规范的，你好，世界。
So anything in this white oval is editable
所以，这个白色椭圆中的任何内容都可以编辑
that you can change as just text there.
你可以在这里将其更改为文本。
If I now zoom out, let me go ahead and click the green flag.
现在，如果我放大，让我点击绿色旗帜。
And voila-- this should be my first program in Scratch.
瞧，这应该是我的第一个 Scratch 程序。
Hello, world.
你好，世界。
Without any of the distractions of syntax
没有语法带来的干扰
or weird characters on the screen, it's just done what I want it to do.
或屏幕上奇怪的字符，它只是做了我想要它做的事情。
All right.
好的。
Let me go ahead and click Stop there.
让我点击停止。
And let me make it a little more connected
让我把它与我们迄今为止讨论的内容联系得更紧密一些。
to what we've discussed thus far.
与我们迄今为止讨论的内容联系得更紧密一些。
So this puzzle piece here, say hello, world,
所以这个拼图碎片，说“你好，世界”，
represents what type of building block using the vocabulary of today?
使用今天的词汇，它代表哪种类型的构建块？
So it's a function.
所以这是一个函数。
So these purple blocks are functions, say, hello, world.
所以这些紫色块是函数，比如“hello, world”。
And let me give you another piece of terminology.
让我再给你介绍另一个术语。
These white ovals that take textual input--
这些白色椭圆形，接受文本输入——
in general, those are called parameters or arguments.
一般来说，这些被称为参数或实参。
And they customize the behavior of a function.
它们会定制函数的行为。
So a parameter or an argument customizes,
所以参数或实参会定制，
modifies the default behavior of a function, like in this case, say.
修改函数的默认行为，就像这种情况下的“say”。
Similarly, in the C code from earlier that we'll see next week,
类似地，在我们下周看到的早期 C 代码中，
the printf function took a quoted phrase like, hello, world, similarly as input.
printf 函数接受像“hello, world”这样的带引号的短语作为输入。
But more on that in the future.
但这将在未来详细介绍。
So how does this connect to the mental model we presented earlier?
那么，这如何与我们之前提出的心理模型联系起来？
Well, here's problem-solving as I described it earlier, inputs to outputs
那么，就像我之前描述的那样，这就是解决问题的方式，输入到输出
with algorithms or code in the middle.
中间是算法或代码。
Well, what we've got here really is an input of, hello, world, the white oval.
实际上，我们这里有一个输入，即“hello, world”，白色的椭圆形。
The function or algorithm that it's going into as input is the say block.
作为输入的函数或算法是“say”块。
And what is the output of using this say block, the say function?
那么，使用“say”块（“say”函数）的输出是什么？
It's the visual effect of having the cat have the little speech bubble appear
就是让猫的头上出现一个小气泡的视觉效果
above its head, saying, hello, world.
上面写着“hello, world”。
So everything we do, in fact, can be mapped back
所以我们所做的一切，实际上都可以映射回
to that very simple idea of inputs and outputs.
那个非常简单的输入和输出的概念。
Well, let's make it a little more interesting, though.
不过，让我们让它更有趣一些。
It's a little boring to just say "hello, world" all the time.
一直说“hello, world”有点无聊。
Let me go ahead and drag this away.
让我把它拖走。
And if you just drag it to the left and let go, it gets automatically deleted.
如果你把它拖到左边然后松开，它就会自动删除。
Let me go under Sensing in light blue here.
让我到“Sensing”（感知）模块里，它是浅蓝色的。
And you'll see there's a bunch of blocks, one of which
你会看到有很多块，其中一块
is an ask block, an ask function, which is going to prompt
是一个“ask”（询问）块，一个“ask”函数，它将提示
the human, me, for some input.
人类，也就是我，输入一些东西。
So let me go ahead and drag that over here, and it snaps together.
所以让我把它拖到这里，它会自动对齐。
I could change the question, but I'm OK with that question.
我可以改变问题，但我对这个问题感到满意。
We'll use what's your name.
我们将使用“what's your name”。
But notice that this block, ask, is a little special.
但请注意，这个“ask”块有点特殊。
It is not just going to display like a speech bubble on the screen.
它不仅仅是在屏幕上显示像气泡一样的文字。
It's actually going to return a value, and this is
它实际上会返回一个值，而这就是
another term of art today and onward.
从今天开始，另一个专业术语。
A return value is some value that can be handed back to you conceptually
返回值是一个可以从概念上返回给你的值
from a function so that you can do something with it.
来自函数，以便你可以对其进行操作。
It's as though the ask function asks someone for their name,
就像“ask”函数询问某人的姓名一样，
writes it down on a piece of paper, and hands you the piece of paper.
把它写在一张纸上，然后把这张纸给你。
You can do anything now that you want with that name.
现在你可以用这个名字做任何你想做的事。
And here is how you access the name in this special block called
而你访问这个名字的方法是在这个特殊的块中，叫做
answer, which, again, will start calling a return value.
“answer”，它又开始被称为返回值。
So if I want to say "hello" to someone specific, I'm going to do this.
所以，如果我想对某个人说“hello”，我会这样做。
Let me zoom out.
让我缩小一下。
Let me go back to Looks, and let me go back to Say.
让我回到“Looks”（外观）模块，再回到“Say”。
And I'm going to change the say block here to "hello, comma."
我将把这里的“say”块改成“hello, ”。
Then I'm going to zoom out.
然后我再缩小一下。
Well, I need two inputs, I think.
我认为，我需要两个输入。
So I'm going to grab another say block, and I'm going to put it below.
所以我会再拿一个“say”块，把它放在下面。
And I could just type "David," but this is
我可以直接输入“David”，但这会
going to defeat the whole point of asking me for the name.
破坏询问我名字的整个目的。
And it will only work for me.
而且它只对我有用。
So I don't want to do that.
所以我不想这样做。
So let me go back to Sensing, and notice the shape is important here.
所以我回到“Sensing”，注意这里的形状很重要。
Even if it's not quite the same size, the shape matters.
即使它的大小不太一样，形状也很重要。
And I can actually drag this and change the input of this say function
我实际上可以把它拖动，并改变这个“say”函数的输入
to be whatever that return value is, that piece of paper
成为那个返回值，那张纸
that has the person's name on it.
上面写着那个人的名字。
And it grows to fill, but now we have a program
它会自动调整大小，但现在我们有一个程序
that I think when I click the green flag-- watch-- is going to prompt me.
我认为当我点击绿色的旗子时——看着——它会提示我。
What's your name?
你的名字是什么？
And now I have room to type down here.
现在我可以在这里输入了。
So I'm going to type D-A-V-I-D. I'm going to hit Enter,
所以我将输入 D-A-V-I-D，然后按回车键，
and it should say "hello, Dave."
它应该显示“hello, Dave”。
Wait.
等等。
Hmm.
嗯。
Huh.
Maybe it was-- didn't work.
也许它——没用。
D-A-V-I-D. Here we go.
D-A-V-I-D。开始了。
Hello, David.
Hello, David。
Hmm.
嗯。
It's missing the hello, but I'm quite sure we have a hello right there.
它没有显示“hello”，但我相当确定我们那里有一个“hello”。
So what explains this bug or mistake?
所以，是什么解释了这个 bug 或错误？
Yeah.
是啊。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众： [听不清]
So they overlap.
所以它们重叠了。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·马兰：没错。
Put another way, my Mac, my PC, it's just so darn
换句话说，我的 Mac，我的 PC，它就是太快了
fast that it did exactly what it was supposed to.
以至于它准确地执行了它应该做的事情。
But it said "hello, David" so fast that we didn't even see, we being the human,
但它说“hello, David”太快了，以至于我们，作为人类，
the slowest part of the puzzle, see the actual hello.
这个拼图中最慢的部分，没有看到真正的“hello”。
So there's a few different ways to fix this, as you know.
所以，正如你所知，有很多不同的方法可以修复它。
We could have it say "hello" for some number of seconds.
我们可以让它显示“hello”几秒钟。
So I could kind of do that.
所以我可以这样做。
So let me do this.
所以让我这样做。
I can decouple these by just dragging and letting it go
我可以通过拖动然后松开，来分离它们
so that they're magnetically far apart.
这样它们就会被磁性地隔开。
Let me go ahead and drag this one, say hello for two seconds.
让我拖动这个，让它显示“hello”两秒钟。
I'm going to change the grammar here to be hello comma again.
我要把这里的语法改回“hello, ”。
I'm going to go ahead and disconnect these two.
我将分离这两个。
I'm going to throw away the old one that I don't want to use.
我将丢弃那个我不想要使用的旧块。
And I'm going to reconnect this so that now--
我将重新连接它，这样现在——
OK.
好的。
It's going to say hello for two seconds and then my name, hopefully.
它将显示“hello”两秒钟，然后是我的名字，希望如此。
So let me click Stop and Start.
所以让我点击“停止”和“开始”。
D-A-V-I-D. Enter.
D-A-V-I-D。按下回车键。
OK.
好的。
So it's better, but it's kind of poorly implemented.
所以它确实更好了，但实现方式有点糟糕。
Like, come on.
拜托。
I just wanted to say hello comma David.
我只是想说一句“你好，大卫”。
Why is that hard?
为什么这么难？
Well, maybe we can actually combine these a little differently.
好吧，也许我们可以以不同的方式组合这些。
And let me propose this.
让我来提议一下。
Let me actually get rid of these blocks again.
让我把这些块再次删除。
And let me go ahead and just say one thing.
让我继续说一件事。
But can I somehow combine this to say hello comma David all in one breath?
但我能以某种方式将这些组合起来，一次性说出“你好，大卫”吗？
Well, it turns out if I go under Operators,
事实证明，如果我在“操作符”下，
I know from having played with this before that there's this puzzle
我之前玩过这个，我知道这里有一个名为“连接”的拼图
piece down here called join.
块。
It's an oval.
它是一个椭圆形。
It's a little big, but, again, it will grow to fill.
它有点大，但同样，它会增长以填满。
And by default, it wants to join two words, "apple" and "banana."
默认情况下，它想连接两个词，“苹果”和“香蕉”。
But those are just placeholders.
但这些只是占位符。
So let me go ahead and drag this over the default hello.
所以我把它拖到默认的“你好”上。
Let me change "apple" to hello comma space and then banana.
我把它改为“你好，空格，然后是香蕉”。
Let me go back to Sensing.
我回到“感知”。
Let me grab answer and drag and drop that.
我抓住“回答”，然后拖放它。
So now notice that I'm kind of layering my ideas.
所以现在注意，我有点分层地构建我的想法。
And put another way, the output of this join block
换句话说，这个“连接”块的输出
is presumably going to join two things together,
可能会将两件事连接在一起，
apple and banana or hello comma David.
苹果和香蕉，或者“你好，大卫”。
And then the output of join is going to become the input to say.
然后“连接”的输出将成为“说”的输入。
So aesthetically, it just looks better.
所以从美学上来说，它看起来更好。
It's still correct, but it's just better.
它仍然是正确的，但它确实更好。
So if I type "David," and hit Enter, hello, David.
所以我输入“大卫”，然后按下回车键，“你好，大卫”。
This is what a normal program would presumably
这正是正常程序应该做的事情，
do, not show you part of the phrase and then the rest of the phrase.
而不是只显示一部分短语，然后是短语的剩余部分。
Like, it's just better in this way.
就像，它以这种方式更好。
So let's connect this now to this same puzzle piece and this methodology.
所以让我们现在将它连接到这个相同的拼图块和这种方法。
So here's that same puzzle piece, ask.
所以这是同一个拼图块，“询问”。
How do we fit it into this input and output flow with algorithms?
我们如何用算法将它融入这个输入和输出流？
Well, the input to that puzzle piece is something like, what's your name,
嗯，那个拼图块的输入是类似这样的东西，你的名字是，
question mark.
问号。
Then the algorithm or the code implementation thereof
然后算法，或者它的代码实现
is this ask block and wait so the human has a moment to type their response in.
就是这个“询问”块和“等待”，以便用户有时间输入他们的回应。
The output of that function recall is a return value.
请记住，那个函数的输出是一个返回值。
You don't see anything on the screen by default because we've not used say yet,
默认情况下你不会在屏幕上看到任何东西，因为我们还没有使用“说”，
but we get this return value.
但我们得到了这个返回值。
And let me scooch everything over now so that we can now
现在让我把所有东西都移过去，这样我们就可以
join those inputs together.
将这些输入连接在一起。
So here's this puzzle piece.
所以这是这个拼图块。
Let me go ahead and propose that the inputs now to the join block
让我提议一下，现在“连接”块的输入
are two arguments or two parameters, so to speak, hello and answer.
是两个参数，或者说两个参数，分别是“你好”和“回答”。
They go into that join puzzle piece, whose purpose in life
它们进入那个“连接”拼图块，它存在的意义
is to return one joined version thereof.
就是返回一个连接在一起的版本。
Let me slide this all over logically now so
现在让我逻辑地把这些都移过去，所以
that now that output becomes the input to the say block
现在那个输出就变成了“说”块的输入
and now is why the cat has the speech bubble saying all at once,
现在也解释了为什么猫的对话框里一次性显示了“你好，大卫”。
hello comma David.
“你好，大卫”。
So what we've done here is kind of composed the output
所以我们在这里做的事情是将输出
and from one function into the input of another.
从一个函数组合到另一个函数的输入。
And you can think of this in a couple of different ways,
你可以从几个不同的角度来思考这一点，
left to right, as I did there, or kind of
从左到右，就像我之前做的那样，或者类似
like stacking these things on top of one another.
将这些东西叠放在一起。
But at the end of the day, even as programming
但归根结底，即使是编程
gets more and more powerful for us, it's just inputs and outputs, inputs
变得越来越强大，它也仅仅是输入和输出，输入
and outputs.
和输出。
And thankfully, with built-in functionality from our friends
幸运的是，借助来自我们朋友
at MIT who designed Scratch, I can even do something playful like this.
麻省理工学院（MIT）的设计的 Scratch 的内置功能，我甚至可以做一些像这样的有趣的事情。
I can go to that Extensions button at the bottom.
我可以点击底部那个“扩展”按钮。
And there's a lot of fancy things I can add here, like text-to-speech.
这里有很多花哨的东西可以添加，比如文字转语音。
So let me go ahead and choose text-to-speech.
所以让我选择“文字转语音”。
And let me go ahead here and change the say block in purple.
让我在这里把紫色的“说”块换掉。
Let me get rid of the say block, and let me borrow this.
让我删除“说”块，然后借用这个。
Let me get the speak block like this.
让我得到像这样的“朗读”块。
And now let me drag and drop this oval.
现在让我拖放这个椭圆形。
It's going to grow to fill.
它会增长以填满。
And I think it's just about to be a little more interesting.
我想它马上就会变得更有趣。
Let me click Play now, and hopefully this isn't too loud.
现在让我点击“播放”，希望它不会太大声。
D-A-V-I-D. Enter.
D-A-V-I-D。按下回车键。
SPEAKER: Hello, David.
说话者：你好，大卫。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
Thank you.
谢谢。
That's a low bar.
这可是一个很低的标准。
[CHUCKLES] Let me go ahead and set the voice too.
[轻笑] 让我继续设置一下声音。
And you might now remember how we began class, where
你可能还记得我们是怎么开始上课的，
we had a robotic, computerized voice.
我们用了一个机械的，电脑化的声音。
Well, we didn't use Scratch at the time, but we could change this in Scratch
好吧，当时我们没有使用 Scratch，但我们可以用 Scratch
alone to be a little different.
来改变这一点，让它有点不同。
So D-A-V-I-D.
所以 D-A-V-I-D。
SPEAKER: Hello, David.
说话者：你好，大卫。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
Little creepy, but we can play all day long with that.
有点诡异，但我们可以整天玩这个。
But the point is that these functions are just
但重点是这些函数只是
now doing something a little different.
现在做了一些不同的事情。
But it's just these inputs and outputs.
但它也仅仅是这些输入和输出。
Well, let's make the cat more like a cat.
好吧，让我们让猫更像猫。
Let me go ahead and throw away all of this asking question stuff.
让我继续把所有这些“询问”的东西都扔掉。
Let me go up to Sound, and let me go ahead
让我回到“声音”，然后继续
and drag the play sound meow until done.
拖动“播放声音喵叫，直到完成”。
And here too it comes with meow.
这里也带有喵叫。
You can add your own sounds as well.
你也可以添加自己的声音。
But I'm just going to use the default meow and here too.
但我只是在这里使用默认的喵叫。
Hopefully, this won't be too loud.
希望这不会太吵。
Let's make the cat meow by clicking Play.
让我们点击播放让猫叫。
[MEOWING]
[猫叫]
OK.
好的。
It's a little piercing, but it's cute.
有点尖锐，但很可爱。
And if I want the cat to meow twice, I could just play the game twice.
如果我想让猫叫两次，我就可以玩两次游戏。
[MEOWING]
[猫叫]
All right.
好的。
But it would be nice to just get it to meow automatically two, or three,
但是，如果能让它自动叫两声，三声，
or more times.
甚至更多次，那就更好了。
So you know what I could do?
你知道我该怎么做吗？
I could just drag a second one of these.
我可以再拖一个这样的模块过来。
Actually, you know what?
其实你知道吗？
I could even just right-click or Control-click and duplicate them.
我甚至可以右键单击或使用 Ctrl 键单击并复制它们。
But I'll just keep dragging and dropping.
但我还是会一直拖放。
There's different ways to solve problems.
解决问题的方法有很多种。
And now let me click Play.
现在让我点击播放。
[MEOWING]
[猫叫]
OK.
好的。
Cat does not sound particularly happy.
这猫听起来不太开心。
So we could go under--
所以我们可以去下面——
how about Control?
试试控制键？
We could wait one second.
我们可以等待一秒钟。
Now, there's no room, but it will sort of expand to give room for me.
现在没有空间了，但它会自动扩展，为我腾出空间。
So let me try this.
所以让我试试这个。
And now it's going to wait one second in between meows.
现在它会在两次猫叫之间等待一秒钟。
[MEOWING]
[猫叫]
OK.
好的。
Let me stipulate that is correct.
我声明这是正确的。
If my goal is to get the cat to meow three times, it meowed three times.
如果我的目标是让猫叫三次，它就叫了三次。
But per our discussion earlier of algorithms and the design thereof,
但是根据我们之前讨论的算法及其设计，
this is not the best design.
这不是最好的设计。
[MEOWING]
[猫叫]
OK?
好吗？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Thank you for playing along at home.
感谢您在家参与互动。
Yeah.
是的。
In what sense is this arguably not well-designed?
为什么可以说它设计不好呢？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: You repeated yourself.
观众：你重复了自己。
DAVID J. MALAN: I repeated myself, which actually in programming
大卫·J·马兰：我重复了自己，这在编程中其实
tends not to be a good thing.
通常不是一件好事。
Now, it was easy.
现在，这很简单。
I almost resorted to copy-paste, which saves me time upfront.
我差点就用复制粘贴了，这在前期可以节省时间。
But just imagine a contrived scenario.
但想象一下一个牵强的场景。
Now, what if I want it to wait like two seconds in between?
现在，如果我想让它在两次猫叫之间等待两秒钟呢？
All right.
好的。
It's not that big a deal.
这没什么大不了的。
I change it here, and I change it here.
我在这里修改一下，在这里也修改一下。
But what if the program is meant to meow 10 times?
但如果程序要让猫叫 10 次呢？
Then I have to change it here, and here, and here, and here, and here.
然后我必须在这里修改，在这里修改，在这里修改，在这里修改，在这里修改。
And eventually I'm going to screw up.
最后我肯定会出错。
Humans are fallible.
人都会犯错。
I'm going to overlook one of them.
我会漏掉其中一个。
One time, it's going to be one second.
一次会是一秒钟。
Another is going to be two, and just stupid things will happen.
另一次会是两秒，然后就会发生一些愚蠢的事情。
You're setting yourself up for failure if you design things poorly.
如果你设计的东西很糟糕，就会给自己埋下失败的种子。
And so I would propose that we use another type of building block
所以，我建议我们使用另一种类型的构建块
to solve this instead.
来解决这个问题。
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·J·马兰：是的。
So we could use a loop and just write minimal code
所以我们可以使用循环，只写最少的代码
but to accomplish even more functionality.
但可以实现更多的功能。
So let me throw away most of these blocks.
所以让我丢掉大部分的模块。
And let's go and grab this repeat block, which we haven't used yet,
然后让我们去获取这个重复模块，我们还没有使用过它，
but it's right there.
但它就在那里。
And as the name suggests, this will allow
正如它的名字所暗示的那样，这将允许
me to repeat something some number of times.
我重复某件事若干次。
Let me put these two puzzle pieces inside.
让我把这两块拼图放进去。
It'll grow to fill.
它会自动填充。
Let me reconnect it to the green flag.
让我把它重新连接到绿色旗帜上。
I'll change the default 10 to a 3.
我会把默认的 10 改成 3。
And now--
现在——
[MEOWING]
[猫叫]
It's just sort of better because if now you want it to meow more times,
它更好，因为现在如果你想让它叫更多次，
you change it one place.
你只需要修改一个地方。
If you want it to slow down, you change it in one place.
如果你想让它慢下来，你只需要修改一个地方。
There's no room for error.
没有出错的空间。
And that's generally a good thing.
这通常是一件好事。
But this is silly.
但这太可笑了。
Like, Scratch comes with a cat.
比如说，Scratch 自带一只猫。
Why didn't MIT give us a puzzle piece called "meow?"
为什么麻省理工学院没有给我们一个叫做“喵”的拼图模块？
Like, why am I implementing the idea of meowing myself?
就像，为什么我要自己实现“喵”这个概念？
Like, that took me what?
就像，那花了我的什么？
1, 2, 3, 4 puzzle pieces.
1、2、3、4 个拼图模块。
Why isn't there just one puzzle piece that meows for me?
为什么没有一个拼图模块能帮我叫“喵”？
This too we can do in code, be it in Scratch, or C, or other languages too.
我们也可以在代码中做到这一点，无论是 Scratch、C 还是其他语言。
I'm going to go down to these pink my blocks here,
我会去下面这些粉色的我的模块，
where I can create my own puzzle piece.
在那里我可以创建自己的拼图模块。
And I'm going to call this literally "meow."
我会把它命名为“喵”。
And I'm going to go ahead and just click OK.
然后我就会点击确定。
And notice that it's given me this new type of start connector.
注意，它给了我这种新的启动连接器。
It's a start puzzle piece that nothing goes above it.
这是一个启动拼图模块，上面没有其他模块。
But you can put anything you want below it.
但你可以在它下面放任何你想放的东西。
And I'm going to go ahead and cheat here.
然后我会在这里作弊。
I'm just going to grab my existing code, so to speak.
我将获取我现有的代码，可以说。
This is code I'm writing, even though it's puzzle pieces.
尽管它像拼图一样，但这也是我在写代码。
And now let me just claim, and I'll move this aside.
现在让我声明一下，我会把这个放到一边。
Here is now an implementation of my own function,
现在，这是我自己实现的函数，
my own block called "meow," whose purpose in life
我自己的积木叫做“喵”，它存在的意义
is to meow until done and then wait one second.
就是一直喵到结束，然后等待一秒钟。
But what's powerful now is notice at top left, now that I've made the block,
但现在很强大的地方是，请注意左上角，现在我已经做好了积木，
I can use it any number of times.
我可以使用它任意多次。
So I can grab this meow block, drag it over here, and you know what?
所以我可以抓住这个“喵”积木，把它拖到这里，你知道吗？
Now that "meow" exists as an idea, I can abstract that away.
现在“喵”作为一种概念存在，我可以把它抽象出来。
And I'm just going to arbitrarily drag it way to the bottom.
我就要把它随意拖到最底部。
I'm not deleting it.
我没有把它删除。
I'm just putting it out of sight, out of mind so
我只是把它隐藏起来，不再去想它，这样
that we can focus now on this idea.
我们现在就可以专注于这个概念了。
And I claim that this implementation of meowing
我声称这种“喵”的实现方式
is sort of better because it's more compact, it does what it says,
在某种程度上更好，因为它更加紧凑，它做到了它所描述的，
and I don't care about the implementation details of "meow."
而且我并不关心“喵”的实现细节。
So this idea of abstraction, something we're going to use frequently.
所以这个抽象的概念，我们将会经常用到。
To abstract something away is to simplify.
将某些东西抽象出来就是简化。
Don't think about the underlying implementation details.
不要去想底层的实现细节。
Just care about what it does or what it's called.
只需要关心它做什么或者它的名字是什么。
Someone has to care about the implementation details,
有人必须关心实现细节，
like me 30 seconds ago.
就像我 30 秒前那样。
But here on out, I don't need to care.
但从现在开始，我不需要再关心了。
And so in fact, you and I are using the abstraction
实际上，你和我都在使用 Scratch 的抽象，
that is Scratch because I don't know how to put a speech bubble on the screen.
因为我不知道如何在屏幕上放一个对话框。
I don't know how to create that sound, meow.
我也不知道如何创建那个声音“喵”。
MIT did that, and they abstracted those pieces
麻省理工学院做到了这一点，他们把这些部分
of functionality away already for us by just giving us
的功能抽象出来，并直接给了我们
these puzzle pieces we see here.
这些我们在这里看到的拼图。
So the code will work the exact same.
所以代码将完全一样地工作。
[MEOWING]
[喵叫声]
But it's sort of better designed now because now I've
但现在它设计得更好了一些，因为现在我已经
abstracted away the idea of meowing.
将“喵”的概念抽象出来了。
But I bet I can improve this further.
但我相信我还可以进一步改进它。
Can I get rid of the repeat block altogether?
我可以完全去掉重复积木吗？
And let me just tell the meow block how many times to meow.
让我直接告诉“喵”积木要喵多少次。
Well, let me go down to the bottom and look at the implementation details.
好吧，让我到最底部看一下实现细节。
I'm going to right-click or Control-click on this,
我要右键单击或 Control-单击它，
and I'm going to edit it.
我要编辑它。
So I'm going to make a change.
所以我要做一些修改。
And I didn't do this before, but I'm going to call it "meow," as before.
我以前没有这样做，但我现在要把它叫做“喵”，和以前一样。
I'm going to add an input.
我要添加一个输入。
And just so I know what it says what it does,
为了让我知道它做了什么，
I'm going to add the word "times" here.
我要在这里添加单词“times”。
And I'm going to change this placeholder to n.
我要将这个占位符更改为 n。
n for "number" is the go-to placeholder any time
n 代表“number”，是我们在计算机科学中想要谈论一个数字时最常用的占位符。
we want to talk about a number in CS.
我们在计算机科学中想要谈论一个数字时最常用的占位符。
So now notice the puzzle piece looks a little different.
所以现在请注意这个拼图看起来有点不同。
It takes an argument or a parameter called
它接收一个参数，叫做
n, which represents the number of times you want the thing to meow.
n，它代表你想要这个东西喵的次数。
Now, that doesn't do that yet.
现在，它还没有做到这一点。
So let me go back to my other code.
所以让我回到我的另一段代码。
Let me just decouple these temporarily.
让我先暂时将它们分开。
I'm going to move my loop into my implementation of meowing.
我要把我的循环移动到“喵”的实现中。
But I don't want to hard code, that is literally write the number 3 anymore.
但我不想再硬编码了，也就是不再直接写数字 3。
I'm going to grab this oval and put it there.
我要抓住这个椭圆形，把它放到那里。
So now I've generalized the function.
所以现在我已经将这个函数泛化了。
So now it will meow any number of times, 0 on up, by executing that loop
所以现在它可以喵任意多次，从 0 开始，通过执行那个循环
and now more powerfully.
而现在更加强大。
Out of sight, out of mind.
眼不见，心不烦。
Notice that my code just became so darn simple.
请注意，我的代码变得如此简单。
Like, my function is called "meow."
比如，我的函数叫做“喵”。
It meows some number of times.
它喵叫一定次数。
All I have to do is type a number there, and it just works.
我所要做的就是在那里输入一个数字，它就能正常工作。
And I don't care any more about those lower-level, so to speak,
我再也不关心那些更底层的，可以这么说，
implementation details.
实现细节了。
So here, no surprise.
所以在这里，不出所料。
If I type in the number 3, zoom out, and hit Play--
如果我输入数字 3，缩小，然后点击播放——
[MEOWING]
[喵叫声]
--it still works just fine.
——它仍然可以正常工作。
So any questions on what we've just done here?
所以关于我们刚刚做的事情，有什么问题吗？
It's still just meowing, but that's besides the point.
它仍然只是在喵叫，但这并不是重点。
It's this creation of our own functions, this modularity,
是我们自己创建函数，这种模块化，
this abstraction that's going to be the idea that keeps coming back to us.
这种抽象，将是我们反复出现的概念。
No?
没有？
All right.
好吧。
So let's make this a little more cat-like.
所以让我们让它更像猫一些。
Let me throw away all of this code.
让我丢掉所有这些代码。
And let me go ahead--
然后我开始——
oops-- let me throw away this code first and then the rest of this code.
哎呦——让我先丢掉这段代码，然后再丢掉剩下的代码。
And let me go ahead and give myself another green flag block.
然后我开始，再给自己一个绿色旗帜积木。
And let me go ahead, and let's create a cat that allows us to pet it
然后我开始，我们创建一个猫，让我们可以抚摸它
by moving my cursor over the cat.
通过将我的光标移到猫的上面。
And maybe it likes that, so it'll meow when I do that.
也许它喜欢这样，所以当我这样做的时候，它就会喵叫。
So let me go under Control, and let me grab this if conditional,
所以让我到控制下面，然后抓住这个 if 条件语句，
which we talked about as a building block earlier.
我们之前把它当作一个构建块讨论过。
Let me go to Sensing, and we haven't used this before.
让我到感知下面，我们以前没有使用过这个。
But here is a weird sort of diagonal shape
但是这里有一个奇怪的斜线形状
that says touching mouse pointer question mark.
上面写着“触摸鼠标指针”问号。
So that's a Boolean expression.
所以这是一个布尔表达式。
So I'm going to drag that, and it's definitely the wrong size.
所以我要拖动它，它显然大小不对。
But it is the right shape, so it will grow to fill.
但它的形状是对的，所以它会扩展到填满。
And the question I want to ask is if the cat is touching the mouse pointer,
而我想问的问题是，如果猫正在触摸鼠标指针，
then go ahead and meow happily.
那就继续开心地喵叫。
So let me grab the meow sound, put it in there.
所以让我抓住“喵”的声音，把它放到那里。
And so I think when I click the green flag to start the program,
所以我想当我点击绿色旗帜开始程序的时候，
and now I let the mouse pointer touch the cat, we should hear--
现在我让鼠标指针碰到猫，我们应该听到——
huh.
咦。
Doesn't seem to be working.
好像没有起作用。
There's a bug or a mistake in this program too.
这个程序中也存在一个错误或者 bug。
What did I do wrong?
我做错了什么？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: You didn't specify the sprite [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：你没有指定精灵[听不清]。
DAVID J. MALAN: I don't need to specify the sprite explicitly
大卫·J·马兰：我不需要明确地指定精灵
because a detail I didn't discuss earlier.
因为之前我还没讲过一个细节。
In the bottom right of the screen, notice
在屏幕的右下角，注意
that the cat is already selected.
猫已经被选中了。
So this code relates to that cat.
所以这段代码与那只猫相关。
So your instinct is good if we had two or more sprites,
所以你的直觉没错，如果我们有两个或多个精灵，
but I just have one, so I'm covered there.
但我只有一个，所以这里就不用担心了。
Other thoughts.
还有其他想法吗？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: It only checks once.
观众：它只检查一次。
DAVID J. MALAN: It only checks?
大卫·J·马兰：它只检查？
AUDIENCE: Once.
观众：一次。
DAVID J. MALAN: Once.
大卫·J·马兰：一次。
So I click the green flag.
所以我点击了绿色旗帜。
The computer did what I told it to do.
电脑做了我告诉它做的事情。
The mouse pointer was not touching the cat at that moment
那个时候鼠标指针没有接触到猫
because it was touching the green flag.
因为它接触到了绿色旗帜。
So, of course, it didn't meow.
所以，当然，它没有喵喵叫。
So what maybe is the fix here?
所以，也许，这里的解决方案是什么？
What puzzle piece can we add?
我们能添加什么拼图？
AUDIENCE: After the green flag is [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：在绿色旗帜被[听不清]之后...
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
OK.
好的。
Interesting solution.
有趣的解决方案。
So let me go ahead, and under Control let me grab a-- wait one second.
所以让我继续，在控制下让我抓取一个——等等。
I'm going to change the 1 to 5, and now I'm going to click the green flag.
我要把 1 改成 5，现在我要点击绿色旗帜。
So here we go.
开始了。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
1，2，3，4，5。
Damn it.
该死。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
OK.
好的。
That was yours, not mine.
那是你的，不是我的。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
It didn't work.
它没用。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Sorry?
大卫·J·马兰：抱歉？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, maybe forever.
大卫·J·马兰：哦，也许是永远。
So your approach would work, but it's very much a hack, if you will.
所以你的方法是可行的，但如果可以的话，它非常像个黑客手段。
Like, I would have to time it perfectly so that the mouse pointer is touching
比如，我必须精确地计时，以便鼠标指针接触到
it, or, conversely, I have to drag it there and just
它，或者相反，我必须把它拖过去，然后就
leave it there for five seconds.
把它放在那里五秒钟。
And that's a little weird because you don't just touch a cat
这有点奇怪，因为你不会仅仅触碰一只猫
and then five seconds later it meows at you.
然后五秒钟后它就对你喵喵叫。
Like, presumably, we want it to be more interactive.
我们想要它更具交互性。
So I like this idea of a loop.
所以我喜欢循环的想法。
Right?
对吧？
Why don't we just tell the cat to forever listen for the cursor
为什么我们不直接告诉猫永远监听光标
as by using not repeat but forever?
通过使用forever而不是repeat？
Let me move this in here.
让我把它移到这里。
So now the cat's going to be told when the green flag is clicked just forever,
所以现在猫被告知，当点击绿色旗帜时，永远
if touching, if touching, if touching.
如果接触，如果接触，如果接触。
Oh, meow when actually touched.
哦，当真正接触时喵喵叫。
So now if I zoom out and hit Play, nothing's happening.
所以，如果我现在缩小然后点击播放，什么也没发生。
I don't have to wait any number of seconds.
我不需要等待任何秒数。
But when I do touch the cat--
但当我接触到猫的时候——
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
[CHUCKLES] Fan section here.
[轻笑声] 这里的粉丝区。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
So now it's actually working quite well.
所以现在它运行得相当好。
So there we have sort of a logical bug.
所以我们这里有一个逻辑错误。
But it does make sense if you think about what it was
但如果你想想你实际告诉计算机做的事情，就会发现它是合理的。
you told the computer to actually do.
你实际告诉计算机做的事情。
Well, let's make things even more interesting
好吧，让我们让事情更有趣一些
by using one of these extensions.
通过使用这些扩展中的一个。
In this bottom left corner, this is how I got to text-to-speech earlier.
在这个左下角，这是我之前如何实现文本转语音的。
Let me go to Video Sensing over here too.
我也去看看这里的视频传感。
And I can actually-- there we go-- literally, the video has come on.
我实际上——好了——实际上，视频开始了。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续做这个。
Get rid of this code, and let me step out of the frame.
删除这段代码，让我走出画面。
When video motion is greater than--
当视频运动大于——
well, this is CS50, so let's just type in 50,
好吧，这是 CS50，所以我们输入 50，
which is just a measure of motion.
这只是一个运动的衡量标准。
Let me go and play sound meow.
让我去播放喵喵的声音。
OK.
好的。
And let me stop and restart.
让我停止并重新开始。
All right.
好的。
So there's the cat.
所以，这就是猫。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
OK.
好的。
It worked.
它成功了。
The cat's a little insensitive.
猫有点迟钝。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
There we go.
好了。
Actually, you know what?
实际上，你知道吗？
Maybe it's just-- let me put-- let's change it.
也许就是——让我放——让我们改变它。
20.
20。
Oh, my God.
我的天啊。
Oh, that's OK.
哦，没事。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
There we go.
好了。
All right.
好的。
There we go.
好了。
So now it's a little more sensitive to the petting by using the camera.
所以现在它对使用摄像头进行抚摸更加敏感了。
Now, this is kind of a weird example.
现在，这是一个有点奇怪的例子。
And if I just start moving around crazily, like,
如果我开始疯狂地四处乱动，就像，
it's just going to meow incessantly, which was what was happening--
它就会不停地喵喵叫，这就是当时发生的事情——
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
Stop.
停下来。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK.
好的。
When in doubt, this is when you reload the page.
有疑问时，就是你重新加载页面的时候。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
All right.
好吧。
So now we're back to where we wanted to be.
所以现在我们回到了我们想要的地方。
But where can we now use these kinds of building blocks?
但是我们现在可以在哪里使用这些积木？
Like, we were doing such tiny little programs.
就像，我们正在做一些非常小的程序。
But even that we could turn into a whole game, I bet.
但我敢说，即使那样我们也可以把它变成一个完整的游戏。
Could we get like one volunteer to come on up?
我们可以找一位志愿者上来吗？
One volunteer?
一位志愿者？
Everyone's looking down.
大家都低着头看。
OK.
好的。
On the end here.
在那边。
Come on down.
下来吧。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好吧。
Round of applause for our one brave volunteer here.
让我们为我们这位勇敢的志愿者鼓掌。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好吧。
These Super Mario cookies are on the line for you,
这些超级马里奥饼干就取决于你的表现了，
depending on how this goes.
这取决于结果如何。
So I'm going to have you come over here.
所以我要让你到这边来。
And in advance on Scratch's website, we have some pre-made games,
之前在 Scratch 网站上，我们已经有一些预制的遊戲，
one of them written by one of your predecessors, a former student,
其中一个是由你之前的一位学生编写，
that they implemented this sort of "Whac-A-Mole" game.
他们实现了类似“打地鼠”的游戏。
So what you're about to see is the camera turn on on you.
所以你马上就会看到摄像头对准你。
And you're going to see four moles above, below, left, and right.
你会看到四个地鼠，分别在上面、下面、左边和右边。
And using only your head--
只需要用你的头——
up, down, left, right-- the goal is to whack a mole
上下左右——目标是打地鼠
to get a point every time your head touches one of these sprites.
每次你的头碰到这些精灵时，你就能获得一分。
So you're about to see things get very interesting very quickly.
所以你马上就会看到事情变得非常有趣，而且速度很快。
But using these building blocks, just those simple
但是使用这些积木，只有这些简单的
blocks but have four sprites, not four cats but four moles in this case.
积木，但有四个精灵，不是四只猫，而是四个地鼠。
We can actually turn these into actual games.
实际上，我们可以把这些变成真正的游戏。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
So here we go.
好了，我们开始吧。
Click Beginner.
点击“初学者”。
OK.
好的。
And we just need you to center your head first.
首先，你需要将你的头放在中央。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[模糊的聊天声]
[CHUCKLES]
[轻笑声]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
Nice.
不错。
Ten seconds.
十秒。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
Nice.
不错。
Two seconds.
两秒。
AUDIENCE: [LAUGHS]
观众：[笑声]
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好吧。
A round of applause.
鼓掌吧。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢。
You want to introduce yourself?
你想介绍一下自己吗？
AUDIENCE: Hi, everybody.
观众：大家好。
My name is [? Vanilla. ?] I'm a first year,
我的名字是[？香草？]，我是一年级学生，
and I'm going to be majoring in computer science and economics.
我将主修计算机科学和经济学。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice to meet you.
大卫·马兰：很高兴认识你。
Here we go.
好了，我们开始吧。
Thank you.
谢谢。
AUDIENCE: Nice to meet you.
观众：很高兴认识你。
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[掌声，欢呼声]
DAVID J. MALAN: So we won't look at the code for that actual game.
大卫·马兰：所以我们不会查看那个实际游戏的代码。
It was written by one of your predecessors.
它是你的前辈写的。
And you can see it online if you're curious.
如果你好奇的话，你可以在网上看到它。
But you can think about now with our functions, conditionals,
但现在你可以考虑使用我们的函数、条件语句，
Boolean expressions, loops how you could kind of compose that kind of program.
布尔表达式、循环，你如何组合出这样的程序。
So odds are there was a loop that was just constantly listening
所以很可能有一个循环，它一直在监听
for that kind of connectivity, or it was one
这种连接，或者它是一个
of those extensions that was waiting for motion to go
那些等待运动去
touch one of those sprites.
触碰其中一个精灵。
Notice that there's these numbers up here.
注意，这里有一些数字。
And we haven't talked about this yet.
我们还没有讨论过这个。
But just like in math, where you can have variables x, y, and z,
但在编程中，你可以使用其他拼图块创建变量
in programming, you can create variables using other puzzle pieces
就像在数学中，你可以有变量 x、y 和 z 一样，
in Scratch that just keep track of how many seconds are left,
在 Scratch 中，这些变量可以跟踪还剩多少秒，
that keeps track of how many times her head hit one of the moles.
它可以跟踪她的头击中了多少次地鼠。
And so you can implement the mechanics of games using very simple building
因此，你可以使用非常简单的积木来实现游戏的机制
blocks.
块。
But how do you go about building something
但是如何构建一些
that's more interesting and interactive like that?
更有趣、更具互动性的东西？
Let me go ahead and bring up, for instance,
让我展示一下，比如，
one of the very first things I wrote years ago
几年前我写的最早的东西之一
when I was in graduate school and Scratch had just come out.
那是在我读研究生的时候，Scratch 刚发布。
I was taking a class at MIT's Media Lab.
我在麻省理工学院媒体实验室上了一门课。
And they invited us to beta test-- that is, try out the software before it then
他们邀请我们进行 Beta 测试，也就是在软件发布之前试用它。
became part of the world.
成为世界的一部分。
And the game I made was this one here.
我做的游戏就是这个。
Let me find the right version of "Oscartime."
让我找到正确的“奥斯卡时间”版本。
So "Oscartime" is a game that took me tens of hours probably in the end.
所以，“奥斯卡时间”这个游戏，可能最终花了我几十个小时。
It was a little bit addictive, but let me go ahead and full-screen it.
它有点上瘾，但是让我全屏播放它。
And I won't play the whole game.
我不会玩完整的游戏。
But it looked a little something like this.
但它看起来有点像这样。
OSCAR: (SINGS) Oh, I love--
奥斯卡：(唱歌)哦，我爱——
DAVID J. MALAN: Where trash is falling from the sky.
大卫·马兰：垃圾从天空中掉下来。
And I can click on it and drag it.
我可以点击它并拖动它。
And notice as I get close, the lid opens up like this.
注意，当我靠近时，盖子像这样打开。
And if I let it keep falling, it goes in, and Oscar gives me a point.
如果我让它继续落下，它就会进去，奥斯卡会给我一个分数。
And I can do this again.
我还可以再做一次。
OSCAR: If you really want to see something trashy--
奥斯卡：如果你真的想看看一些垃圾——
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
Here comes something else.
来了点其他的东西。
OSCAR: I have here a sneaker that--
奥斯卡：我这里有一双运动鞋，它——
DAVID J. MALAN: So now there's two pieces of trash.
大卫·J·马兰：所以现在有两件垃圾了。
OSCAR: It's all full of holes, and the laces are--
奥斯卡：它到处都是洞，鞋带是——
DAVID J. MALAN: And it just keeps going, and going, and going.
大卫·J·马兰：它一直在不断落下，落下，落下。
And if we can lower the volume for just a moment, we'll let more trash fall.
如果我们能把音量调低一点，我们就会让更多垃圾落下。
But to your comment earlier about one sprite or more
但是你之前提到的一个精灵或者更多精灵，这就是我们在这里看到的情况。
sprites, that's what we're seeing here.
精灵，这就是我们在这里看到的情况。
Even though our examples thus far are just one cat, one or two puzzle
虽然到目前为止，我们的例子只有一个猫，一个或两个拼图
pieces, or a few puzzle pieces.
碎片，或者一些拼图碎片。
Here is, I claim, a sprite.
我声称，这是一个精灵。
Here is another sprite.
这是另一个精灵。
And by toggling among them in that bottom right-hand corner,
通过在右下角切换它们，
I can just associate different puzzle pieces with each of these sprites.
我就可以将不同的拼图碎片与这些精灵关联起来。
Now, I didn't start off by implementing this whole game.
现在，我一开始并没有实现整个游戏。
And in just a moment, if we can raise the volume a little bit,
稍等片刻，如果我们可以稍微提高音量，
we'll see even more trash is falling.
我们会看到更多垃圾正在落下。
So this is what--
所以这就是——
I hate this song now, like 10 plus hours listening to this song on loop
我现在讨厌这首歌，就像循环播放这首歌超过10个小时
just to get the timing right.
只是为了让时间安排得当。
But it brings to life all of these different sprites.
但它让所有这些不同的精灵都活跃了起来。
And if you play it again and again, it's always a little bit different
如果你反复播放它，它总是有一点不同
because I'm using some randomness.
因为我用了一些随机性。
So this newspaper doesn't always fall from there.
所以这份报纸并不总是从那里掉下来。
Sometimes it's here.
有时候它在这里。
And so here, again, we have mechanics of a game where
所以在这里，我们再次看到游戏的机制，其中
things are being perturbed a little, randomized a little bit
一些东西被轻微地扰乱，随机化了一点
to keep things more interesting.
让事情更有趣。
And let me go ahead.
让我继续。
OSCAR: (SINGS) I love trash.
奥斯卡：（唱歌）我爱垃圾。
DAVID J. MALAN: There we go.
戴维·J·马兰：好了。
How. about raise a little volume?
怎样？提高一下音量？
One more piece of trash.
再加一点垃圾。
So a clock.
所以是一个钟表。
It just goes on forever, this kind of game.
这种游戏会一直持续下去。
But let's go ahead and consider.
但让我们继续考虑。
Let me close that.
让我关掉它。
Let me go ahead and consider.
让我继续考虑。
How I went about implementing that from the get-go.
我是如何从一开始就实现它的。
So I will stipulate--
所以我要声明——
let me open a few of these versions here-- that the very first thing I did
让我打开这里的一些版本——我做的第一件事
was pretty much just implement the stage.
基本上就是实现舞台。
Right?
对吧？
I was kind of procrastinating, so I poked around.
我有点拖延，所以我四处看看。
I found the Sesame Street lamppost, and I dragged it into the world.
我找到了芝麻街的路灯，把它拖到了这个世界。
And done.
就完成了。
Version one is done.
第一个版本完成了。
It didn't do anything, but at least I had the world sort of laid out.
它什么都没做，但至少我已经将这个世界大体规划出来了。
That is to say I took a baby step toward my goal.
也就是说，我朝着我的目标迈出了第一步。
Then I started thinking about, all right,
然后我开始思考，好吧，
how do I bring the trash to life, even if it doesn't do much of anything else?
即使它什么也做不了，我该如何让垃圾活起来？
And so I created another sprite by clicking the appropriate button
所以我通过点击右下角的相应按钮创建了另一个精灵
in that bottom right-hand corner.
在那个右下角。
And I thought about, well, what do I want this trash to do?
我想着，好吧，我想让这个垃圾做什么？
I want it to just kind of fall from the sky.
我希望它从天空中掉下来。
And so what I did here was the following.
所以我在此所做的是以下内容。
If I go to this trash piece here or-- actually, sorry.
如果我来到这里的这块垃圾，或者——实际上，抱歉。
Out of order.
顺序不对。
What I actually did first was I didn't even have the trash fall.
我实际上做的第一件事是，我甚至没有让垃圾掉下来。
If I play this game, the trash just stays there in the air.
如果我玩这个游戏，垃圾就一直停留在空中。
But I can do this.
但我可以这样做。
I can drag it, and as before, as I touch the other sprite,
我可以拖动它，就像之前一样，当我碰到另一个精灵时，
I get the trash can lid to go up.
我会让垃圾桶盖子打开。
So how do I do that?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me click on Oscar down there, my first sprite.
好吧，让我点击下面的奥斯卡，我的第一个精灵。
And here are the puzzle pieces via which I implemented this idea.
这就是我实现这个想法的拼图碎片。
I changed Oscar's costume, his appearance,
我改变了奥斯卡的服装，他的外观，
to be just number one, which was one of the images I imported into the program.
变成了数字一，这是我导入程序的图像之一。
just to get the timing right.
只是为了让时间安排正确。
But it brings to life all of these different sprites.
但这让所有这些不同的精灵都栩栩如生。
And if you play it again and again, it's always a little bit different
如果你反复播放它，它总是稍微有点不同
because I'm using some randomness.
因为我使用了一些随机性。
So this newspaper doesn't always fall from there.
所以这份报纸并不总是从那里落下。
Sometimes it's here.
有时它在这里。
And so here, again, we have mechanics of a game where
因此，在这里，我们再次看到了游戏的机制，在游戏中
things are being perturbed a little, randomized a little bit
事物被稍微扰乱，稍微随机化了一些
to keep things more interesting.
为了让事情更有趣。
And let me go ahead.
让我继续。
OSCAR: (SINGS) I love trash.
奥斯卡：(唱歌) 我爱垃圾。
DAVID J. MALAN: There we go.
大卫·J·马兰：就是这样。
How. about raise a little volume?
怎么样，提高一下音量？
One more piece of trash.
还有一件垃圾。
So a clock.
所以是一块钟表。
It just goes on forever, this kind of game.
这种游戏会永远持续下去。
But let's go ahead and consider.
但让我们继续考虑。
Let me close that.
让我把它关上。
Let me go ahead and consider.
让我继续考虑。
How I went about implementing that from the get-go.
我从一开始是如何实现它的。
So I will stipulate--
所以我要声明——
let me open a few of these versions here-- that the very first thing I did
让我在这里打开几个版本——我做的第一件事
was pretty much just implement the stage.
就是实现舞台。
Right?
对吧？
I was kind of procrastinating, so I poked around.
我有点拖延，所以我就到处看看。
I found the Sesame Street lamppost, and I dragged it into the world.
我找到了芝麻街的路灯，然后把它拖进了世界。
And done.
完成了。
Version one is done.
第一个版本完成了。
It didn't do anything, but at least I had the world sort of laid out.
它什么也没做，但至少我已经将世界大致布局出来了。
That is to say I took a baby step toward my goal.
也就是说，我朝着我的目标迈出了一小步。
Then I started thinking about, all right,
然后我开始思考，好吧，
how do I bring the trash to life, even if it doesn't do much of anything else?
我怎样才能让垃圾活起来，即使它不做其他任何事情？
And so I created another sprite by clicking the appropriate button
所以我通过点击右下角的相应按钮创建了另一个精灵
in that bottom right-hand corner.
在右下角。
And I thought about, well, what do I want this trash to do?
我思考着，好吧，我想让这垃圾做什么呢？
I want it to just kind of fall from the sky.
我希望它只是从天上掉下来。
And so what I did here was the following.
所以我在这里做了以下的事情。
If I go to this trash piece here or-- actually, sorry.
如果我走到这块垃圾这里，或者——实际上，抱歉。
Out of order.
顺序错了。
What I actually did first was I didn't even have the trash fall.
我实际上最先做的事情是，我甚至没有让垃圾落下。
If I play this game, the trash just stays there in the air.
如果我玩这个游戏，垃圾就会停留在空中。
But I can do this.
但我可以这样做。
I can drag it, and as before, as I touch the other sprite,
我可以拖动它，和之前一样，当我碰到另一个精灵时，
I get the trash can lid to go up.
垃圾桶的盖子会向上弹起。
So how do I do that?
那么，我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me click on Oscar down there, my first sprite.
好吧，让我点击下面的奥斯卡，我的第一个精灵。
And here are the puzzle pieces via which I implemented this idea.
这里就是我用来实现这个想法的拼图碎片。
I changed Oscar's costume, his appearance,
我改变了奥斯卡的服装，他的外貌，
to be just number one, which was one of the images I imported into the program.
只是变成了数字1，这是我导入程序中的其中一张图片。
And then I forever did this.
然后我永远地做了这件事。
If Oscar is touching the mouse pointer, then
如果奥斯卡碰到了鼠标指针，那么
change Oscar's costume to number two, otherwise change it back to one.
将奥斯卡的服装改为数字2，否则将其改回数字1。
So it's super simple animation.
所以这是一个超级简单的动画。
I'm just toggling between lid up, lid down, lid up, lid down,
我只是在盖子打开、盖子关闭、盖子打开、盖子关闭之间切换，
but it kind of feels interactive.
但这感觉起来有点互动。
And if I wanted to really make this pretty,
如果我想让它更漂亮，
I could have 30 different costumes where the lid is ever so slightly higher.
我可以制作30套不同的服装，让盖子稍微高一点。
Then it would look even more like a movie or fluid motion.
然后它看起来更像电影或流畅的动作。
But this was enough to get the job done, which
但这已经足够完成任务了，也就是说
is to say I didn't try to implement all of "Oscartime" together.
我没有尝试将所有“奥斯卡时间”都放在一起实现。
I just took a second baby step toward my goal.
我只是朝着我的目标迈出了第二步。
And then my next version of "Oscartime" might
然后我的下一个“奥斯卡时间”版本可能
have looked a little something like this, where now the trash--
看起来有点像这样，现在垃圾——
there's more going on here.
这里发生了更多的事情。
Let's look at two of these blocks of code.
让我们看看这两块代码。
The first thing I did was I enabled drag mode to draggable,
我做的第一件事是，我将拖动模式设置为可拖动，
and I had to Google to figure this out because otherwise it
我不得不谷歌搜索来弄清楚这一点，因为否则它
didn't let me drag the trash while playing the game.
不允许我在玩游戏时拖动垃圾。
But once I figured that out, I tell the trash
但一旦我弄明白了，我就告诉垃圾
to go to a random x-coordinate between 0 and 240
移动到 0 到 240 之间的随机 x 坐标
from left to right and then the y location 180
从左到右，然后是 y 位置 180
because I always want the trash falling from the sky.
因为我总是希望垃圾从天空中掉下来。
And then what do I do?
然后我该怎么做呢？
I told the trash to forever change its y-coordinate, its vertical coordinate,
我告诉垃圾永远改变它的 y 坐标，也就是垂直坐标，
by negative 1, negative 1, negative 1, one pixel
每次下降 1 像素， 1 像素， 1 像素
at a time, which creates the illusion of it falling from the sky.
这样就能营造出垃圾从天而降的错觉。
But I needed to do one other thing, and let me scroll up.
但我还需要做另外一件事，让我向上滚动一下。
Each of your sprites can have multiple programs, multiple scripts,
每个精灵都可以拥有多个程序，多个脚本，
so to speak, that are not attached to one another.
可以这么说，这些脚本彼此之间并不相关。
They will happen in parallel for you.
它们会同时运行。
The second one is saying this.
第二个脚本是这么写的。
Forever if the trash is touching Oscar, what should it do?
永远，如果垃圾触碰了奥斯卡，它应该怎么做呢？
Go to a completely different x and y location at the very top.
转移到最上面的一个完全不同的 x 和 y 位置。
Why?
为什么？
Well, as soon as I drag the trash over the Oscar,
只要我把垃圾拖到奥斯卡上面，
I want it to disappear as though it's going into the can.
我就希望它消失，就像被扔进了垃圾桶一样。
And I then want it to reappear at the top so more trash falls.
然后我想要它重新出现在顶部，这样就又会有新的垃圾掉下来了。
So I just thought about what would it mean
所以我只是思考了，对于垃圾来说，被扔进垃圾桶意味着什么？
for the trash to go into the trash can.
对于垃圾来说，被扔进垃圾桶意味着什么？
Well, who cares?
好吧，谁在乎呢？
What really matters to the human user is that it just
对于人类用户来说，真正重要的是它只是
disappears and teleports elsewhere.
消失，然后传送到了别的地方。
And so that's the idea I implemented here.
这就是我在这里实现的想法。
So if you can reduce intuitive ideas to just basic building blocks like this,
所以，如果你能将直观的思想分解成像这样的基本构建块，
you can start to make things much more interactive.
你就可以开始让事物变得更加互动。
And lastly, if I look at this version here,
最后，如果我看看这里这个版本，
you'll see that we've combined these.
你会发现我们已经把这些都结合起来了。
And so indeed, if I actually go ahead and play this now,
所以，如果我现在真正去运行一下，
not only is it falling.
它不仅会掉下来。
I can let it fall right on top of Oscar and watch it disappear.
我可以让它直接掉到奥斯卡上面，然后看着它消失。
But notice Oscar doesn't pop out yet because that was the fourth version
但注意，奥斯卡还没弹出来，因为那是第四个版本
and then the fifth version.
然后是第五个版本。
And then I added the annoying music and so forth but sort of
然后我加上了恼人的音乐等等，但是，某种程度上来说，
composed this program step by step by step
我是一步一步地编写了这个程序，
so as to accomplish my larger goal.
以便实现我的最终目标。
And this is going to be true of all of the code you write,
而这对于你编写的任何代码来说都是一样的，
be it in Scratch, or C, or Python, or in the like, trying to come up with--
无论是用 Scratch、C 还是 Python 语言，或者其他任何语言，你都需要尝试着去想出——
or rather, trying to reduce your ideas, your grand vision to just baby steps,
或者说，尝试将你的想法、你的宏伟愿景分解成微不足道的步骤，
building blocks so that you start with version one,
一个个基础模块，这样你就可以从版本一入手，
and maybe you submit version 10 or 20.
或许你最终会提交版本十或版本二十。
But you don't try to implement version 10 or 20 at the get-go.
但你不会一开始就尝试实现版本十或版本二十。
You take those incremental steps.
你应该一步步地前进。
All right.
好的。
How about one other?
还有别的例子吗？
Well, let me propose this.
好吧，让我来提一个建议。
Let me go ahead and open three games that represent one
让我打开三个游戏，它们分别代表着
that your predecessors also implemented, which looks a little something
你们的前辈们也实现过，它看起来有点像
like this in version zero.
版本零的样子。
Suppose I wanted to implement a game that
假设我想要实现一个游戏，它
simply has these kinds of mechanics.
只包含了这些类型的机制。
I'm touching my arrow keys on my keyboard-- up, down, left, and right.
我在键盘上按着方向键——上，下，左，右。
And I'm moving the Harvard logo.
而我在移动哈佛的校徽。
Let me zoom in a bit.
让我稍微放大一点。
So if I hit the up arrow, the Harvard shield goes up.
所以，如果我按向上箭头，哈佛的盾牌就会向上移动。
If I hit the down arrow, the shield goes down.
如果我按向下箭头，盾牌就会向下移动。
If I go all the way to the left, it goes left
如果我一直向左移动，它就会向左移动
until it hits the wall and same thing on the right.
直到撞到墙壁，右侧也是一样。
So this is like the beginnings of a game or a beginning
所以，这就像是一个游戏的开端，或者是一个迷宫的开端，类似于这种。
of a maze, something like that.
Well, how might I implement this?
那么，我该如何实现它呢？
Well, let me look inside this one.
好吧，让我来看看这个例子。
And there's a lot going on, but, again, I sort of took simple steps.
这里有很多东西，但再一次，我只是采取了一些简单的步骤。
Notice that I've got three sprites--
请注意，我使用了三个精灵——
a left wall, which is just a straight line,
左边的墙，只是一条直线，
the right wall, which is a straight line.
右边的墙，也是一条直线。
And just intuitively, why did I implement those as sprites?
直观地来说，为什么我要把它们实现成精灵呢？
Why do they need to exist as entities themselves?
为什么它们需要作为独立的实体存在？
Yeah, in front.
是的，在前面。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
I want it to interact with the shield.
我想让它与盾牌进行交互。
So I need to be able to ask that Boolean expression, like,
所以，我需要能够提出这样的布尔表达式，比如：
not touching mouse pointer but touching shield, for instance,
不触碰鼠标指针，但触碰了盾牌，比如这样。
a different type of yes/no question.
这是一个不同的真假判断问题。
And so what is the code for the shield actually doing?
那么，盾牌的代码实际上在做什么呢？
Well, there's a lot of duplication, and let me focus on the abstraction first.
好吧，这里有很多重复的部分，让我先关注一下抽象部分。
Notice that I've got this one green flag clicked.
请注意，我这里有一个绿色旗帜被点击了。
I want the shield to go dead center, 0 comma 0,
我希望盾牌位于正中央，也就是 0, 0 这个位置，
and then forever listen for the human's keyboard, and feel for the wall.
然后它会一直监听用户的键盘，并感知墙壁。
So I decided to implement my own pink puzzle pieces that
所以我决定实现我自己的粉色拼图块，这些拼图块
implement the two separate ideas.
实现了两个独立的想法。
One, just listen for the keyboard-- up, down, left,
第一个，就是监听键盘——上，下，左，
right-- and then do something.
右——然后执行相应的操作。
And then feel for walls is this idea of whenever I go up,
然后是感知墙壁，这个想法就是，无论何时我向上移动，
down, left, or right, if I touch a wall, I
向下移动，向左移动，或向右移动，如果我碰到了墙壁，我
need to stop doing whatever the keystrokes are telling me to do.
需要停止执行键盘输入告诉我要做的事情。
So now if we dive into those implementation details, listen and feel
所以，现在让我们深入这些实现细节，监听和感知
are abstractions, custom puzzle pieces.
是抽象的，定制的拼图块。
Let's look at the implementation details.
让我们来看看实现细节。
Well, here's the keyboard.
好了，这里就是键盘。
If the key arrow up is pressed, change y by 1.
如果按下向上箭头键，则将 y 坐标加 1。
If key down arrow is pressed, change y by negative 1.
如果按下向下箭头键，则将 y 坐标减 1。
And you can probably see where this is going.
你可能已经猜到了接下来的代码会是什么了。
Right arrow is x by 1.
右箭头是 x 坐标加 1。
Left arrow is x by negative 1, and that's
左箭头是 x 坐标减 1，而这就是
sort of all that's involved with up, down, left, right.
所有关于上，下，左，右的操作了。
But wait a minute.
等等。
Why is there no loop in this listen for keyboard puzzle piece?
为什么在这个监听键盘的拼图块里没有循环呢？
I needed a loop last time so it constantly works.
上一次我需要循环，才能让它不断地执行。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·J·马兰：没错。
I put the loop in my main part of my program
我把循环放在程序的主体部分
up top so something is telling me to keep listening again and again.
最上面，这样就有人不断地告诉我继续监听。
So it's got to be somewhere, but it doesn't have
所以它必须存在于某个地方，但它并不需要
to be in the actual implementation.
存在于实际的实现中。
And lastly, how about this feel for walls?
最后，我们来谈谈这种墙壁的感觉？
Well, if touching left wall, which is just another sprite, change x by 1.
嗯，如果碰到左边的墙壁，它只是一个精灵，就把x值改变1。
So that is to say if I'm touching the left wall,
也就是说，如果我碰到了左边的墙壁，
I want to bounce it back the other direction
我想让它弹回来，往另一个方向
and same thing on the right wall.
在右边的墙壁上也是一样。
If I'm touching the right wall, I want to bounce it
如果我碰到了右边的墙壁，我想让它弹回来
back to the left, which effectively means that even if the human's hitting
回到左边，这实际上意味着，即使人类在按
the key, it's like fighting with this code,
按键，它就像与这段代码作斗争，
but it's never going to go through the wall based on that math.
但根据这个数学公式，它永远不会穿透墙壁。
It's going to stop it right there.
它会把它停在那里。
All right.
好的。
Let's add something else to the mix.
让我们再加点东西。
Suppose I want the game to change to be a little something like this,
假设我想让游戏变得有点像这样，
where Yale is some kind of block in between me and the exit.
耶鲁大学的标志就像是我和出口之间的障碍物。
So some dramatic race here.
所以这里有一些戏剧性的比赛。
OK.
好的。
I just got by, but the Yale logo doesn't seem
我刚刚过去，但耶鲁大学的标志看起来
to be doing all that much except bouncing.
除了弹跳之外，并没有做太多的事情。
So I'm guessing there's a loop, maybe a conditional checking for those walls
所以我想也许有一个循环，也许有一个条件语句来检查那些墙壁
too.
也是。
So let's go ahead and zoom out, see inside.
所以让我们先放大，看看里面。
Let's not worry about Harvard because it's pretty much the same.
我们先别管哈佛大学，因为它基本是一样的。
Let's look at the Yale puzzle pieces.
我们来看看耶鲁大学的拼图碎片。
And sure enough, go to the middle.
当然，来到中间。
0 comma zero.
0,0。
Point in direction 90, so point horizontally on the grid.
指向90度方向，所以水平地指向网格。
And then if touching left wall or touching right wall--
然后，如果碰到左边的墙壁或者右边的墙壁，
I'm kind of cheating this time, but cleverly, just spin around and do 180
这次我有点作弊，但很巧妙，只需旋转并进行180度旋转
so you effectively bounce off the wall.
这样你就可以有效地反弹墙壁。
This just tightened up my code.
这只是让我的代码更紧凑。
I don't need to do the negative 1 or the plus 1.
我不需要做减1或加1。
I just say bounce in this form of code, otherwise just
我只需要用这种代码形式说反弹，否则就
constantly move one step.
不断地移动一步。
Now, if this is a game where Yale is supposed to be better and faster,
现在，如果这是一款耶鲁大学的标志应该更快更强的游戏，
well, let's change the 1 to 5.
好吧，让我们把1改为5。
Move 5 pixels at a time.
每次移动5个像素。
Let's move it 10 back and forth.
让我们让它来回移动10个像素。
Let's maybe 100.
我们试着移动100个像素吧。
Uh-oh.
哦，糟糕。
So what just happened?
所以，刚刚发生了什么？
That is a bug, which we can avoid by just not doing that.
这是一个错误，我们可以通过不做这件事来避免。
But why did it break out of the wall?
但为什么它会穿透墙壁？
Yeah.
没错。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]。
At first it was [INAUDIBLE].
一开始它是[听不清]。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·J·马兰：没错。
Because I'm doing 100 steps at a time, I'm
因为我一次移动100步，我
never actually touching the other sprite because I'm
从来没有真正碰到另一个精灵，因为我
sort of stepping way over it.
有点跨过它了。
So there's never a moment where they're actually touching.
所以，它们实际上从来没有接触过。
So previously, I was just getting lucky by doing fewer steps because it's
所以之前，我只是一直很幸运，因为我移动的步数比较少，所以它
gradually going over the wall, which gives me
慢慢地越过墙壁，这给了我
just enough time to detect as much.
足够的时间来检测它。
So I would have to kind of tinker, and he'll
所以我会进行一些调整，他会
handle this a little bit differently.
以稍微不同的方式来处理这件事。
So it's a bug if it's too fast.
所以如果它太快了，那就是一个错误。
But at least if I keep it slow and reasonable
但至少如果我保持它缓慢而合理，
the math actually does work out, so long as it starts again in the middle.
数学实际上是有效的，只要它从中间重新开始。
Well, let's do one final flourish here, whereby let's bring MIT into the mix.
好吧，让我们在这里做最后的一点润色，让我们把麻省理工学院也加入进来。
Right?
对吧？
They're super smart, so maybe they can kind of
他们超级聪明，所以也许他们可以
track us and follow wherever I'm going.
跟踪我们，并跟随我走到哪里。
So how might this work?
所以，这可能怎么实现呢？
All right.
好的。
So nothing happens yet because we haven't finished composing the game.
所以现在还没有发生任何事，因为我们还没有完成游戏的制作。
And notice here--
请注意这里
OK.
好的。
Now MIT is struggling.
现在麻省理工学院正在挣扎。
It's kind of twitching there because it's going just above, and below,
它有点抽搐，因为它在上面和下面移动，
and then above, and below.
然后又在上面和下面移动。
So we could fix that too if we want.
所以如果我们想的话，我们可以修复它。
But that's just a function of my math, one pixel at a time.
但这只是我的数学公式的结果，每次移动一个像素。
Let me open up this one, see inside, and click on MIT.
让我打开这个，看看里面，然后点击麻省理工学院。
And it doesn't take much to implement MIT, it seems.
看起来，实现麻省理工学院并不需要太多。
So go to random position, forever point towards the Harvard logo outline,
所以，随机移动到某个位置，永远指向哈佛大学的标志轮廓，
AKA the shield, and then move one step.
也就是盾牌，然后移动一步。
So if I wanted to make MIT even smarter, even faster, what do I change here?
所以如果我想让麻省理工学院更聪明，更快，我应该在这里改变什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·J·马兰：没错。
Change one step to two steps to double their speed or five steps, 10 steps,
把一步改为两步，让它们的速度翻倍，或者五步，十步，
or 100 steps.
或者一百步。
And the game is going to be over like that.
这样游戏就会很快结束。
But that's all it takes to now make these kinds of elements.
但这就是现在制作这些元素所需要的全部。
So if you are a game player on your phone, or consoles,
所以，如果你是在手机上，或者在游戏机上，
or computer, or whatever, if you think about almost any game,
或者电脑上，或者其他什么地方，如果你想想几乎所有的游戏，
you can probably now start to think about how they implemented
你可能现在可以开始思考他们是如何实现
those mechanics because it's just being reduced to functions, conditionals,
这些机制的，因为它们只是被简化为函数，条件语句，
loops, variables, and the like in this case.
循环，变量，以及在这种情况下类似的东西。
So let's go ahead here and have maybe one final volunteer.
所以让我们继续，再来一个志愿者。
We've got one more bag of Oreos here.
我们还有一包奥利奥饼干。
OK.
好的。
That was super fast.
太快了。
Do you want to come on up?
你想上来吗？
All right.
好的。
Brave volunteer.
勇敢的志愿者。
Come on up.
上来吧。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
Let me find the full-fledged version of this that one of your predecessors
让我找到这个游戏的完整版本，这个版本是由你的前任之一
made.
制作的。
And let me get the right one.
让我找到正确的那个。
OK.
好的。
Here we go.
我们开始了。
We'll see some instructions on the screen in just a moment.
过一会儿你会看到屏幕上的说明。
And when we hit Play, you'll see that the mechanics are all combined now
当我们点击播放时，你会看到所有机制现在都组合在一起了
into one full-fledged game.
成为一个完整的游戏。
But first, an introduction.
但首先，一个介绍。
It's on.
开始了。
SAM: Hi, everyone.
山姆：大家好。
I'm Sam.
我是山姆。
I live in [INAUDIBLE].
我住在[听不清]。
I'm a freshman, and I'm from Nepal.
我是一年级新生，我来自尼泊尔。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的。
Welcome to the stage.
欢迎来到舞台。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
SAM: Thank you.
山姆：谢谢。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的。
So here we go.
所以我们开始了。
Yep.
是的。
Go ahead and click the green flag.
点击绿色旗帜。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"] You can't touch this.
[MC HAMMER，"你碰不到这个"] 你碰不到这个。
DAVID J. MALAN: You see the grid is just bigger this time.
大卫·马兰：这次你看网格更大。
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
（唱歌）你碰不到这个。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
Now there's that Yale element.
现在有耶鲁元素。
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
（唱歌）你碰不到这个。
My, my, my my music hits me so hard.
我的，我的，我的，我的音乐击中我如此之猛烈。
Makes me say, oh, my Lord.
让我说，哦，我的上帝。
Thank you for blessing me with a mind to rhyme and two hyped feet.
感谢你赐予我一个会押韵的思想和两只兴奋的脚。
It feels good when you know you're down, a super dope homeboy from the Oaktown.
当你发现自己身处低谷时，感觉很好，来自奥克兰的一个超级棒的兄弟。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
大卫·马兰：好的。
Third Yale.
第三个耶鲁。
All started at slightly different positions.
所有都从略微不同的位置开始。
(SINGING) I told you, homeboy.
（唱歌）我告诉你，兄弟。
You can't touch this.
你碰不到这个。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
All right.
好的。
There's MIT.
有麻省理工。
(SINGING) And ya know you can't touch this.
（唱歌）你知道你碰不到这个。
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
[欢呼，掌声]
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh.
大卫·马兰：哦。
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
（唱歌）你碰不到这个。
Yo.
哟。
Let me bust the funky lyrics.
让我来爆出这funky的歌词。
DAVID J. MALAN: Gotta go fast.
大卫·马兰：得快一点。
Oh.
哦。
No.
不。
Oh.
哦。
[CHUCKLES]
[轻笑]
(SINGING) Cold on a mission, so fall on back.
（唱歌）冷酷的任务，所以退回去。
Let them know that you're too much, and this is a beat they can't touch.
让他们知道你太强了，这是他们碰不到的节奏。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
[EXCLAIMING]
[惊呼]
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
（唱歌）你碰不到这个。
DAVID J. MALAN: No more walls but two MITs.
大卫·马兰：没有更多的墙了，而是两个麻省理工。
(SINGING) Yo, sound the bell.
（唱歌）哟，敲响钟声。
School's in, sucker.
上课了，笨蛋。
DAVID J. MALAN: Princeton now.
大卫·马兰：现在是普林斯顿。
(SINGING) Give me a song or rhythm.
（唱歌）给我一首歌曲或节奏。
Making them sweat, that's what I'm giving them.
让他们汗流浃背，这就是我给他们的。
Now, they know you talk about the Hammer when you're talkin'
现在，他们知道你在谈论表演时，你也会谈论锤子。
'bout a show that's hyped and tight.
一个令人兴奋而紧凑的节目。
Singers are sweatin', so pass them a wipe or a tape to learn.
歌手们都在流汗，所以给他们一块毛巾或一盘磁带学习。
DAVID J. MALAN: Second to last level.
大卫·马兰：倒数第二个级别。
(SINGING) The chart's legit.
（唱歌）图表是真实的。
Either work hard, or you might as well quit.
要么努力工作，要么你干脆放弃算了。
That's word because you know you can't touch this.
因为你知道你碰不到这个。
You can't touch this.
你碰不到这个。
Break it down.
分解它。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的。
Clear.
清楚。
There we go.
我们开始了。
Nice.
不错。
Oh, oh.
哦，哦。
Oh.
哦。
Few more lives.
还有几条命。
Oh.
哦。
(SINGING) Stop.
（唱歌）停止。
Hammer time.
锤子时间。
DAVID J. MALAN: Here we go.
大卫·马兰：我们开始了。
There we go.
我们开始了。
[EXCLAIMING]
[惊呼]
All right.
好的。
Couple more tries.
再试几次。
Yes!
是的！
Oh, no.
哦，不。
(SINGING) This is it for a winner.
（唱歌）这是给获胜者的。
Dance to this, and you're gonna get thinner.
跟着它跳舞，你会变得更瘦。
Now move, slide your rump.
现在动起来，晃动你的屁股。
DAVID J. MALAN: Starts getting stressful.
大卫·马兰：开始变得压力很大。
(SINGING) Just for a minute, let's all do the bump.
（唱歌）只有一分钟，让我们一起做碰撞。
Bump, bump, bump.
碰撞，碰撞，碰撞。
Yeah.
是的。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
Look, man.
听着，伙计。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
You'll probably get hyped, boy.
你可能会兴奋起来，小子。
DAVID J. MALAN: One more try.
大卫·J·马兰：再试一次。
(SINGING) You can't touch this.
（演唱）你不能碰这个。
Ring the bell.
敲响铃铛。
School's back in.
学校开学了。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
大卫·J·马兰：好的。
A round of applause, nonetheless.
尽管如此，还是鼓掌吧。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
Nicely done.
做得很好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So as you might have noticed if your eyes started
所以你可能已经注意到，如果你开始
to wander to the light bulbs here, there's
漫游到这里的灯泡，这里有
actually 64 of these light bulbs.
实际上有64个这样的灯泡。
And I'm wondering if you divide 64 by 8, that's 8 bytes of light bulbs.
我想知道，如果你把64除以8，那就是8个字节的灯泡。
And we now have some Unicode in our vocabulary.
我们现在在我们的词汇表中有一些Unicode。
So might very well be the case that we've
所以很有可能，我们已经
been spelling something out on the stage here for you all of this time.
一直在舞台上为你们拼写一些东西，一直都是这样。
But before we adjourn for cake to be served in the Transept,
但在我们休会去横断面吃蛋糕之前，
allow me to introduce some of CS50's human friends,
请允许我介绍一些CS50的人类朋友，
the Harvard Krokodiloes and the Radcliffe Pitches,
哈佛鳄鱼和拉德克利夫音调，
to give us this exciting ending, "This is CS50."
来为我们带来这个激动人心的结尾，“这就是CS50”。
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[鼓掌，欢呼]
[HARMONICA NOTE]
[口琴音符]
[VOCALIZING]
[发声]
SPEAKER: (SINGING) There's a certain someone who I'm indebted to.
演讲者：（演唱）我欠某人一个情。
And since the old [? BNC ?] has 50, I have this friend for you.
而且因为老[？ BNC ？]有50，我有一个朋友给你。
A two, three, four.
二，三，四。
[VOCALIZING]
[发声]
Oh, rubber ducky, you're the one.
哦，橡胶鸭子，你就是那个。
You make [INAUDIBLE] so much fun.
你让[听不清]如此有趣。
Rubber ducky, I'm awfully fond of you.
橡胶鸭子，我非常喜欢你。
[SCATTING] Rubber ducky, you make me smile, and you help my code compile.
[即兴演唱]橡胶鸭子，你让我微笑，你帮助我的代码编译。
Rubber ducky, you're my very best friend.
橡胶鸭子，你是我最好的朋友。
It's true.
这是真的。
When I'm at a standstill, your debugging abilities stun me.
当我陷入僵局时，你的调试能力让我惊叹。
When I'm at the end of my rope, you just snap, and my code's up and running.
当我无计可施时，你只要打个响指，我的代码就启动并运行。
Rubber ducky, you're so fine, and I'm lucky that you're mine.
橡胶鸭子，你太棒了，我很幸运有你。
Rubber ducky, you're my very best friend.
橡胶鸭子，你是我最好的朋友。
It's true.
这是真的。
You're my best friend.
你是我最好的朋友。
It's true.
这是真的。
Rubber ducky, I'm awfully fond of you.
橡胶鸭子，我非常喜欢你。
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
[欢呼，鼓掌]
SPEAKER: Good afternoon, CS50.
演讲者：下午好，CS50。
We are the Harvard Krokodiloes, Harvard's oldest a cappella group,
我们是哈佛鳄鱼，哈佛最古老的无伴奏合唱团，
founded way back in 1946 at the historic Hasty Pudding Club.
成立于1946年，在历史悠久的匆忙布丁俱乐部。
We'd love to make a big thank you to CS50 staff
我们想衷心感谢CS50的工作人员
and to David Malan for having us perform here at Sanders Theater.
以及大卫·马兰，让我们在这里桑德斯剧院表演。
And you enjoyed this performance, please come audition for us
如果你喜欢这场表演，请来参加我们的试镜
this weekend at Farkas Hall.
这个周末在法卡斯大厅。
[CHEERING, APPLAUSE]
[欢呼，鼓掌]
SPEAKER: Hello, everyone.
演讲者：大家好。
We are some of the Radcliffe Pitches, and we are also
我们是一些拉德克利夫音调，我们也是
hosting auditions this weekend.
这个周末举办试镜。
You can find more information at our Instagram, @radcliffepitches.
你可以在我们的Instagram上找到更多信息，@radcliffepitches。
Now, let me tell you a little bit about just about a year ago
现在，让我告诉你一些关于大约一年前
today, when I was sitting in your very seats on my first day of CS50 lecture.
今天，当我坐在你的座位上参加我的第一次CS50讲座时。
And this is just about how I was feeling.
这就是我当时的感觉。
[HARMONICA NOTE]
[口琴音符]
[VOCALIZING]
[发声]
(SINGING) It's the first day of class, and I'm brand new to code.
（演唱）这是开学第一天，我刚接触代码。
Is this for me?
这适合我吗？
So many people around.
周围有那么多人。
Can I get through the workload?
我能完成工作量吗？
But it's my dream.
但这是我的梦想。
I tend to stick to English, not science.
我倾向于坚持英语，而不是科学。
But my [INAUDIBLE] friends told me to try this.
但我[听不清]的朋友们告诉我尝试一下。
Hey, dancing robot dog, you kind of look like you have your life together,
嘿，跳舞的机器人狗，你看起来似乎很会生活，
I guess.
我想。
I really need some advice.
我真的需要一些建议。
(ALL SINGING) We know you're feeling unsure,
（所有人演唱）我们知道你感到不确定，
but this is really the right call.
但这是真的正确选择。
In CS50, you'll meet new friends, get free food.
在CS50，你会结识新朋友，获得免费的食物。
You'll be all set for this fall in CS50.
你会为今年秋天在CS50做好准备。
You have a thousand TAs who will help you.
你会有一千个助教来帮助你。
You'll get cupcakes, duckies, Chinese food.
你会得到纸杯蛋糕、鸭子、中国菜。
And you can always take this class and set aside.
而且你随时可以选这门课并留出时间。
SPEAKER: This is CS50.
演讲者：这就是CS50。
Fist bump.
击掌。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[鼓掌，欢呼]
DAVID J. MALAN: Thank you to the Kroks.
大卫·J·马兰：感谢鳄鱼们。
Thank you to the Pitches.
感谢音调们。
Cake is now served.
蛋糕现在供应。
Come on up to say hi if you'd like or meet Spot.
如果你想的话，上来打个招呼或者见见斑点。
See you next time.
下次见。
[APPLAUSE, CHEERING]
[鼓掌，欢呼]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]